<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><search><entry><title>Transformer Succinctness: The Other Side of Expressiveness</title><url>/en/transformers-succinctness-summary/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>Transformer</tag><tag>Machine Learning</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  One of the two Outstanding Paper awards at ICLR 2026 went to a purely theoretical work: Transformers are Inherently Succinct. A paper with no experiments, no benchmarks, nothing but mathematical proofs, and it won best paper. The review committee&amp;rsquo;s rationale: &amp;ldquo;it offers a new perspective for explaining the power of the Transformer architecture.&amp;rdquo; The original paper is dense, drawing heavily on formal language theory and complexity theory. This post attempts to lay out the core results and construction ideas in a more intuitive way.
What is this &amp;ldquo;new perspective&amp;rdquo;? Past work compared expressiveness, i.e. which model can recognize a broader class of languages. This paper asks a different question: for the same language, which model can describe it using less space?
The paper summarizes its main result in one line:
Transformers can describe concepts extremely succinctly.
Not a little shorter. Absurdly shorter. For the same language, the description size …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>LLM2Vec: Turning Decoder LLMs into Embedding Models</title><url>/en/llm2vec-paper-summary/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>Embedding</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Embedding models have long been BERT&rsquo;s territory. Semantic search, RAG, clustering — all dominated by encoder-only models. Decoder-only models like GPT and LLaMA crush generation tasks, but the community has assumed they&rsquo;re not suitable for embeddings because causal attention only sees preceding tokens and can&rsquo;t build complete sentence representations.
LLM2Vec (COLM 2024) argued this assumption is wrong. Three steps, no labeled data, no GPT-4 synthetic data, and any decoder-only LLM becomes a SOTA embedding model on MTEB. Two years later, the approach has been validated and adopted by many subsequent works — worth revisiting what it actually did.
LLM2Vec Method Step one: replace the causal attention mask with an all-ones matrix so every token attends to every other token. This sounds brutal — the model has never seen future information during training, and directly enabling bidirectional attention usually hurts performance.
Step two is the key. Masked Next Token Prediction (MNTP) adapts the model to bidirectional attention. Randomly mask some input tokens and have the model predict the masked tokens using the full context (including future tokens). One difference from BERT&rsquo;s MLM: BERT uses the representation at the masked position itself to predict the original token; MNTP uses the representation at position i-1 to predict position i, preserving the decoder&rsquo;s &ldquo;predict i from i-1&rdquo; habit so the model doesn&rsquo;t need to learn an entirely new prediction pattern. Train with LoRA on English Wikipedia for 1,000 steps — 100 minutes on a single A100 for a 7B model.
Step three: unsupervised contrastive learning with SimCSE. Pass the same sentence through dropout twice to get two different representations, pull them closer while pushing apart other sentences in the batch. This step aggregates token-level bidirectional representations into good sentence-level representations.
Total training cost for all three steps: 1,000 steps MNTP + 1,000 steps SimCSE, one A100, a few hours.
Difference Between Causal and Bidirectional Representations The Mistral-related finding in the paper is interesting. After enabling bidirectional attention, LLaMA models suffer a sharp performance drop without MNTP training — as expected. But Mistral-7B with bidirectional attention and no additional training shows almost no performance change, even gaining 0.6% on NER.
The paper analyzes this by running the same input through both causal and bidirectional attention and comparing representations at each layer and token position. LLaMA shows massive differences, with cosine similarity approaching zero. Mistral&rsquo;s representations remain highly consistent, staying close to 1.0 throughout.
The paper speculates that Mistral may have used some form of bidirectional attention during pretraining, such as prefix language modeling. Training details aren&rsquo;t public so this can&rsquo;t be confirmed, but the experimental results are hard to explain otherwise. Either the architecture has special handling, or the training strategy already included bidirectional signals.
As a side note, the traditional approach for decoder embeddings is to take the last token&rsquo;s (EOS) representation. Intuitively this makes sense since under causal attention the last token sees all preceding information.
But the paper&rsquo;s experiments show that even for unmodified causal models, mean pooling outperforms EOS pooling. The gap widens after enabling bidirectional attention. While the EOS token&rsquo;s representation theoretically aggregates all information, in practice tokens near the end contribute far more than those at the beginning — the information distribution is uneven. Mean pooling avoids this problem.
Supervised MTEB Results After the three unsupervised steps, an additional round of supervised contrastive learning can be applied. The paper uses the public portion of the E5 dataset (about 1.5 million samples), achieving SOTA among models trained on public data on MTEB.
More interesting is the sample efficiency comparison.
Models transformed by LLM2Vec surpass the untransformed baseline&rsquo;s full 1,000-step performance within just the first 25 supervised training steps. The three unsupervised steps serve as a warm-up — the model already has decent sentence representation ability before seeing any labeled data.
One counterintuitive detail: in the supervised setting, skipping SimCSE (doing only bidirectional attention + MNTP) actually performs slightly better than doing all three steps. SimCSE&rsquo;s value is mainly in purely unsupervised and data-scarce scenarios. With sufficient supervised signal, the contrastive signal learned by SimCSE gets overridden, and the extra step introduces a slight bias.
Summary LLM2Vec has no new architecture, no new loss function — each of the three steps combines existing techniques. Replacing the attention mask with all-ones is a one-line code change, MNTP is a splice of MLM and NTP, and SimCSE is a 2021 paper. The core insight is simple: decoders are bad at embeddings because of the causal mask, not because they lack the ability.
On MTEB, LLM2Vec + Mistral-7B achieves an unsupervised score of 56.80, surpassing all previous unsupervised models including BERT + SimCSE&rsquo;s 45.45. With supervised training, Meta-LLaMA-3-8B + LLM2Vec reaches 65.01, ranking first among models using only public data. LLM2Vec shows that decoders&rsquo; poor embedding performance is a causal mask limitation, not a capability issue. Remove that limitation with simple adaptation training, and they surpass encoder models specifically trained for embeddings on MTEB.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on Training Data Depletion and Quality Degradation</title><url>/en/training-data-depletion/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  There used to be a popular claim: human-generated data on the internet would be exhausted within a few years, and LLM training data was running out. Epoch AI predicted in 2022 that high-quality text data might be depleted around 2026. The discussion was intense at the time, but it seems to come up less often now.
The internet is indeed flooded with AI-generated content. Search for almost anything and the first few results likely include AI-written text. According to earlier fears, this AI-generated text would be crawled back as training data, models eating their own output, getting worse with each iteration — the so-called model collapse. A Nature paper rigorously demonstrated this: recursively training on a model&rsquo;s own output causes tail distributions to gradually vanish, making outputs increasingly homogeneous.
But what&rsquo;s actually happening diverges from this narrative in a key way: not all content enters the training pipeline. Search engines and RAG systems are using the strongest LLMs to score and filter content quality. Starting with Google&rsquo;s March 2024 update , low-quality AI content has been systematically downranked — Google&rsquo;s stated figure is a 45% reduction in low-quality and unoriginal content in search results. Other search engines are doing similar deduplication and quality checks. AI-generated content is indeed increasing, but the data that enters training pipelines has been rigorously filtered.
As a result, the internet and LLMs have already formed a human-in-the-loop cycle. Humans write content, models learn; models generate content, humans and stronger models together filter what&rsquo;s worth keeping, and what survives enters the next round of training. Structurally, this process resembles RLHF, except the feedback signal comes not from annotator preference scores but from search engine rankings, user clicks and dwell time, and quality filtering models.
A linguistic analogy helps here. Language itself has always been evolving — every generation invents new words, new usages, new grammatical variants. By the same panic logic, language should have degenerated into nothing but slang and abbreviations long ago. Why hasn&rsquo;t this happened? Because the contexts in which language is used have built-in selection mechanisms: everyday conversation, formal writing, news reporting — these contexts continuously exert selective pressure, ensuring the continuation of core expressive capabilities. The spread of AI-generated content on the internet faces similar selective pressure.
This doesn&rsquo;t mean problems don&rsquo;t exist. Low-quality AI content polluting long-tail queries is real, and information quality in certain vertical domains is genuinely declining. But the causal chain of &ldquo;AI content floods the internet causing model training to collapse&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t hold up, in my view.
So the entire ecosystem looks more like a spontaneous large-scale reinforcement learning loop. In a sense, with AI capabilities augmenting human output, the efficiency of producing high-quality data has dramatically increased. At this point, the question becomes analogous to whether the steam engine and AI created fewer jobs or increased demand.
As for whether high-quality data is hand-crafted by humans, AI-assisted, or purely AI-generated — it doesn&rsquo;t seem to matter that much. Black cat, white cat — if it efficiently expresses and conveys information, it&rsquo;s a good cat.
Perhaps those worried about training data running out have underestimated both how fast filtering mechanisms evolve and humanity&rsquo;s capacity to keep producing quality content.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Claude Code: 1.6% AI, 98.4% Scaffolding</title><url>/en/dive-into-claude-code/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s memory management, context compaction, RAG, security classifier, Edit tool, and sub-agent cache sharing — each time reading the source code line by line. But after reading this paper, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d been looking at individual parts without seeing the whole machine.
The paper is Dive into Claude Code: The Design Space of Today&amp;rsquo;s and Future AI Agent Systems , 46 pages, a complete architectural dissection of Claude Code from source code. Not a usage tutorial, not a benchmark evaluation, but an answer to an engineering question: what is a production AI agent system&amp;rsquo;s code actually doing?
1.6% vs. 98.4% The paper&amp;rsquo;s sharpest number: only 1.6% of Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s codebase is AI decision logic. The remaining 98.4% is deterministic infrastructure — permission gates, tool routing, context management, error recovery.
This ratio reflects a design philosophy: don&amp;rsquo;t constrain what the model decides, build an environment …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Hivemind of Language Models</title><url>/en/artificial-hivemind/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Ask GPT-4 to recommend an underrated sci-fi film. It says Moon. Ask Claude the same question — also Moon. Try Gemini — Moon again. A NeurIPS 2025 Best Paper, Artificial Hivemind: The Open-Ended Homogeneity of Language Models (and Beyond) , quantifies this phenomenon at scale: different language models give strikingly similar answers to open-ended questions.
Hivemind — a classic science fiction concept where a group of individuals shares a single consciousness. As a description of collective language model behavior, the term fits uncomfortably well.
The Infinity-Chat Dataset Accuracy has MMLU. Safety has red-teaming benchmarks. But &amp;ldquo;how diverse are the answers?&amp;rdquo; has lacked a proper evaluation tool. The paper fills this gap with Infinity-Chat: 26,000 real user queries with no single correct answer, paired with 31,250 human annotations (25 independent annotators per example). These are questions like &amp;ldquo;recommend an obscure hobby,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;write a poem about …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>From RAG to Knowledge Compilation</title><url>/en/llm-wiki/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  RAG re-retrieves, re-assembles, and re-reasons on every query. Ask something that requires synthesizing five documents and the model has to find all five, stitch them together, and derive the answer from scratch. Ask ten times, retrieve ten times. Nothing accumulates.
Karpathy recently posted a gist called LLM Wiki proposing a different approach: instead of retrieving at query time, have the LLM pre-compile knowledge into a structured wiki and query the compiled result.
Link: LLM Wiki (Karpathy) Where RAG Falls Short To be clear, RAG&amp;rsquo;s operating model has a fundamental efficiency problem.
You load 200 papers into a RAG system. Ask &amp;ldquo;what are the research trends in this field over the past three years?&amp;rdquo; The model hits the vector database, pulls back the top-10 chunks, stuffs them into the prompt, and generates an answer. Sounds reasonable, but think about it: the information needed spans dozens of papers. Ten chunks won&amp;rsquo;t cover it. Even at k=50, the relationships …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Theoretical Ceiling of Vector Retrieval</title><url>/en/embedding-retrieval-limits/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Dense retrieval has become the default first stage in RAG pipelines. Encode documents into vectors, encode queries into vectors, compute cosine similarity, done. But a basic question rarely gets asked: for a d-dimensional embedding, how many distinct top-k retrieval results can it actually represent?
An ICLR 2026 paper from Google DeepMind and JHU, &amp;ldquo;On the Theoretical Limitations of Embedding-Based Retrieval&amp;rdquo;, gives a mathematical answer: not enough. Not even close.
Paper: arxiv.org/abs/2508.21038 The Dimension Lower Bound Start with the combinatorics. Given n documents and top-k retrieval, the total number of possible top-k subsets is $\binom{n}{k}$. This grows extremely fast as n and k increase.
For each top-k subset to be &amp;ldquo;realized,&amp;rdquo; there must exist some query vector whose dot product with the k relevant documents exceeds all others by a margin $\gamma$. The paper&amp;rsquo;s Theorem 1 proves:
$$d \geq \frac{\log \binom{n}{k}}{\log(1 + 1/\gamma)}$$
The …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Unexpected Perks of Talking to AI</title><url>/en/talk-to-ai-perks/</url><categories><category>Thoughts</category></categories><tags><tag>Thoughts</tag><tag>LLM</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Justin Sun (the crypto guy) recently dropped a hot take: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s 2026 already — if you can talk to AI, stop talking to humans.&amp;rdquo; He also said something about deleting contacts born before 1990 and WeChat being for old people. Classic Justin Sun. Take it with a grain of salt.
But strip away the absurd parts, and &amp;ldquo;talk to AI more&amp;rdquo; is something I actually agree with as a heavy user. Here&amp;rsquo;s why, and where it falls apart.
Ask Without Shame Someone drops an acronym in a meeting. A dozen people nod. You have no idea what it means, but you nod too. This has happened to everyone. You don&amp;rsquo;t ask because the social cost is too high. Years into your career and you&amp;rsquo;re asking about something this basic? Can&amp;rsquo;t do it.
With AI, there&amp;rsquo;s none of that. What&amp;rsquo;s the actual difference between git rebase and merge? Read about it before, forgot. Ask. Rust lifetime annotations — read it three times, still don&amp;rsquo;t get it. Ask. And it forgets. Next …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How Claude Dreams: Background Memory Defragmentation</title><url>/en/claude-code-auto-dream/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  There&amp;rsquo;s a module inside Claude Code called autoDream. Its prompt title reads &amp;ldquo;Dream: Memory Consolidation.&amp;rdquo;
This isn&amp;rsquo;t a metaphor. Claude Code actually spins up a background sub-agent that reviews transcripts from past sessions, consolidates scattered memories — merging, deduplicating, correcting — and writes them back to disk. The whole thing is invisible unless you dig into the background task list.
Sticky Notes vs. Notebook Rewrite Claude Code has two memory mechanisms with a clean division of labor.
extractMemories runs at the end of each conversation turn. It only looks at recently added messages in the current session and decides if anything is worth remembering long-term. Tell it &amp;ldquo;we use bun, not npm&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;ll save that preference. Fast — 2 to 4 turns and it&amp;rsquo;s done, like jotting something on a sticky note. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already had Claude write to memory during the conversation, it skips the extraction to avoid duplicate work. …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>AI and Employment: A 200-Year-Old Debate</title><url>/en/ai-employment-paradox/</url><categories><category>Thoughts</category></categories><tags><tag>Thoughts</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Tech job boards in 2025 are schizophrenic. Traditional software engineering roles are shrinking. &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo;-prefixed positions are expanding. Same company, same quarter — cutting junior devs and project managers on one side, opening Agent orchestration engineers and AI application architects on the other.
AI is creating and destroying jobs at the same time. Not news. The real question: which side moves faster, and how long does the gap last between &amp;ldquo;old job gone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;new job accessible&amp;rdquo;? Economists have been fighting about this for two centuries. Their conclusion, distilled: technology creates jobs in the long run, but the transition hurts. Ricardo showed in 1821 that a bigger pie doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean bigger slices for everyone. Keynes invented the term &amp;ldquo;technological unemployment&amp;rdquo; in 1930 — specifically for this kind of pain.
Two hundred years later, the theory holds. But AI has changed what the transition looks like.
What AI Is Already …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Three Evolutions of Agent Engineering</title><url>/en/prompt-context-harness-engineering/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Last June, Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke posted that he preferred &amp;ldquo;context engineering&amp;rdquo; over &amp;ldquo;prompt engineering.&amp;rdquo; Karpathy retweeted with a +1. Simon Willison wrote a blog post saying the term might actually stick. Phil Schmid published a full definition. Half the AI community switched terminology within a week.
By early 2026, Phil Schmid introduced another term: Agent Harness. It didn&amp;rsquo;t generate the same buzz, but anyone building Coding Agents quietly nodded along.
Three terms, three phases of focus. But there&amp;rsquo;s a problem with how the industry discusses them: many people treat them as iterative synonyms, as if context engineering is prompt engineering 2.0 and harness engineering is 3.0. That&amp;rsquo;s wrong. They solve problems at entirely different levels, and the relationship between them is containment, not replacement.
Prompt: How You Talk to the Model Prompt engineering took off in 2022-2023. The core scenario is simple: you&amp;rsquo;re facing a text box, …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Context Management in Claude Code vs OpenClaw</title><url>/en/openclaw-vs-claude-code-agent-arch/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html">  After OpenClaw crossed 350K stars, a narrative started forming in the community: since both run on Opus 4.6 under the hood, the open-source option should be on par with Claude Code. Anyone who has actually used both probably shares the same observation — in long sessions, OpenClaw starts losing context, forgetting files it already read, redoing work it already did. Claude Code does too, but noticeably later, and it recovers much better.
Same model, different experience. Why?
After reading through both codebases, the gap isn&amp;amp;rsquo;t in model capability — it&amp;amp;rsquo;s in how each Agent framework manages the 200K context window. Three core differences:
Claude Code has a four-layer compression cascade where the first three layers are free; OpenClaw has one layer that always calls the LLM Claude Code continuously maintains session notes in the background and uses them as free summaries during compression; OpenClaw only archives sessions on exit Claude Code&amp;amp;rsquo;s sub-agents are …  </content></entry><entry><title>Foundation Models Plateau, Applications Take Off</title><url>/en/foundation-model-plateau-application-era/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Cursor&amp;rsquo;s parent company Anysphere has about 150 employees. In November 2025, its ARR crossed $1 billion . OpenAI, as of early 2026, has 4,500 employees . Its 2025 revenue was $13.1 billion, but according to Fortune, it lost roughly $9 billion and doesn&amp;rsquo;t expect to turn profitable until 2028.
An application company that trains zero models is outproducing, per capita, the company that trains them. This is the most telling signal in AI for 2025.
Models Are Getting Harder to Improve The GPT-5 story begins with the failure that preceded it. According to The Information ( Inside OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Rocky Path to GPT-5 ), OpenAI spent the second half of 2024 on a project called Orion, originally intended to be GPT-5. Orion failed to produce a meaningfully better model and was downgraded to GPT-4.5, released in February 2025.
The actual GPT-5 didn&amp;rsquo;t ship until August 2025. MIT Technology Review&amp;rsquo;s same-day assessment was blunt: &amp;ldquo;GPT-5 is, above all else, a refined …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How OpenClaw Hit 350K Stars in 4 Months</title><url>/en/openclaw-why-viral/</url><categories><category>Product</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>Product</tag><tag>Software Engineering</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  In late November 2025, an open-source project called OpenClaw went live on GitHub. Four and a half months later, it had 350K stars, 70K forks, 81 releases, and sponsorships from OpenAI, NVIDIA, and Vercel. For comparison: Open WebUI took two and a half years to reach 130K stars; NextChat took three years to hit 88K. Growth like OpenClaw&amp;rsquo;s is rare in GitHub&amp;rsquo;s history.
It isn&amp;rsquo;t a new model, a training framework, or even a &amp;ldquo;technical breakthrough&amp;rdquo; in the traditional sense. It&amp;rsquo;s a personal AI assistant that runs on your own machine and talks to you through the chat apps you already use: WhatsApp, Telegram, Slack, Discord, WeChat, Feishu, iMessage, Matrix, and over 25 platforms in total, all connected to a single backend.
Why did it break out of the developer bubble?
The Five-Minute Aha Moment OpenClaw&amp;rsquo;s viral spark wasn&amp;rsquo;t a blog post or a Hacker News front-page hit. It was a very specific experience: you install it, and suddenly an AI is …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Deferred Tool Loading in Claude Code</title><url>/en/claude-code-deferred-tools/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When you use Claude Code, there&amp;rsquo;s something you probably never notice: it has over 40 registered tools, but when you ask it to read a file or edit a few lines of code, it only uses three or four. The definitions for the remaining 30-plus tools, each around 500 tokens, add up to over 10,000 tokens of fixed overhead per request. You just want to change one line of CSS, but you&amp;rsquo;re paying for WebSearch, NotebookEdit, CronCreate, and a bunch of tools you&amp;rsquo;ll never touch.
This problem has a well-known solution in traditional software: dynamic linking. Instead of loading every shared library at startup, the program waits until a function is actually called before loading its library. Claude Code does something similar, except it&amp;rsquo;s not managing memory address space. It&amp;rsquo;s managing token budget.
How Big Is the Problem The more capable an LLM Agent becomes, the more tools it registers. File reading, writing, searching, and command execution are the basics. Add …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Why Claude Code's Edit Tool Doesn't Mangle Your Files</title><url>/en/claude-code-edit-tool/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html">  Claude Code&amp;amp;rsquo;s Edit tool has a deceptively simple interface: give it an old_string, give it a new_string, and it finds the former in a file and replaces it with the latter. Sounds like nothing more than a str.replace(). But in the context of an LLM Agent, this seemingly trivial operation is backed by an entire engineering pipeline spanning string sanitization to concurrency safety. The model stuffs line numbers into its replacement strings. It conjures curly quotes out of thin air. External tools modify the target file while the user is still reviewing the permission dialog. The Edit tool has to stay correct through all of this — far more than find-and-replace can handle.
From observing its behavior, the Edit tool&amp;amp;rsquo;s execution breaks down into three phases: API-layer preprocessing (before the tool even receives input), input validation (before the permission dialog is shown), and the actual write (after the user approves). Each phase handles a distinct class of problems and …  </content></entry><entry><title>Claude Code's Undercover Mode: When AI Learns to Hide Itself</title><url>/en/claude-code-undercover/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Claude Code has a mode that appears in no documentation whatsoever. When active, it systematically erases every trace of AI involvement. No Co-Authored-By trailer, no &amp;ldquo;Generated with Claude Code&amp;rdquo; footer, and the system prompt itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t even tell the model what it is. This mode is called Undercover Mode. It exists only in Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s internal builds; external users will never see it, because dead code elimination strips the entire feature out during public builds.
The behavioral implications are telling: this mechanism exists because Anthropic employees routinely use Claude Code to commit to public repositories. Without some form of protection, commit messages might contain unreleased model codenames, PR descriptions might expose internal project names, and model identifiers in the system prompt could leak through some vector or another. Undercover Mode is designed to plug all of these holes.
Activation Conditions Undercover Mode activation is not based on …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How Forked Sub-Agents Share Prompt Cache for 90% Savings</title><url>/en/claude-code-fork-cache/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html">  When tackling complex tasks, Claude Code spawns multiple sub-agents in parallel, each needing the full parent conversation context. If the parent has accumulated 100K tokens and three sub-agents are spawned, a naive implementation charges 300K tokens of input.
Anyone familiar with LLM inference optimization will recognize this immediately: it&amp;amp;rsquo;s a KV Cache sharing problem. When multiple requests share the same prefix, the Attention layer&amp;amp;rsquo;s Key/Value tensors can be reused, skipping redundant computation. Anthropic exposes this capability to API users as Prompt Cache, offering a 90% discount on cached prefix portions — but only if the prefix bytes are exactly identical across requests. Claude Code&amp;amp;rsquo;s fork sub-agents are deliberately constructed so that over 99% of the bytes are identical, compressing the effective input cost of three sub-agents to roughly 120K token-equivalent (100K full price + 2 × 100K × 10%).
Byte-Identical, Not Semantically Equivalent The prompt cache …  </content></entry><entry><title>Context Compaction in Claude Code: A Five-Layer Cascade and the Art of Free Summaries</title><url>/en/claude-code-context-compaction/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  A 200K context window sounds generous — until you&amp;rsquo;re in a moderately complex coding session. Read a few dozen files, run several rounds of grep, execute some bash commands, and you&amp;rsquo;ve already burned through most of it. Compaction is inevitable, but compaction itself costs money: you need an LLM call to generate a summary, and the input to that call is the very context you&amp;rsquo;re trying to compress. This creates a fascinating engineering trade-off: compact too early and you lose useful information; compact too late and the window overflows; and the cost of compaction itself can&amp;rsquo;t be ignored. Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s answer is a multi-layer cascade: avoid compaction if you can, do it cheaply if you must, and only call the LLM as a last resort.
Layer 0: Persisting Large Results to Disk Before any compaction happens, Claude Code controls the volume of data entering the context at the source. When a tool returns a result exceeding a threshold (50K characters by default), the …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How Claude Code Defends Against Bash Injection</title><url>/en/claude-code-bash-security/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[   The security challenge of AI-executed Bash commands isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;should we trust the model&amp;rdquo; — it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;how do we make sure a command actually means what it looks like.&amp;rdquo;
Claude Code lets AI execute Bash commands directly. Not through a structured interface like MCP; it literally gives the model a shell. MCP&amp;rsquo;s approach wraps tools into JSON schemas, which is safe enough, but you can&amp;rsquo;t realistically write adapters for thousands of CLI tools. The capability ceiling is obvious. A raw shell can do anything; the tradeoff is that the security problem shifts from &amp;ldquo;controlling interface permissions&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;figuring out what a command actually does.&amp;rdquo; In the previous post, I covered how YOLO Classifier uses AI to review AI, but the Classifier works with the full command string and makes a semantic judgment: is this operation dangerous? Before that judgment even happens, there&amp;rsquo;s a deeper question that needs answering: does this …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Inside Claude Code's YOLO Classifier</title><url>/en/claude-code-auto-mode-security/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[   Claude Code has an auto mode that executes operations without confirmation. But &amp;ldquo;auto&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean &amp;ldquo;unreviewed&amp;rdquo; — there&amp;rsquo;s a classifier watching every action.
The Auto Mode Paradox One of the most annoying things about using Claude Code is the permission popups. Every Bash command, every file write requires a confirmation click. Power users turn on auto mode, letting Claude execute everything autonomously without asking.
This creates an obvious problem: what if the model decides to rm -rf /, push to the production branch, or write a backdoor into .bashrc?
Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s solution isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;trust the model&amp;rdquo; — it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;use another AI to review this AI.&amp;rdquo; The source module is called YOLO Classifier. YOLO stands for You Only Live Once, a self-deprecating name for a &amp;ldquo;just do it&amp;rdquo; mode. But inside this &amp;ldquo;just do it&amp;rdquo; mode, every step is actually being questioned.
Why Not a Rule Engine The first …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Dissecting Claude Code's RAG Mechanism</title><url>/en/claude-code-rag/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>LLM</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>NLP</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[   Claude Code has no vector database and no embedding index, yet it can pinpoint the exact file you need in a million-line codebase. Behind this is a retrieval architecture completely different from traditional RAG.
This Isn&amp;rsquo;t the RAG You Know If you&amp;rsquo;ve used RAG before, the pipeline should be familiar: build an offline index, user asks a question, vector-search for Top-K chunks, inject into prompt, generate an answer. A straight line, one pass, done.
Claude Code doesn&amp;rsquo;t work like that at all. It has no offline index. The model itself drives the retrieval process.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 Traditional RAG: +--------+ +-----------+ +----------+ +--------+ | Query | --&amp;gt; | Vector DB | --&amp;gt; | Top-K | --&amp;gt; | LLM | | | | (offline | | chunks | | answer | | | | indexed) | | injected | | | +--------+ +-----------+ +----------+ +--------+ One-shot: retrieve once, generate once. Claude Code (Agentic RAG): +--------+ +------------------+ …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>LLMs Are the Monkeys That Finally Typed Shakespeare</title><url>/en/llm-infinite-monkeys/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>Thoughts</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Nassim Taleb proposed a thought experiment in Fooled by Randomness: given infinite monkeys typing on infinite typewriters, one of them will eventually produce the complete text of the Iliad.
The more I think about it, the more I believe this story&amp;rsquo;s endgame is today&amp;rsquo;s large language models.
Monkeys, Shakespeare, and an Underappreciated Metaphor Let&amp;rsquo;s lay out the classic thought experiment clearly.
The infinite monkey theorem states: given enough time and enough random attempts, any ordered content can emerge from randomness. A single monkey typing for ten thousand years will almost certainly produce gibberish, but infinite monkeys typing for infinite time? Probability 1. The complete works of Shakespeare, Einstein&amp;rsquo;s papers on relativity, your diary entry for tomorrow, all of it will theoretically appear.
Taleb used this example to illustrate survivorship bias: if ten thousand fund managers operate randomly, one of them will inevitably beat the market for ten …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>A Deep Dive into Claude Code's Memory Management</title><url>/en/claude-code-memory-management/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>LLM</tag><tag>Product</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Developers who&amp;rsquo;ve used Claude Code probably share this experience: even in an ultra-long conversation where dozens of files have been modified, it seems to always &amp;ldquo;remember&amp;rdquo; what it did before. Even more remarkably, if you told it &amp;ldquo;I prefer bun over npm&amp;rdquo; in a previous session, it automatically follows that preference next time.
Behind this is a sophisticated memory management system. Let&amp;rsquo;s tear apart Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s memory mechanism layer by layer.
Global Architecture: A Three-Layer Memory System Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s memory management can be compared to the human memory system:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 +----------------------------------------------------------+ | Persistent Memory (Long-term Memory) | | memdir: MEMORY.md index + topic files | | Persisted across sessions | +----------------------------------------------------------+ | Session Memory (Working Memory) | | Background sub-agent maintains Markdown summary | | Valid within a single …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Agents Are Supposed to Help, So Why Are We More Exhausted?</title><url>/en/why-agents-make-us-more-tired/</url><categories><category>NLP</category></categories><tags><tag>Thoughts</tag><tag>Product</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>LLM Agent</tag><tag>LLM</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated my blog in over a year. Not out of laziness, nor because I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on technology. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a conviction: once AI became powerful enough, the value of technical blogs dropped significantly. People shifted from searching and reading to learning through direct conversations with AI. On top of that, AI-generated content floods social media the moment anything happens, making me feel there&amp;rsquo;s little point in writing after the fact. Blog traffic has plummeted over the past year, which further killed my motivation to spend hours crafting a post. I miss the days when every article was painstakingly typed out, word by word, over hours or even days.
AI tools have made remarkable progress in the past six months. As a heavy user, I want to talk about this: if agents are supposed to be our helpers, why do we feel more exhausted than ever?
The Current Workflow Agents are now involved in every stage of a feature, from start to finish. Feasibility …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>TeX Live mktexmf cannot find font solution</title><url>/en/tex-mktexmf-cannot-find-font/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html">  When compiling a LaTeX document that uses a customized font in TeX Live on Windows, you might encounter the following error:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 kpathsea: Running mktextfm Fontin The command name is F:\texlive\2025\bin\windows\mktextfm name = Fontin, rootname = Fontin, pointsize = mktexmf: empty or non-existent rootfile! kpathsea: Running mktexmf Fontin.mf The command name is F:\texlive\2025\bin\windows\mktexmf Cannot find Fontin.mf. kpathsea: Appending font creation commands to missfont.log. kpathsea: Running mktextfm Fontin The command name is F:\texlive\2025\bin\windows\mktextfm name = Fontin, rootname = Fontin, pointsize = mktexmf: empty or non-existent rootfile! kpathsea: Running mktexmf Fontin.mf The command name is F:\texlive\2025\bin\windows\mktexmf Cannot find Fontin.mf. This error occurs because the TeX system cannot find the necessary font files (specifically .mf or .tfm files) for Fontin, and fails to generate them. The weird part is that you have installed the font already.
Solution is straightforward: Install the font for all users on your Windows system.
Locate the Fontin font file (e.g., Fontin.ttf). Right-click the file. Choose Install for all users from the context menu. After installing the font for all users, recompile your document. The error should disappear.
  </content></entry><entry><title>Mastering MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline for Efficient Data Processing</title><url>/en/mastering-mongodb-aggregation-pipeline-for-efficient-data-processing/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  MongoDB&amp;rsquo;s Aggregation Pipeline is a powerful tool for processing and analyzing data, suitable for both real-time queries and offline data analysis. It allows developers to use multiple stages to transform, filter, group, and sort data, enabling efficient execution of complex computations. This article will explore the basic concepts, application examples, performance analysis, and optimization strategies of the Aggregation Pipeline.
Aggregation Pipeline Basics The Aggregation Pipeline consists of multiple stages, each responsible for a specific data processing task, such as:
$match: Filters documents, similar to SQL&amp;rsquo;s WHERE, reducing the amount of data scanned. For example, SELECT * FROM orders WHERE status = &#39;active&#39;; is equivalent to { &amp;quot;$match&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;status&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;active&amp;quot; } }.
$group: Groups data and computes aggregate values, similar to SQL&amp;rsquo;s GROUP BY. For example, SELECT category, COUNT(*) FROM orders GROUP BY category; can be achieved in …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>SwitchyOmega No Longer Be Supported Solution</title><url>/en/switchyomega-no-longer-be-supported-solution/</url><categories><category>Networking</category></categories><tags><tag>Networking</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Today, when I opened Chrome, I suddenly received a prompt saying that SwitchyOmega &ldquo;# This extension may soon no longer be supported because it doesn&rsquo;t follow best practices for Chrome extensions.&rdquo; It seems that the plugin was disabled after Chrome automatically updated. Another bad news: the Stylish plugin has also been rendered unusable for the same reason.
Moreover, the Chrome Web Store is inaccessible, preventing the installation of other extensions—deadlock.
The solution is to search for “ZeroOmega” on Bing. It is a forked alternative to SwitchyOmega: ZeroOmega .
If SwitchyOmega is currently available, you can install it directly from the Chrome Web Store. # Proxy SwitchyOmega 3 (ZeroOmega) If you cannot access Chrome Web Store, the installation method is a little bit tricky: download the latest &ldquo;.crx&rdquo; file (note: not the zip file) from the Releases page on the GitHub site above. Then, change its extension to &ldquo;.rar&rdquo; and extract it into a folder. Note: Locally installed extensions cannot be updated automatically, and they will become invalid if the local directory is deleted. Therefore, the configuration here is only intended to enable access to the Chrome Web Store and install the official extension from the above link.
Next, go to the chrome://extensions/ page, click &ldquo;Load unpacked extension,&rdquo; and select the extracted folder to install it locally.
If you previously exported a SwitchyOmega proxy configuration file, you can import it directly after installation for a seamless transition. Otherwise, you can refer to # Exporting SwitchyOmega config when it cannot be enabled .
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Solving Double-Spending with MongoDB: Transactions vs. Versioning</title><url>/en/solving-double-spending-with-mongodb/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  The double-spending problem is a critical challenge in transaction systems, especially when managing account balances or funds. It occurs when a system allows the same funds to be spent multiple times due to concurrent operations or race conditions. In this article, we explore two approaches to resolving this issue using MongoDB: transaction-based handling and versioning-based handling.
This post is an in-depth discussion of the double-spending problem from the Building a Transaction System with MongoDB blog.
Problem Overview Consider a system where users can initiate transactions like purchases. If two requests attempt to spend the same funds concurrently, the system may incorrectly process both, leading to an invalid state. For example:
User A has $100 in their account. Two concurrent processes try to deduct $60 each. Without safeguards, the system might process both, resulting in a balance of $-20. MongoDB provides tools to prevent such issues, ensuring consistency and correctness …  </content></entry><entry><title>How to Fix Windows 11 RDP Black Screen After Windows Update</title><url>/en/how-to-fix-win11-rdp-black-screen/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html">  After a Windows Update, RDP on Windows 11 might stop working correctly. Symptoms include a black screen upon connection, no visible mouse or interface, and an automatic disconnection after about a minute. This forces users to return to the local machine to investigate the issue.
Troubleshooting the Issue Checking the RDP settings and firewall configurations revealed no issues. Given that black screen problems are common on Linux systems and often related to drivers, it was suspected that the NIC driver might be causing the issue.
Since the connection succeeded but disconnected after one minute, the wireless NIC was identified as a possible culprit.
Initially, the energy-saving option to &amp;ldquo;allow the computer to turn off this device to save power&amp;rdquo; in the wireless NIC settings was disabled, but the problem persisted.
In Device Manager, it was discovered that the NIC driver had recently been updated: The NIC in question was Realtek 8811CU Wireless LAN 802.11ac USB NIC with a driver version of 1030.44.1014.2024.
Solution: Rolling Back the NIC Driver The issue was resolved by rolling back the NIC driver to the previous version 1030.38.712.2019. After doing this, the Remote Desktop (mstsc) started functioning normally again, with no black screen.
Steps to Roll Back the NIC Driver Open Device Manager.
Expand the Network adapters category.
Right-click on the NIC (Realtek 8811CU Wireless LAN 802.11ac USB NIC) and select Properties.
Go to the Driver tab.
Click on Roll Back Driver and follow the on-screen instructions. Restart your computer to apply the changes.
Test RDP to ensure the issue is resolved.
By following these steps, the RDP black screen issue caused by the NIC driver update can be effectively fixed.
  </content></entry><entry><title>How to Set Crontab Timezone</title><url>/en/how-to-set-crontab-timezone/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag></tags><content type="html">  If you’ve ever struggled to set the correct timezone for your cron jobs on Ubuntu 22.04, you’re not alone. In this blog, we’ll walk you through a troubleshooting journey that highlights common pitfalls and the ultimate solution.
The Problem: Why Isn’t My Cron Task Running as Expected? Imagine this scenario: you set up a cron job to run at a specific time, but it doesn’t execute as planned. After some digging, you realize the issue might be related to timezones. You try a few fixes but nothing seems to work.
Step 1: Trying CRON_TZ Modern cron implementations support the CRON_TZ variable, which allows you to specify the timezone for individual cron jobs. Here’s an example for crontab -e:
1 2 CRON_TZ=Asia/Shanghai 0 8 * * * /path/to/your/script.sh In theory, this should ensure the job runs at 8:00 AM Beijing Time. However, CRON_TZ doesn’t work as expected on my Ubuntu 22.04.
Step 2: Setting the System Timezone with timedatectl Try setting the system timezone globally using timedatectl:
1 sudo timedatectl set-timezone Asia/Shanghai This command updates the system timezone, and you can verify it with:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 $ timedatectl Local time: Fri 2024-12-06 20:44:09 CST Universal time: Fri 2024-12-06 12:44:09 UTC RTC time: Fri 2024-12-06 12:44:09 Time zone: Asia/Shanghai (CST, +0800) System clock synchronized: yes NTP service: active RTC in local TZ: no Unfortunately, I found that crontab still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.
Step 3: The Real Culprit: Restarting the Cron Service The key step that many people overlook is restarting the cron service after making timezone changes. By default, cron reads the system timezone during startup and doesn’t automatically refresh it when the system timezone changes.
To fix this, simply restart the cron service:
1 sudo systemctl restart cron.service Once restarted, cron will use the updated timezone.
Step-by-Step Guide To avoid any issues with cron and timezones on Ubuntu 22.04, follow these steps:
Set the Desired Timezone Globally:
1 sudo timedatectl set-timezone Asia/Shanghai Verify the Timezone:
1 timedatectl Restart the Cron Service:
1 sudo systemctl restart cron.service   </content></entry><entry><title>Use az cli to Query VM Remaining CPU Credits</title><url>/en/use-az-cli-to-query-vm-cpu-credits/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When working with Azure Virtual Machines (VMs), monitoring performance metrics is essential for ensuring optimal operation. A common scenario involves tracking the CPU Credits Remaining for a B-series burstable VM instance.
Typically, we use az vm monitor metrics tail to get the CPU Credits Remaining metric:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 $ az vm monitor metrics tail -g $group -n $name --metric &#34;CPU Credits Remaining&#34; 2&gt;/dev/null { &#34;cost&#34;: 59, &#34;interval&#34;: &#34;PT1M&#34;, &#34;namespace&#34;: &#34;Microsoft.Compute/virtualMachines&#34;, &#34;resourceregion&#34;: &#34;xx&#34;, &#34;timespan&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T09:25:10Z/2024-12-02T10:25:10Z&#34;, &#34;value&#34;: [ { &#34;displayDescription&#34;: &#34;Total number of credits available to burst. Only available on B-series burstable VMs&#34;, &#34;errorCode&#34;: &#34;Success&#34;, &#34;id&#34;: &#34;/subscriptions/xx/resourceGroups/xx/providers/Microsoft.Compute/virtualMachines/xx/providers/Microsoft.Insights/metrics/CPU Credits Remaining&#34;, &#34;name&#34;: { &#34;localizedValue&#34;: &#34;CPU Credits Remaining&#34;, &#34;value&#34;: &#34;CPU Credits Remaining&#34; }, &#34;resourceGroup&#34;: &#34;Linux&#34;, &#34;timeseries&#34;: [ { &#34;data&#34;: [ { &#34;average&#34;: 113.08, &#34;timeStamp&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T09:25:00Z&#34; }, ... { &#34;average&#34;: 124.48, &#34;timeStamp&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T10:22:00Z&#34; }, { &#34;average&#34;: 124.68, &#34;timeStamp&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T10:23:00Z&#34; }, { &#34;timeStamp&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T10:24:00Z&#34; } ], &#34;metadatavalues&#34;: [] } ], &#34;type&#34;: &#34;Microsoft.Insights/metrics&#34;, &#34;unit&#34;: &#34;Count&#34; } ] } Breakdown of the Command:
az vm monitor metrics tail: This Azure CLI command fetches the latest metrics for a specific VM. -g $group: Specifies the resource group of the VM. -n $name: Specifies the name of the VM. --metric &quot;CPU Credits Remaining&quot;: Fetches the specific metric showing remaining CPU credits. 2&gt;/dev/null: Redirects any error messages to /dev/null, effectively silencing errors. This ensures that only the valid JSON output is processed further. Since we want get the latest CPU Credits Remaining metric, we need to parse the json output by jq:
1 2 3 4 5 $ az vm monitor metrics tail -g $group -n $name --metric &#34;CPU Credits Remaining&#34; 2&gt;/dev/null | jq -r &#34;.value[0].timeseries[0].data[-2]&#34; { &#34;average&#34;: 137.48, &#34;timeStamp&#34;: &#34;2024-12-02T11:27:00Z&#34; } Here we extract the second-to-last (-2) data point of the CPU Credits metric&rsquo;s time series for analysis because the last data point doesn&rsquo;t contains credit field.
References:
# az vm monitor metrics   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Building a Transaction System with MongoDB</title><url>/en/building-a-transaction-system-with-mongodb/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  Transaction systems are at the heart of modern commerce and financial activities, spanning a wide range of scenarios from e-commerce order processing to real-time settlements in financial institutions. Such systems demand high concurrency handling, real-time data storage, and efficient retrieval capabilities, all while balancing data consistency and performance. As transaction data continues to grow in scale and complexity, traditional transaction system architectures often struggle to meet these challenges due to rigid table structures and limited horizontal scalability.
MongoDB, as a distributed document-oriented database, provides a modern solution for building complex and efficient transaction systems. With its flexible schema design, high throughput capabilities, and built-in transaction support, MongoDB addresses diverse business needs effectively.
Problem Statement and Challenges The core functionalities of a transaction system include account management, balance inquiry, …  </content></entry><entry><title>Certbot: Automating Nginx SSL Renewal</title><url>/en/certbot-automating-nginx-ssl-renewal/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag></tags><content type="html">  Received a certificate renewal notification from Tencent Cloud, but when applying for a new certificate, I found out that Tencent Cloud no longer offers free one-year certificates:
Starting from April 25, 2024, the validity period of new free certificates issued by Tencent Cloud will be adjusted to 90 days.
Since I’ve always updated certificates manually, doing it every three months feels quite tedious. So, I decided to explore Certbot from Let&amp;amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. My only concern was how to prove ownership of a subdomain. After trying it out, I realized this wasn’t an issue at all, as Certbot only issues certificates and doesn’t pose any threat to the website itself.
Here are the configuration steps for Certbot. In fact, it’s very simple and only requires running a few commands.
Installing Certbot Here, I chose to install Certbot using apt instead of the recommended snap. Personally, I find snap to be too heavy compared to the lightweight nature of apt. I also prefer not to see a bunch of …  </content></entry><entry><title>Building Large-Scale Social Network Graphs with MongoDB</title><url>/en/building-large-scale-social-network-graphs-with-mongodb/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  Nowadays, many popular apps incorporate social network features, such as Twitter, WhatsApp, and Facebook. These platforms need to scale to accommodate billions of users (graph nodes), which is no small feat. Building and maintaining a scalable social network infrastructure requires careful planning and strategic data modeling. In fact, specialized social networking applications like Facebook have dedicated teams focusing solely on optimizing their performance to the highest level. However, for smaller apps or startup projects looking to add social networking capabilities, creating a full team to handle such architecture is often impractical and unnecessary.
So, is it possible to build a high-performance, scalable social network using the right data modeling and storage solutions? The answer is yes. Early versions of Facebook used MySQL as the underlying storage to construct their social network, but today we have more advanced and efficient storage options available: MongoDB.
Problem …  </content></entry><entry><title>TypeError: Argument has incorrect type (expected numpy.ndarray, got DataFrame) Solution</title><url>/en/argument-incorrect-type-expected-ndarray/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After upgrading packages in a conda env, talib cannot accept dataframe as input, the error message looks like TypeError: Argument 'xxx' has incorrect type (expected numpy.ndarray, got DataFrame):
1 2 3 4 5 6 Traceback (most recent call last): File &#34;/data/1.py&#34;, line 7, in &lt;module&gt; df[&#39;SMA_5&#39;] = ta.SMA(df[&#39;Close&#39;], timeperiod=5) File &#34;/data/miniconda3/envs/a/lib/python3.10/site-packages/talib/__init__.py&#34;, line 64, in wrapper result = func(*_args, **_kwds) TypeError: Argument &#39;real&#39; has incorrect type (expected numpy.ndarray, got DataFrame) Most of the web search results are misleading, like changing the df into np array. Since the code works before updating packages, the problem should be package incompatibility issue.
The problem can be easily reproduced by the following code:
1 2 3 4 5 import talib as ta import yfinance as yf df = yf.download(&#34;MSFT&#34;, period=&#39;5d&#39;) df[&#39;SMA&#39;] = ta.SMA(df[&#39;Close&#39;], timeperiod=3) Using $ conda list to check the version diff:
Not work version:
1 2 3 4 python 3.10.13 hd12c33a_1_cpython conda-forge pandas 2.1.4 py310h1128e8f_0 ta-lib 0.4.32 py310h8a78493_0 conda-forge yfinance 0.2.48 pyhd8ed1ab_0 conda-forge Work version:
1 2 3 4 python 3.8.20 he870216_0 pandas 1.5.3 py38h417a72b_0 ta-lib 0.4.32 py38he82f83a_0 conda-forge yfinance 0.2.40 pyhd8ed1ab_0 conda-forge BTW, it&rsquo;s not that obvious to find that the root cause is yfinance instead of talib and pandas.
Finally found that talib is work for yfinance 0.2.44 but not work for 0.2.46+.
The solution is to downgrade the yfinance to 0.2.44:
1 $ conda install yfinance=0.2.44 Then talib and pandas works perfectly.
Posted an github issue to yfinance: https://github.com/ranaroussi/yfinance/issues/2107   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Windows 11 drive D usable but not visible in File Explorer</title><url>/en/drive-d-usable-but-not-visible-in-file-explorer/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Today, I encountered a strange issue in Windows 11 where the D drive was visible in the Disk Management tool but not in File Explorer. I searched online for many solutions, such as updating drivers in Device Manager, disabling and re-enabling the device, using diskpart to delete and recreate the partition, changing the volume label, changing the drive letter, etc., but none worked.
Problem Description A new D drive, visible in diskmgmt.msc Disk Management, everything seemed normal. It could even be accessed in File Explorer (though the drive wasn’t displayed in the left sidebar). The D drive could be used normally, such as via the command line. Changing the drive letter to “E” or another letter made it visible in File Explorer, but switching it back to “D” caused it to disappear again. Solution In summary, the problem only appeared in File Explorer, suggesting that the D drive letter was somehow occupied. I also found some articles suggesting showing all hidden folders, but that didn&rsquo;t help. I then considered the issue might be related to a registry key in File Explorer.
Use the shortcut Win + R to open the Run dialog. Type regedit and press Enter to open the Registry Editor. If prompted by UAC (User Account Control), choose &ldquo;Yes&rdquo; to continue. In the Registry Editor, navigate to the following path: 1 HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Polices\Explorer\ Check if there’s a NoDrives key. Delete if exists. In Disk Management, change the drive letter to &ldquo;E&rdquo;, then switch it back to &ldquo;D&rdquo;. At this point, the D drive will appear.   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Use az cli to Query Multiple Fields of Resource Information</title><url>/en/use-az-cli-to-query-multiple-fields/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Use az cli to query multiple fields of VM information. Here we need to use JMESPath language to implement it.
Typically, we will use az vm show to get the detailed VM information:
1 2 3 4 $ az vm show -g Linux -n alpha -d -o table Name ResourceGroup PowerState PublicIps Fqdns Location Zones ------ --------------- ------------ ------------ ------- ---------- ------- alpha Linux VM running 11.1.111.111 eastasia 1 However, this table doesn&rsquo;t contains the VM size. If we remove the -o table argument, the VM size will be shown like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 $ az vm show -g Linux -n alpha -d { &#34;additionalCapabilities&#34;: { &#34;hibernationEnabled&#34;: false, &#34;ultraSsdEnabled&#34;: null }, ... &#34;hardwareProfile&#34;: { &#34;vmSize&#34;: &#34;Standard_D2lds_v5&#34;, &#34;vmSizeProperties&#34;: null }, ... } Then we can get VM information with queries :
1 2 $ az vm show -g Linux -n alpha -d --query &#39;hardwareProfile.vmSize&#39; &#34;Standard_D2lds_v5&#34; Can we get the powerState and the vmSize at the same time? az vm show -g Linux -n alpha -d --query 'hardwareProfile.vmSize' --query 'powerState' doesn&rsquo;t work. So how to query multiple fields of the json?
The answer is using JMESPath language , putting all the required fields in the []:
1 2 3 4 5 $ az vm show -g Linux -n alpha -d --query &#39;[name, resourceGroup, powerState, hardwareProfile.vmSize]&#39; -o tsv alpha Linux VM running Standard_D2lds_v5 References:
# Azure CLI - Query Power state of a virtual machine   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>WinSCP Transfer to Temporary Filename Not Working</title><url>/en/winscp-transfer-to-temp-filename-not-working/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  In WinSCP, I found that when uploading file to the server, the file doesn&rsquo;t have a temporary filename extension &ldquo;.filepart&rdquo;.
Enable temporary filename for all files in &ldquo;Preferences -&gt; Transfer -&gt; Endurance&rdquo; still does not work.
First I think it&rsquo;s a bug for WinSCP 6.3.3, I attempted to use old version 5.21 but it also has the same issue.
After investigation, the reason is that this feature is only available for SFTP protocol, while I use SCP protocol to connect the server.
The solution is to modify the &ldquo;File protocol&rdquo; to SFTP.
Reference:
Locking files while uploading / Upload to temporary file name Transfer was successfully finished, but temporary transfer file … could not be renamed to target file name … SCP vs SFTP - 5 Key Comparisons | JSCAPE Managed File Transfer   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Ubuntu Server Freezes After Several Minutes</title><url>/en/ubuntu-freezes-after-several-minutes/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After upgrading Ubuntu 20.04 LTS to Ubuntu 22.04LTS, the server always freezes after ~10 minutes. All services are down, cannot ssh, connect to serial console but cannot input. However, this issue never happen before release upgrade.
After hard reboot, I tried to find clue in logs.
journalctl -xe has no related error messages.
Then I browse syslog around the server freeze time by less /var/log/syslog and found something interesting:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 ... Apr 17 23:32:08 user NetworkManager[1057]: &lt;info&gt; [1713367928.2254] manager: sleep: sleep requested (sleeping: no enabled: yes) Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: Reached target Sleep. Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: Starting Record successful boot for GRUB... Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: Starting System Suspend... Apr 17 23:32:08 user gnome-shell[1875]: Screen lock is locked down, not locking Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: grub-common.service: Deactivated successfully. Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: Finished Record successful boot for GRUB. Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd[1]: Starting GRUB failed boot detection... Apr 17 23:32:08 user systemd-sleep[2313]: Entering sleep state &#39;suspend&#39;... ^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@^@ ... Seems that the server automatically go to sleep after 10 minutes when idle. Although I never use GUI (ssh console only), I guess the issue is caused by gnome desktop. The release upgrade automatically install gnome which suspends the system when idle.
The solution is easy, just remove all gnome related packages:
1 $ sudo apt remove gnome* It would be better to disable suspend and hibernate in systemd, but I didn&rsquo;t do it.
1 $ sudo systemctl mask sleep.target suspend.target hibernate.target hybrid-sleep.target   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Word Wildcard Replace Bug When Track Changes</title><url>/en/word-wildcard-replace-bug-when-track-changes/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Cannot believe that Word has such a bug: when tracking changes, wildcard replacement cannot correctly work.
I want to batch replace English parentheses with Chinese parentheses, so I use wildcard replacement:
1 2 3 Find What: \((*)\) Options: Use Wildcards Replace With: （\1） For example, for &ldquo;(abc)&rdquo;, the expected result is &ldquo;（abc）&rdquo;, however, the result is &ldquo;abc（）&rdquo;.
The solution is simple: disable track changes.
Reference: Word wildcard find &amp; replace puts strings \1 and \2 out of sequence   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Windows Explorer Crashes on Right Click Menu Solution</title><url>/en/explorer-crash-fix/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html">  Recently, when I attempt to open the property window of a folder in File Explorer, it crashes all the time. It bothers me a lot and I finally fix it by cleaning up the right click context menu.
When we install more software, the right click menu gets messy. Even worse, the bad items might crash your explorer.
Directly manage and modify the right click menu in regedit is tedious and error-prone. Suggest to download a tool such as RightMenuMgr to clean up the menu.
Open the tool and disable useless items in the right category just by a simple click:
For my case, the bad guy is the FormatFactoryShell, which makes the explorer crashes:
HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Classes\Directory\shellex\ContextMenuHandlers\FormatFactoryShell
You can find the bad item by binary-search. After that, just uncheck the item and the problem would be fixed.
  </content></entry><entry><title>ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement Solution</title><url>/en/could-not-find-a-version-that-satisfies-the-requirement-solution/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html">   1 2 3 4 $ pip install torch==1.12.0 Defaulting to user installation because normal site-packages is not writeable ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement torch==1.12.0 (from versions: 1.0.0, 1.0.1, 1.0.1.post2, 1.1.0, 1.2.0, 1.3.0, 1.3.1, 1.4.0, 1.5.0, 1.5.1, 1.6.0, 1.7.0, 1.7.1, 1.8.0, 1.8.1, 1.9.0, 1.9.1, 1.10.0, 1.10.1, 1.10.2) ERROR: No matching distribution found for torch==1.12.0 The root cause is that python version is too low (3.6). We need to upgrade python to a new version.
If you use conda, just create an env xxx with specific python version:
1 2 $ conda create -n xxx python=3.9 $ conda activate xxx If the issue still persists, double check the pip and python version:
1 2 $ pip --version pip 21.3.1 from /data/.local/lib/python3.6/site-packages/pip (python 3.6) The above issue can be easily bypassed by python -m pip:
1 2 $ python -m pip --version pip 23.0.1 from /data/miniconda3/envs/alpaca/lib/python3.9/site-packages/pip (python 3.9) Then everything works fine:
1 2 3 4 5 $ python -m pip install torch==1.12.0 Looking in indexes: https://pypi.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/simple Collecting torch==1.12.0 Downloading https://pypi.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/packages/8f/27/addb0019d7aa3704576ca9c055f7566a3db31f95110e55b31173b87aec4a/torch-1.12.0-cp39-cp39-manylinux1_x86_64.whl (776.3 MB) ━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━ 776.3/776.3 MB 1.8 MB/s eta 0:00:00   </content></entry><entry><title>Hexo Set Environment Variable</title><url>/en/how-to-set-hexo-env/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently I upgrade NexT theme to v8.14.1. The related post plugin hexo-related-popular-posts had been replaced by hexo-related-posts, which generates related posts by tf-idf algorithm. However, the compute cost is a little bit heavy if you have many posts. A good trade-off is enable this feature only for production environment. The plugin hexo-related-posts already takes this into account and use enable_env_name to disable its execution. Unfortunately, the document has typo so I takes some time to fix it.
So how to set environment variable in Hexo?
Short Answer：$ hexo &lt;command&gt; --&lt;env_key&gt; env_value。
The following secitons will illustrate how to enable related post on production.
Requirements Use hexo server to preview post in local, disable related post Enable related post on production, deploy by GitHub Action How to check if the related post is enabled? Just check the hexo s or hexo g log:
1 2 3 4 5 INFO Start processing INFO Calculating of related posts is enabled. Start processing... INFO TF/IDF is calculated INFO Related post processing done ... Set Environment Variable hexo-related-posts document：
It&rsquo;s possible to disable plugin execution depending on env variable. For example, if you want to calculate related post only for production build, you can set this parameter to prod. In this case, related post will be generated only if you put prod key during running Hexo, i.e. hexo generate -- --prod
However, hexo generate -- --prod doesn&rsquo;t work. Check the source code:
1 2 const enable = (hexo.config.related_posts.enable || hexo.config.related_posts.enable === undefined) &amp;&amp; (hexo.config.related_posts.enable_env_name !== undefined ? hexo.env.args[hexo.config.related_posts.enable_env_name] : true); Hexo official document # Variables doesn&rsquo;t explain how to pass value to global variable env. The problem reduced to how to pass value to hexo.env.args.
Refer to this post # Hexo Environment Variables , just add parameter after hexo commands, then hexo.env.args will contains the key prod:
1 2 $ hexo server --prod $ hexo generate --prod If you want to pass a key/value pair, do it like this: hexo server --prod 1 .
Modify Config and GitHub Action Workflow Modify hexo _config.yml:
1 2 3 4 related_posts: enable: true enable_env_name: prod icon: fa fa-signs-post Modify theme NexT _config.yml
1 2 3 related_posts: enable: true icon: fa fa-signs-post Since we # Deploy Hexo by GitHub Actions , modify the action workflow file like this (append --prod after hexo g):
1 2 3 4 5 6 - name: Hexo run: | pandoc --version npm i -g hexo-cli npm i hexo clean &amp;&amp; hexo g --prod Then related posts will be disabled by default (local hexo s).
Tips： hexo-related-posts has cache, to test if it&rsquo;s enabled, modify any posts or do hexo clean first.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Git Sync Remote Branch Automatically by Webhook</title><url>/en/git-sync-remote-branch-automatically-by-webhook/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  How to make your local repository always sync with GitHub repository? The answer is webhook.
When the repo received a push event, GitHub will send a POST request to the webhook URL with details of any subscribed events. What we need to do is to implement a webhook (on local side) which performs git pull to keep sync with remote.
Simplest GitHub Webhook Implementation What&rsquo;s a webhook?
Webhooks allow you to build or set up integrations, such as GitHub Apps or OAuth Apps, which subscribe to certain events on GitHub.com. When one of those events is triggered, we&rsquo;ll send a HTTP POST payload to the webhook&rsquo;s configured URL. Webhooks can be used to update an external issue tracker, trigger CI builds, update a backup mirror, or even deploy to your production server. You&rsquo;re only limited by your imagination
Here we implement a simplest webhook which handles push event from GitHub. No secret, no payload parsing, just git pull --ff-only origin master when receiving the push event. More complicated webhook development can refer to here .
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 #!/usr/bin/python import git import logging from flask import Flask logging.basicConfig(level=logging.INFO) app = Flask(&#39;gitwebhook&#39;) def pull(): repo = git.Repo(&#39;/home/local/repo/folder&#39;) repo.git.checkout(&#39;master&#39;) repo.git.pull(&#39;--ff-only&#39;, &#39;origin&#39;, &#39;master&#39;) @app.route(&#39;/push&#39;,methods = [&#39;POST&#39;]) def handle_push(): logging.info(&#34;Received push event&#34;) try: pull() except Exception as ex: return str(ex), 500 return &#39;Success&#39; if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;: app.run(host=&#39;0.0.0.0&#39;, port=5000) The above code is pretty clean and self-explained. We use Flask as the webserver and leverage gitpython to perform git operations.
Then we can serve the webhook on your local machine which can access the local repo /home/local/repo/folder. Assume the server is running at https://example.com:5000/.
Configure Webhook on GitHub Goto repo Settings -&gt; Webhooks -&gt; Add Webhook:
Done.
Let&rsquo;s check the delivery result by clicking the webhooks detail, Recent Deliveries:
The webhook return success if it pulls remote master by fast-forward, otherwise, an exception will be thrown and return HTTP 500.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>When Using Proxy in Chrome, DNS Is Performed on Which Side?</title><url>/en/chrome-using-proxy-dns-is-done-client-side-or-proxy-side/</url><categories><category>Networking</category></categories><tags><tag>Networking</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When using proxy (e.g. SwitchyOmega) in Chrome, name resolution (DNS) is performed on client side or proxy side? Let&rsquo;s explore how it works.
The test in this post is done by Chrome 107.0.5304.107, SwitchyOmega with HTTP proxy.
First, we should find an unvisited website, here we use example.com.
Start Wireshark locally, apply filter dns to capture DNS traffic Direct visit example.com Now, Wireshark captures DNS traffic locally:
Then, we clear local DNS cache by:
1 &gt; ipconfig /flushdns Start tcpdump on proxy server: $ tcpdump -i eth0 port 53 Use proxy and visit example.com Now tcpdump captures DNS traffic on the proxy server:
1 2 3 4 5 $ tcpdump -i eth0 port 53 tcpdump: verbose output suppressed, use -v or -vv for full protocol decode listening on eth0, link-type EN10MB (Ethernet), capture size 262144 bytes 19:08:53.073284 IP xx.net.31379 &gt; 69.63.19.16.domain: 41145+ [1au] A? example.com. (40) 19:08:53.073427 IP xx.net.48504 &gt; 69.63.19.16.domain: 62656+ [1au] AAAA? example.com. (40) Conclusion: When using proxy in Chrome, name resolution is performed on proxy side.
Here are documents to explain this for SOCKSv5 proxy. It seems that the same mechanism is applied for HTTP proxy as well：
In Chrome when a proxy&rsquo;s scheme is set to SOCKSv5, name resolution is always done proxy side (even though the protocol allows for client side as well). In Firefox client side vs proxy side name resolution can be configured with network.proxy.socks_remote_dns; Chrome has no equivalent option and will always use proxy side resolution.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>ENOTDIR: not a directory, open package.json Solution</title><url>/en/npm-enotdir-error-solution/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When I install elasticdump, the following error appears:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 $ npm install elasticdump ... npm WARN @1.0.0 No description npm WARN @1.0.0 No repository field. npm ERR! Linux 5.4.0-1091-azure npm ERR! argv &#34;/usr/bin/node&#34; &#34;/usr/bin/npm&#34; &#34;install&#34; &#34;elasticdump&#34; npm ERR! node v8.10.0 npm ERR! npm v3.5.2 npm ERR! path /home/finisky/node_modules/.staging/@types/node-1f2b596d/package.json npm ERR! code ENOTDIR npm ERR! errno -20 npm ERR! syscall open npm ERR! ENOTDIR: not a directory, open &#39;/home/finisky/node_modules/.staging/@types/node-1f2b596d/package.json&#39; I spent hours to figure out the root cause: npm is deprecated (v3.5.2).
Solve the issue is easy, just upgrade npm:
1 2 $ curl -sL https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_16.x | sudo -E bash - $ sudo apt install nodejs Then:
1 2 $ npm --version 8.19.2 Reinstall elasticdump and you are done!
1 $ npm install elasticdump   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Git reset --hard Not Working: File System Is Not Case Sensitive</title><url>/en/git-is-case-sensitive-while-file-system-is-not/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  git reset --hard not working: everytime you reset, the file is flipped between file.txt and File.txt, really weird&hellip;
It&rsquo;s not a joke, just clone this repo on Windows and you can reproduce it:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 D:\$ git clone https://github.com/finisky/git-case-demo.git Cloning into &#39;git-case-demo&#39;... remote: Enumerating objects: 11, done. remote: Counting objects: 100% (11/11), done. remote: Compressing objects: 100% (6/6), done. remote: Total 11 (delta 0), reused 8 (delta 0), pack-reused 0 Unpacking objects: 100% (11/11), 1.85 KiB | 126.00 KiB/s, done. warning: the following paths have collided (e.g. case-sensitive paths on a case-insensitive filesystem) and only one from the same colliding group is in the working tree: &#39;File.txt&#39; &#39;file.txt&#39; After clone the repo, you will find that the main branch is not clean. git reset --hard not working:
Browse the repo on GitHub, you will find that the folder structure are different with local:
GitHub has two files File.txt and file.txt, while local has only one file file.txt. GitHub has two folders Folder and folder, while local has only one folder Folder. That&rsquo;s why git reset --hard not working:
git is case-sensitive, while filesystem is not。
So the problem occurs on Windows only. Windows regards File.txt and file.txt as the same file. Linux/Mac is case-sensitive as git, so the problem will never happen.
Similarly, Windows regards Folder and folder as the same one, so the files will be merged into one folder.
Typically, the issue will be found when you configure CICD pipeline. Your local development environment is Windows but the build agent is Linux. It&rsquo;s hard to debug as it reports that files are not found while they are in your Windows folder&hellip;
Solution Apparently we can fix it in a case-sensitive environment such as Linux/Mac. The problem is, what if we don&rsquo;t have such environment (Windows only)?
The solution is to use git command git mv.
Fix Case-Insensitive Files Assume we keep the lower case file and use the upper case file to overwrite it:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git mv File.txt file.txt (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git status On branch fixconflicts Changes to be committed: (use &#34;git restore --staged &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to unstage) deleted: File.txt modified: file.txt Note that directly deleting File.txt on Windows doesn&rsquo;t work, as both files will be deleted:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git status On branch fixconflicts Changes not staged for commit: (use &#34;git add/rm &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to update what will be committed) (use &#34;git restore &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to discard changes in working directory) deleted: File.txt deleted: file.txt no changes added to commit (use &#34;git add&#34; and/or &#34;git commit -a&#34;) Finally, commit changes and the branch will be clean.
Merge Case-Insensitive Folders Merge the two folders by two git mv:
1 2 $ git mv Folder temp $ git mv temp folder The idea is rename it to a different folder temp first, and then merge temp with folder:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git mv Folder temp (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git status On branch fixconflicts Changes to be committed: (use &#34;git restore --staged &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to unstage) renamed: Folder/file2.txt -&gt; temp/file2.txt Changes not staged for commit: (use &#34;git add/rm &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to update what will be committed) (use &#34;git restore &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to discard changes in working directory) deleted: folder/file1.txt Untracked files: (use &#34;git add &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to include in what will be committed) temp/file1.txt (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git mv temp folder (fixconflicts -&gt; origin)D:\git-case-demo$ git status On branch fixconflicts Changes to be committed: (use &#34;git restore --staged &lt;file&gt;...&#34; to unstage) renamed: Folder/file2.txt -&gt; folder/file2.txt Demo Demo Repo: https://github.com/finisky/git-case-demo FYI, the fixconflicts branch resolves all issues according to this article.
Reference # Git is case-sensitive and your filesystem may not be - Weird folder merging on Windows # Git on Windows: &ldquo;merging&rdquo; 2 directories with the same name but different case # Git case sensitivity   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Migrate GitHub Pages by 301 Redirects</title><url>/en/migrate-github-pages-by-301-redirects/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>SEO</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  GitHub Pages cannot perform HTTP 301 redirects as you cannot modify the server config. However, 301 redirects is really crucial for SEO. In order to keep the site ranking, you need to 301 redirects the old GitHub Pages to your new site, and manually notify Google Search Console :
Do you lose credit for links when you redirect to new URLs?
No, 301 or 302 redirects do not cause a loss in PageRank
So how to migrate GitHub Pages to a new site without losing site ranking?
Prerequisite A domain name The idea is that we leverage GitHub Pages custom domain to perform 301 redirects.
Migration Steps Assume that you want to migrate oldsite.github.io to newsite.vercel.app. You have a domain name newsite.com.
Add a Record Go to your domain registrar (e.g. GoDaddy) and add a record newsite.com -&gt; oldsite.github.io.
Add a custom domain in GitHub Pages (301 redirects) Go to: GitHub Pages Repository Settings -&gt; Pages -&gt; Custom domain
Add your domain name (e.g. newsite.com) to the custom domain and press Save.
After a while, the site refreshed:
1 Your site is live at https://newsite.com/ Use curl to visit https://oldsite.github.io and you will find that the site is 301 redirect to the custom domain name:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 $ curl -I https://oldsite.github.io HTTP/1.1 301 Moved Permanently Connection: keep-alive Content-Length: 162 Server: GitHub.com Content-Type: text/html permissions-policy: interest-cohort=() Location: http://newsite.com/ ... Now your site is available at both https://newsite.com/ and https://oldsite.github.io.
Update the Record Go to your domain registrar and update the record to the final target: newsite.com -&gt; newsite.vercel.app (vercel/azure websites/self hosting).
Now your site is hosted on both https://newsite.com/ (newsite.vercel.app) and https://oldsite.github.io. All traffic to the old site will be 301 redirected to the new site.
After several days (half a year or longer), your site will be completely migrated to the new site without pagerank loss. Then you can safely deleted the old GitHub Pages.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Clear Chrome DNS and Disk Cache</title><url>/en/clear-chrome-cache/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html">  I bind a custom domain finisky.eu.org to the github pages finisky.github.io and then remove it. However, when I visit finisky.github.io, it always redirects to finisky.eu.org which is unavailable. I suspect the issue is caused by cache.
First, try to clear/flush the Chrome DNS cache . Just go to chrome://net-internals/#dns and press Clear host cache:
However, when I access finisky.github.io, it still 301 redirects to finisky.eu.org.
If I access finisky.github.io by Edge/IE/curl, everything works fine. Visit https://finisky.github.io/?xx is also fine. So the issue is caused by Chrome.
Use Chrome F12 to debug:
It clearly shows that the website is loaded from disk cache.
Right-click the item and press Clear browser cache, done!
Reference: # Troubleshooting custom domains and GitHub Pages   </content></entry><entry><title>'pandoc exited with code null' Solution</title><url>/en/pandoc-exited-with-code-null-solution/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>Markdown</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  As the post number increases, Hexo generate posts slower and slower. Recently, it usually generates posts for several minutes and report the following error:
[ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] pandoc exited with code null. at Object._prettifyError (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/lib.js:36:11)
I spent several hours to figure out the issue. Finally, I found the root cause is &hellip; VM memory is too small &hellip; :-(
Observations The GitHub actions is able to sucessfully generate the whole sites Remove the largest markdown file and it works htop shows that the swap space is exhausted So I guess the issue is caused by the VM&rsquo;s limited resource, especially the RAM size (only 1G).
Solution The solution is easy: increase the swap space.
Follow this post and create a new swap file:
1 2 3 4 sudo fallocate -l 512M /swapfile sudo chmod 600 /swapfile sudo mkswap /swapfile sudo swapon /swapfile Double check the swap space by htop. Now Hexo works again!
The full error message:
======================================== NexT version 8.5.0 Documentation: https://theme-next.js.org ======================================== INFO Start processing FATAL { err: Template render error: (unknown path) Error: [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] On undefined [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] pandoc exited with code null. at Object._prettifyError (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/lib.js:36:11) at /home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:563:19 at Template.root [as rootRenderFunc] (eval at _compile (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:633:18), :53:3) at Template.render (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:552:10) at Environment.renderString (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:380:17) at /home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/extend/tag.js:236:16 at tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Function.Promise.fromNode.Promise.fromCallback (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:209:30) at Tag.render (/home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/extend/tag.js:235:20) at Object.onRenderEnd (/home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/hexo/post.js:297:22) at /home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/hexo/render.js:79:21 at tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Promise._settlePromiseFromHandler (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:547:31) at Promise._settlePromise (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:604:18) at Promise._settlePromise0 (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:649:10) at Promise._settlePromises (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:729:18) at _drainQueueStep (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:93:12) at _drainQueue (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:86:9) at Async._drainQueues (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:102:5) at Immediate.Async.drainQueues (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:15:14) at processImmediate (node:internal/timers:464:21) { cause: Template render error: (unknown path) Error: [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] On undefined [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] pandoc exited with code null. at Object._prettifyError (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/lib.js:36:11) at /home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:563:19 at Template.root [as rootRenderFunc] (eval at _compile (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:633:18), :53:3) at Template.render (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:552:10) at Environment.renderString (/home/finisky/node_modules/nunjucks/src/environment.js:380:17) at /home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/extend/tag.js:236:16 at tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Function.Promise.fromNode.Promise.fromCallback (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:209:30) at Tag.render (/home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/extend/tag.js:235:20) at Object.onRenderEnd (/home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/hexo/post.js:297:22) at /home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/hexo/render.js:79:21 at tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Promise._settlePromiseFromHandler (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:547:31) at Promise._settlePromise (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:604:18) at Promise._settlePromise0 (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:649:10) at Promise._settlePromises (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:729:18) at _drainQueueStep (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:93:12) at _drainQueue (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:86:9) at Async._drainQueues (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:102:5) at Immediate.Async.drainQueues (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:15:14) at processImmediate (node:internal/timers:464:21), isOperational: true } } Something&rsquo;s wrong. Maybe you can find the solution here: %s https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>About Me</title><url>/en/about/</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html">  Bio Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering Work at Microsoft Experience in search ranking, NLP, chatbot, AI and system design Philosophy: simple, reliable, maintainable More&amp;hellip; Living in Beijing, China Love hiking, swimming, pingpong, photography, history, etc. Contact Email: a@b.com, where a = finiskygarden, b = gmail
Wechat Official Account: Finisky Garden
  </content></entry><entry><title>FiniCounter: A Website Vistor Counter</title><url>/en/finicounter-impl/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>Hugo</tag><tag>Serverless</tag><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>Hexo Extension</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Static website such as Hexo/Hugo/Jekyll is very popular recent years. It is fast, easy to write, deploy and host. However, no free lunch: it is non-trivial to store dynamic information such as pageview counts and comments under the serverless architecture. This site uses Waline to implement article view count and comment system.
Accidently I found that we do not have a full site pageview counter. Waline has post-level counter instead of site-level one.
Just DIY: FiniCounter. Use Vercel serverless function as the web API framework, MongoDB as the storage. When a user comes to any page of the site, we invoke the count API through fetch API, increment the counter in the MongoDB, return the updated value and display in the page.
Initially I want to develop a tool for myself. After I finish it, I decide to make it as a public free service :-) . FiniCounter looks like this:
Backend Implementation The backend logic is straightforward. The server received a Http GET request and increment the corresponding count in MongoDB.
The API format: https://finicounter.eu.org/counter?host=xxx.com
It uses domain name host as the key to count.
The main code is self-explained:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 MONGODB_URL = os.environ.get(&#34;MONGODB_URL&#34;) CORS_ORIGINS = os.environ.get(&#34;CORS_ORIGINS&#34;) DB_NAME = os.environ.get(&#34;DB_NAME&#34;) if os.environ.get(&#34;DB_NAME&#34;) is not None else &#34;MyCounter&#34; COLLECTION_NAME = &#34;Counter&#34; cors_headers = {&#34;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#34;: CORS_ORIGINS, &#34;Access-Control-Allow-Method&#34;: &#34;POST, GET, OPTIONS&#34;} mongoClient = pymongo.MongoClient(MONGODB_URL) db = mongoClient[DB_NAME] collection= db[COLLECTION_NAME] app = Sanic(&#34;finicounter&#34;) @app.route(&#34;/counter&#34;) async def counter(request): args = request.get_args() host = args[&#34;host&#34;][0] result = collection.find_one_and_update({&#34;host&#34;: host}, {&#34;$inc&#34;: {&#34;views&#34;: 1}, &#34;$set&#34;: { &#34;updateTime&#34;: datetime.datetime.utcnow()}}, upsert = True, return_document = pymongo.collection.ReturnDocument.AFTER, maxTimeMS=50) return response.json({&#34;views&#34;: result[&#39;views&#39;]}, headers = cors_headers) app.run(host=&#34;0.0.0.0&#34;, port=8000, fast=True) Host By Yourself Host FiniCounter yourself is easy. What you need is a Vercel account and a MongoDB.
Just fork https://github.com/finisky/finicounter to your GitHub account, create a new project in Vercel, import the private repository and configure 3 environment variables:
Value CORS_ORIGINS * (or your domain) DB_NAME MongoDB DB name MONGODB_URL MongoDB Connection String The data is stored in the Counter Collection of DB DB_NAME .
Frontend Implementation The fronted is implemented by fetch API. The innerText of the element with id finicount_views will be set to the retrieved counter value. The script:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 async function getViews() { let url = &#34;https://finicounter.eu.org/counter?host=&#34; + window.location.hostname; try { let res = await fetch(url); return await res.json(); } catch (error) { console.log(error); } } async function renderViews() { let res = await getViews(); let elem = document.getElementById(&#34;finicount_views&#34;); if (typeof elem !== &#39;undefined&#39; &amp;&amp; elem !== null) { elem.innerText = formatNumber(res.views); } } function formatNumber(num) { return num.toString().replace(/(\d)(?=(\d{3})+(?!\d))/g, &#34;$1,&#34;); } renderViews(); The function formatNumber will format the counter like 12,345,678 . Feel free to customize your own script if necessary.
How to Use Basic Usage Add the following script to your websites: 1 &lt;script async src=&#34;//finicounter.eu.org/finicounter.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; Add a container with id finicount_views to show the view counts: 1 &lt;span id=&#34;finicount_views&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; You are done! The view count will be shown on your site like this 12,345,678.
Notice: the script should be added to every pages of your website. Otherwise, the page view counter might missing counts.
It is also welcome to directly use the counter API https://finicounter.eu.org/counter?host=xxx.com and customize the javascript yourself.
Each counter will be automatically deleted if not accessed for more than 3 months.
Hexo NexT Theme Integration For Hexo NexT theme, we can easily integrate FiniCounter by Injects . The total pageview can be displayed in the footer:
Just add a new js file totalpageview.js in the Hexo root folder scripts/:
1 2 3 hexo.extend.filter.register(&#39;theme_inject&#39;, function(injects) { injects.footer.raw(&#39;totalpageview&#39;, &#39;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://finicounter.eu.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Total Pageview:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;finicount_views&#34; style=&#34;display:inline;padding-left:5px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//finicounter.eu.org/finicounter.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#39;, {}, {cache: false}); }); Leave Hexo NexT Plugin as future work :-) .
Demo Demo This site is using FiniCounter :-) . Demo on this site .
Source Code Source code is available here .
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rollback Stylish Chrome Extension</title><url>/en/rollback-stylish/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html"><![CDATA[   Stylish used to be an excellent Chrome extension. It is able to customize css style for any website. I used this extension to change font to Monaco for many years.
Unfortunately, a recent auto update (July 6, 2022) makes it completely unusable: seems that the custom css style is applied after loading the page, so the page will keep the original font until finished loading the whole page and suddenly change to the custom style. Besides, the extension UI has a big change which cannot load properly.
Check the latest user review and found lots of 1 star bad review:
So I investigate how to rollback to an old version Stylish and disable update.
Uninstall Stylish The Stylish v3.0.1 is truly rubbish. Even the basic custom css functionality is not working. I don&rsquo;t understand why such a semi-finished product is released to hurt 3,000,000+ users.
Download Old Version of Stylish Crx4Chrome is a nice website which keep Chrome extensions&rsquo; crx file history. I downloaded Stylish 2.1.4 。
Install Old Stylish and Disable Auto-update Chrome doesn&rsquo;t support install extension from Crx4Chrome. The solution is easy: rename the .crx to .zip, uncompressed and modify update_url in manifest.json to disable auto-update:
from:
1 &#34;update_url&#34;: &#34;https://clients2.google.com/service/update2/crx&#34; to something not exist:
1 &#34;update_url&#34;: &#34;https://clients2.google.com/service/update2/crx/error&#34; Go to chrome://extensions/, press load unpacked extension and choose the corresponding folder.
My Stylish is back :-) :
Share my style css:
1 2 3 *:not([class*=&#34;icon&#34;]):not(i) { font-family: &#34;Monaco&#34;, &#34;Microsoft Yahei&#34; !important; } The only problem is that if you setup Chrome on a new device, the Stylish extension cannot be automatically installed or synced.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Hexo Generate Wrong Permalinks Date</title><url>/en/wrong-permalinks-date/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>SEO</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After Deploy Hexo From Private Repository to GitHub Pages , we encounter many issues: GitHub Checkout Action Preserve File Modification Time , and now some posts&rsquo; permalinks date may shift one day. For instance, assume the original markdown date is 2020-07-13 00:50:05, the generated permalinks date becomes 2020/07/12. Since the permalinks changed, search engines will regard these posts are not found which impact the SEO performance.
Cosidering that the issue doesn&rsquo;t happen for all posts but for posts that wrote between 0-8am, it&rsquo;s likely that the root cause is timezone setting.
Read the official document # Permalinks but found no clue. Then we found related discussion .
Root cause: the time zone of _config.yml and the timezone setting of the machine are inconsistent.
I tried two solutions:
Delete _config.yml timezone setting timezone: Asia/Shanghai. However, all the posts&rsquo; createtime and modification time are shifts for 8 hours. It doesn&rsquo;t work. Set the GitHub Actions machine&rsquo;s timezone the same as the _config.yml timezone setting. It works! The latter is the best solution, suggest to keep the deploy machine&rsquo;s configuration exactly the same as your local machine.
Add a new step Set Timezone after Restore Timestamps in .github/workflows/main.yml, use timedatectl to set timezone and output:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 - name: Restore Timestamps uses: chetan/git-restore-mtime-action@v1 - name: Set Timezone run: | sudo timedatectl set-timezone Asia/Shanghai timedatectl - name: Prepare Node env uses: actions/setup-node@v3 with: Now it works!
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>GitHub Checkout Action Preserve File Modification Time</title><url>/en/github-action-to-restore-file-mtime/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>Hugo</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  By # Deploy Hexo From Private Repository to GitHub Pages , we can leverage GitHub Actions to automatically deploy the Hexo website. However, for each deployment commit, the post&rsquo;s edit time will be changed to the current time instead of actual modification time. It may mislead the search engine to regard the website as a frequently modified site.
By default, Hexo uses the post file modification time as its edit time. By design, git doesn&rsquo;t preserve the file modification time (refer to this ). After checkout action, the file modification time will be the current time.
Therefore, we need to restore the modification time by third party tools: git-restore-mtime .
git-restore-mtime is a GitHub Workflow Action which restores timestamps of files in the current tree based on their last commit times.
Although the sample usage yaml looks complicated, using git-restore-mtime action is easy. Just add a new step after checkout action:
1 2 - name: Restore Timestamps uses: chetan/git-restore-mtime-action@v1 Unfortunately, it doesn&rsquo;t work. Because git-restore-mtime leverages the git reflog to find the correct timestamp for each file. The default checkout action only checkout the last commit instead of full history. So we need to add another line fetch-depth: 0 in the checkout step to pull the full history:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 ... - name: Checkout uses: actions/checkout@v3.0.0 with: token: ${{ secrets.MYPAT }} submodules: &#39;true&#39; persist-credentials: false fetch-depth: 0 - name: Restore Timestamps uses: chetan/git-restore-mtime-action@v1 ... Now it works! Every Hexo post&rsquo;s edit time is correct.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>'pandoc exited with code 64' Solution</title><url>/en/pandoc-code64-bug/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>Markdown</tag><tag>BinarySearch</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After I upgraded pandoc from 2.14.0.3 to 2.18, hexo-renderer-pandoc cannot render one of my post correctly. Everything works fine in 2.14.0.3. The error looks like:
INFO Start processing FATAL { err: Error: [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] On /home/finisky/source/_posts/test.md [ERROR][hexo-renderer-pandoc] pandoc exited with code 64: YAML parse exception at line 4, column 0, while scanning a simple key: could not find expected &lsquo;:&rsquo;
at Hexo.pandocRenderer (/home/finisky/node_modules/hexo-renderer-pandoc/index.js:114:11) at Hexo.tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Hexo.&lt;anonymous&gt; (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/method.js:15:34) at /home/finisky/node_modules/hexo/lib/hexo/render.js:75:22 at tryCatcher (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/util.js:16:23) at Promise._settlePromiseFromHandler (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:547:31) at Promise._settlePromise (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:604:18) at Promise._settlePromiseCtx (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/promise.js:641:10) at _drainQueueStep (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:97:12) at _drainQueue (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:86:9) at Async._drainQueues (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:102:5) at Immediate.Async.drainQueues [as _onImmediate] (/home/finisky/node_modules/bluebird/js/release/async.js:15:14) at processImmediate (node:internal/timers:464:21) } Something&rsquo;s wrong. Maybe you can find the solution here: %s https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html Reproduce and Debug I use binary search to find which lines has bug.
Then I construct a minimum version a.md to reproduce the issue (I want to insert two separator lines before and after the code block):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 begin. --- first: ``` test ``` --- end Run pandoc:
1 2 3 4 $ pandoc -f markdown -t html a.md YAML parse exception at line 2, column 0, while scanning for the next token: found character that cannot start any token Seems that the issue is around line 3~5: ---, : and triple backtick cannot be appeared at the same time.
There are several ways to bypass the issue:
Add a blank line after ---: 1 2 3 4 --- first: ``` Remove or replace the : 1 2 3 --- first. ``` Remove the trailing --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 begin. --- first: ``` test ``` end Root Cause Refer to this github issue I submitted:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 --- ``` first: ``` test ``` ``` The above is not a valid yaml. It&rsquo;s a markdown, why we talk about yaml?
Because the parser regards it as an inline yaml meta block.
Refer to PANDOC MANUAL :
A YAML metadata block is a valid YAML object, delimited by a line of three hyphens (---) at the top and a line of three hyphens (---) or three dots (...) at the bottom. A YAML metadata block may occur anywhere in the document, but if it is not at the beginning, it must be preceded by a blank line.
Solution Solution: To avoid ambiguity, adding a blank line before and after --- if you want a separator line.
The interesting point is that both StackEdit and DILLINGER parse the markdown correctly as well as pandoc 2.14.
I use StackEdit to write posts and pandoc to generate Hexo posts. StackEdit and DILLNGER try their best to optimize the user experience but the gap hides the imprecise grammar. Actually, pandoc is the most strict parser I met as this is not the first time I encountered such grammar issue. The best solution is to use rigorous grammar as pandoc. :-)
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Deploy Hexo From Private Repository to GitHub Pages</title><url>/en/deploy-hexo-from-private-repo/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>Hugo</tag></tags><content type="html">  Last time we talked how to deploy Hugo from private repository to GitHub Pages . I thought it is trivial to modify the workflow yaml to make it works for Hexo. However, it is much more complicated than I ever thought. The reason is that Hexo has to setup more dependencies with compatibility issues while Hugo is relatively self-contained and clean.
Actually, I spent several hours and attempted more than 20 times to make the workflow yaml works. :-)
Compared to Hugo workflow, there are several issues to be resolved:
Setup private submodules for your themes Configure PAT to pull private submodules as well as your main repo Pandoc installation for mathjax (optional) Let&amp;amp;rsquo;s start!
Typically, assume you have three repos (can belong to different github accounts). Without loss of generality, we assume the source repo, the target repo and the theme submodule repo are belong to the SAME github account.
Source Repo (private): store the source code Theme Repo (private): store the modified …  </content></entry><entry><title>Deploy Hugo From Private Repository to GitHub Pages</title><url>/en/deploy-hugo-from-private-repo/</url><categories><category>Hugo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hugo</tag><tag>Hexo</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Hugo is a nice static site generator. A common scenario is to store your website source code in a private repository and serve it on GitHub Pages. Can we leverage the github actions to automatically build and deploy the site from the private repository to GitHub Pages? The answer is absolutely yes!
Before we start, you need to have two repos (can belong to different github accounts):
Source Repo: the repo to store Target Repo: host the GitHub Pages (xxx.github.io) What we need to do is to create a personal access token in the target github account, configure it in the source repo and create an action workflow yaml.
Create Personal Access Token Personal access tokens (PATs) are an alternative to using passwords for authentication to GitHub Enterprise Server when using the GitHub API or the command line.
We will use the PAT to push the built hugo website from the source repo to the target repo.
Just follow this post to generate a PAT:
Profile Photo -&gt; Settings -&gt; Developer settings -&gt; Personal access tokens -&gt; Generate new token
Remember to check the following two scopes: workflow and write:packages.
Copy the token and properly save it, assume it is TOKENXXX.
Notice that the PAT is an account-level token, deploy key is recommended to use as a repo-level token.
Configure the PAT as a Secret in Source Repo Go to the source repo:
Settings -&gt; Secrets -&gt; Actions -&gt; New repository secret
Paste the token created before TOKENXXX to the value field. Name the secret as SECRETNAME.
Create Action Workflow Yaml in Source Repo The action workflow consists of the following parts:
Checkout: checkout the source code Setup Hugo: setup Hugo environment Run Hugo: build the static website Deploy: use # GitHub Pages Deploy Action to publish the website to the target GitHub Page The action workflow yaml is based on: # Using GitHub Actions to Publish Hugo Site From Private to Public Repo . Modify according to your needs, create a new workflow action in the source repo and paste it into the editor. The yaml should be put in the path: .github/workflows/main.yml :
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 name: Hugo Build &amp; Deploy - Private to Public on: push: branches: [ master ] jobs: build: runs-on: ubuntu-latest steps: - name: Checkout uses: actions/checkout@v2.3.4 with: persist-credentials: false # Setup Hugo - name: Hugo setup uses: peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2.5.0 with: hugo-version: &#39;latest&#39; # Download (if necessary) and use Hugo extended version. Example: true extended: false # Runs Hugo to build the Static Site - name: Run Hugo run: | hugo --verbose # Deploy the Static Site to Public Repo (GitHub Pages) - name: Deploy uses: JamesIves/github-pages-deploy-action@v4.3.3 with: token: ${{ secrets.SECRETNAME }} repository-name: xxx/xxx.github.io branch: master # The branch the action should deploy to. folder: public # The folder the action should deploy. single-commit: true commit-message: &#34;Deploy by source&#34; Modify the following fields:
branches: [ master ]: the action will be triggered when you push to the master branch token: ${{ secrets.SECRETNAME }}: change the secret name to the PAT secret name repository-name: xxx/xxx.github.io: the target GitHub Page repository address Then after you push the source code to the source repo, the deployment action will be triggered:
The action workflow can be easily applied to deploy Hexo site as well: just modify Setup Hugo and Run Hugo would be OK.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Why Neural Networks Can Represent Lanugage Models</title><url>/en/why-nn-can-represent-lm/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>Machine Learning</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>Language Model</tag></tags><content type="html">  My first understanding of a language model is originated from n-gram. When I know RNNLM, I have a question: why a neural network can represent a language model?
After some research, I found the answer. Essentially, language model is a probability distribution :
A statistical language model is a probability distribution over sequences of words.
In a language model, the probability of a sequence $w_1, w_2, \ldots w_m$ can be represented as:
$$P(w_1, w_2, \ldots w_m) = \prod^{m}{i = 1}{P(w_i|w_1, w_2, \ldots w{i-1})}$$
Then the problem reduces to: can a neural network represent a probability distribution? This article mentioned this point:
Neural networks are universal function approximators that can approximate any functions to arbitrary precisions
Moreover, I found the # Universal approximation theorem :
In the mathematical theory of artificial neural networks, universal approximation theorems are results that establish the density of an algorithmically generated class of functions within a given function space of interest. Typically, these results concern the approximation capabilities of the feedforward architecture on the space of continuous functions between two Euclidean spaces, and the approximation is with respect to the compact convergence topology.
The theorem proves the above statement: neural networks can approximate any functions with any precisions. Unfortunately, the theorem only points out the existence of such network, but do not provide a way to contruct it.
The universal approximation theorem is the foundation of why neural networks can represent language models.
  </content></entry><entry><title>C++ priority_queue Example</title><url>/en/priority-queue-example/</url><categories><category>Coding Interview</category></categories><tags><tag>Coding Interview</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  LeetCode Top K Frequent Words need to use STL priority_queue to solve the problem.
priority_queue definition :
1 2 3 4 5 template&lt; class T, class Container = std::vector&lt;T&gt;, class Compare = std::less&lt;typename Container::value_type&gt; &gt; class priority_queue; There are two ways to implement the priority_queue compare function of customized type.
Overload Operator Define a struct Cmp and overload operator ():
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 struct Cmp { bool operator()(const pair&lt;string, int&gt; &amp;a, const pair&lt;string, int&gt; &amp;b) { if (a.second == b.second) return a.first &lt; b.first; return a.second &gt; b.second; }; }; priority_queue&lt;pair&lt;string, int&gt;, vector&lt;pair&lt;string, int&gt;&gt;, Cmp&gt; pq; lambda Function It would be simpler to implement the compare function using lambda. No extra struct is needed:
1 2 3 4 5 6 auto cmp = [](const pair&lt;string, int&gt; &amp;a, const pair&lt;string, int&gt; &amp;b) { if (a.second == b.second) return a.first &lt; b.first; return a.second &gt; b.second; }; priority_queue&lt;pair&lt;string, int&gt;, vector&lt;pair&lt;string, int&gt;&gt;, decltype(cmp)&gt; pq(cmp); Notice: the priority_queue constructor here is different with overloading operator. The compare function cmp MUST be passed into the constructor. Otherwise, compile error occurs:
Line 16: Char 85: error: no matching constructor for initialization of &lsquo;priority_queue&lt;pair&lt;std::string, int&gt;, vector&lt;pair&lt;std::string, int&raquo;, decltype(cmp)&gt;&rsquo; (aka &lsquo;priority_queue&lt;pair&lt;basic_string, int&gt;, vector&lt;pair&lt;basic_string, int&raquo;, (lambda at solution.cpp:20:20)&gt;&rsquo;) priority_queue&lt;pair&lt;string, int&gt;, vector&lt;pair&lt;string, int&raquo;, decltype(cmp)&gt; pq; ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:501:2: note: candidate template ignored: requirement &lsquo;_and&lt;std::is_default_constructible&lt;(lambda at prog_joined.cpp:20:20)&gt;, std::is_default_constructible&lt;std::vector&lt;std::pair&lt;std::__cxx11::basic_string&lt;char, std::char_traits, std::allocator&gt;, int&gt;, std::allocator&lt;std::pair&lt;std::__cxx11::basic_string&lt;char, std::char_traits, std::allocator&gt;, int&raquo;&raquo;&gt;::value&rsquo; was not satisfied [with _Seq = std::vector&lt;std::pair&lt;std::__cxx11::basic_string, int&gt;, std::allocator&lt;std::pair&lt;std::__cxx11::basic_string, int&raquo;&gt;] priority_queue() ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:516:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires single argument &lsquo;__a&rsquo;, but no arguments were provided priority_queue(const _Alloc&amp; __a) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:443:11: note: candidate constructor (the implicit copy constructor) not viable: requires 1 argument, but 0 were provided class priority_queue ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:443:11: note: candidate constructor (the implicit move constructor) not viable: requires 1 argument, but 0 were provided /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:505:7: note: candidate constructor not viable: requires 2 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(const _Compare&amp; __x, const _Sequence&amp; __s) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:510:7: note: candidate constructor not viable: requires at least argument &lsquo;__x&rsquo;, but no arguments were provided priority_queue(const _Compare&amp; __x, _Sequence&amp;&amp; __s = _Sequence()) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:520:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 2 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(const _Compare&amp; __x, const _Alloc&amp; __a) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:537:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 2 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(const priority_queue&amp; __q, const _Alloc&amp; __a) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:541:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 2 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(priority_queue&amp;&amp; __q, const _Alloc&amp; __a) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:526:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 3 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(const _Compare&amp; __x, const _Sequence&amp; __c, ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:532:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 3 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(const _Compare&amp; __x, _Sequence&amp;&amp; __c, const _Alloc&amp; __a) ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:573:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires 4 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(_InputIterator __first, _InputIterator __last, ^ /usr/bin/../lib/gcc/x86_64-linux-gnu/9/../../../../include/c++/9/bits/stl_queue.h:584:2: note: candidate constructor template not viable: requires at least 2 arguments, but 0 were provided priority_queue(_InputIterator __first, _InputIterator __last, ^ 1 error generated.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Speed Up Github Image Hosting By Jsdelivr CDN</title><url>/en/speedup-github-by-cdn/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>Hugo</tag><tag>Markdown</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  This blog uses github as image hosting service after migration. However, sometimes the image loading speed is slow. After some investigation, we found that we can easily improve the image loading speed by jsdelivr CDN.
Jsdelivr Image Url Format Assume the original github image url is:
1 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/{user}/{repo}/master/{folderpath}/{filename} To leverage jsdelivr CDN, just convert the url to this:
1 https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/{user}/{repo}/{folderpath}/{filename} Or just do a prefix replacement:
1 2 3 4 5 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/{user}/{repo}/master/ --&gt; https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/{user}/{repo}/ For example, for image p.png in github user user&rsquo;s repository repo, folder a/:
1 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/user/repo/master/a/p.png The CDN url should be:
1 https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/user/repo/a/p.png If you encounter the following error:
Package size exceeded the configured limit of 50 MB. Try https://github.com/user/repo/tree/master/master/a/xxx.jpg instead.
Probably the image url is wrong. For this case, there is a duplicate master and the url should be: https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/user/repo/a/xxx.jpg
Script to Replace Image Url Use the following script to replace the image url:
1 2 3 4 5 6 #!/bin/bash for f in ./source/_posts/*.md; do echo &#34;Process &#34;$f sed -i &#39;s/https:\/\/raw.githubusercontent.com\/user\/repo\/master\//https:\/\/cdn.jsdelivr.net\/gh\/user\/repo\//&#39; $f done Reference https://blog.csdn.net/q906270629/article/details/115394248 https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/76951130   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Transaction BulkWrite Endless Retry</title><url>/en/mongodb-endless-retry/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Transaction</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Previously we talked about # How to Retry MongoDB Transaction . However, if you use BulkWrite() and one of the operation is retryable (e.g. duplicated key error), the new transactions API will retry the bulk write endlessly which might lead to server CPU 100%. (MongoDB Server v4.4.6-ent, MongoDB Driver v2.12.2)
To avoid such issue, we have three suggestions:
Add a cancellation token to limit the max retry time Break the transaction after max retry count Set BulkWriteOptions { IsOrdered = true } The first two suggestions are also applicable to transactions which don&rsquo;t use BulkWrite().
Limit Max Transaction Execution Time First, let&rsquo;s refine the RetryReplaceAsync() by adding CancellationToken, which limits the max execution time of the transaction:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 private async Task RetryReplaceAsync(IMongoClient mongoClient, string uuid, string value) { var collection = mongoClient.GetDatabase(DatabaseName).GetCollection&lt;BsonDocument&gt;(CollectionName); using (var session = await mongoClient.StartSessionAsync()) using (var cts = new CancellationTokenSource(TimeSpan.FromSeconds(1))) { var filter = Builders&lt;BsonDocument&gt;.Filter.Eq(&#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid); await session.WithTransactionAsync( async (s, ct) =&gt; { await collection.ReplaceOneAsync(s, filter, new BsonDocument { { &#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid }, { &#34;op&#34;, value } }, new ReplaceOptions { IsUpsert = true }, ct); return string.Empty; }, cancellationToken: cts.Token); } } Limit Max Transaction Retry Count Just add 3 lines:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 private async Task RetryReplaceAsync(IMongoClient mongoClient, string uuid, string value) { var collection = mongoClient.GetDatabase(DatabaseName).GetCollection&lt;BsonDocument&gt;(CollectionName); int count = 0; using (var session = await mongoClient.StartSessionAsync()) using (var cts = new CancellationTokenSource(TimeSpan.FromSeconds(1))) { var filter = Builders&lt;BsonDocument&gt;.Filter.Eq(&#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid); await session.WithTransactionAsync( async (s, ct) =&gt; { if (++count &gt;= 3) { throw new ApplicationException($&#34;Reached max retry times&#34;); } await collection.ReplaceOneAsync(s, filter, new BsonDocument { { &#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid }, { &#34;op&#34;, value } }, new ReplaceOptions { IsUpsert = true }, ct); return string.Empty; }, cancellationToken: cts.Token); } } Execute BulkWrite Operations In Order The bulk write operation can be executed ordered or unordered. To improve performance, it seems that unordered execution is better. However, the unordered execution might eat some exceptions for a single operation, which leads to endless transaction retry.
As a result, we suggest to execute the operations in order. The code looks like this:
1 await collection.BulkWriteAsync(session, listWrites, new BulkWriteOptions { IsOrdered = true }, cancellationToken: ct); Reference https://developer.mongodb.com/community/forums/t/handling-duplicated-key-error-in-bulk-insert-retry-scenarios/2869 https://stackoverflow.com/questions/61244296/how-to-handle-duplicate-error-in-mongo-bulkinsert-retry   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Brief Introduction to NLP Prompting</title><url>/en/brief-intro-to-prompt/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>Machine Learning</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>Prompt</tag><tag>NLU</tag><tag>NLG</tag><tag>Language Model</tag></tags><content type="html">  Prompting is one of the hottest NLP techniques. This is a brief introduction to prompting by three questions: what&amp;amp;rsquo;s prompting, why prompting and how to prompting. As a brief introduction, we do not cover too much details but try to summarize the main idea of prompting. For more details, please refer to the original papers.
What&amp;amp;rsquo;s Prompting I don&amp;amp;rsquo;t find a rigorous defintion for prompting. Just quoting some pieces from papers.
Users prepend a natural language task instruction and a few examples to the task input; then generate the output from the LM. This approach is known as in-context learning or prompting.
By: # Prefix-Tuning: Optimizing Continuous Prompts for Generation This description brought two concepts: in-context learning and prompting.
Another explantion from probability perspective:
Prompting is the approach of adding extra information for the model to condition on during its generation of Y .
By: # The Power of Scale for Parameter-Efficient Prompt Tuning …  </content></entry><entry><title>Hugo Add Customized CSS or Javascript</title><url>/en/hugo-add-css-js/</url><categories><category>Hugo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hugo</tag><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently I switched the static website generator from Hexo to Hugo. The main reason is that Hexo is too slow, cannot generate websites with thousands of pages.
Then I found this: # Who Should Use Hugo? Hugo is for people building a blog, a company site, a portfolio site, documentation, a single landing page, or a website with thousands of pages.
No pain no gain. To use Hugo smoothly, the first problem is how to add customized css or js to the site.
The bad news is that Hugo is not that friendly to a freshman. I spent hours to read documents and understood how it works. Comparatively, Hexo&rsquo;s plugin system and injector is more friendly to a freshman (maybe I forgot how long to learn it haha :-D).
In this post, we will go through how to add customized css or js to Hugo sites in Hugoic way.
If you don&rsquo;t want to understand how it works, just go to Modify Templates section would be fine. :-)
Hexo Add Customized css/js Add Customized css/js in Hexo is easy, just add a new file custom.js in the scripts folder of project root directory, then the js would be appended to the end of &lt;head&gt;:
1 2 3 hexo.extend.injector.register(&#39;head_end&#39;, () =&gt; { return &#39;&lt;script data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-xxx&#34; async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#39;; }, &#39;default&#39;); Add Customized css/js In Hugoic Way Simliar to pythonnic, what&rsquo;s the Hugoic way to inject customized css/js?
Hugo runs on top of theme templates, so we need to modify the templates to inject css/js. Before that, we should get some understanding of Hugo basics.
Hugo Layouts Lookup Rules With Theme The first lesson： # Hugo Layouts Lookup Rules With Theme :
In Hugo, layouts can live in either the project’s or the themes&rsquo; layout folders, and the most specific layout will be chosen. Hugo will interleave the lookups listed below, finding the most specific one either in the project or themes.
Unfortunately, I don&rsquo;t find the priority of project layout and theme layout explicitly. Here is an unofficial explanation: # Customizing a Theme 。
Customize the Templates Based on Hugo layouts lookup rules, we should customize the templates by two steps:
Copy /themes/&lt;yourtheme&gt;/layouts/partials/xxx.html to the project root /layouts/partials/xxx.html, aka created a new file with the same folder structure of theme folder in the project root Modify the new file /layouts/partials/xxx.html and add css/js code The main advantages of the solution is the theme can be upgraded independent of the project repo. If we modify the theme files directly, there might be many conflicts when upgrade the theme.
The first time I read the above solution, I don&rsquo;t understand why it works. I spent hours to read documents and found that Hugo has many implicit rules. Here the rule would be the templates in the project layout will overwrite the templates in the theme layout.
layouts/_default/ holds many default templates, while layouts/partials holds partial templates:
Partials are smaller, context-aware components in your list and page templates that can be used economically to keep your templating DRY.
# Partial Template Lookup Order ：
However, partials are simpler in that Hugo will only check in two places:
layouts/partials/*&lt;PARTIALNAME&gt;.html themes/&lt;THEME&gt;/layouts/partials/*&lt;PARTIALNAME&gt;.html This allows a theme’s end user to copy a partial’s contents into a file of the same name for further customization.
Modify Templates Here we take theme PaperMod as example, copy /themes/PaperMod/layouts/partials/head.html to /layouts/partials/head.html and append the following code to the file end:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 ... {{ range .Site.Params.customcss }} &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;{{ . | absURL }}&#34;&gt; {{- end }} {{ range .Site.Params.customjs }} &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;{{ . | absURL }}&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; {{- end }} {{ range $elem := .Site.Params.customjscssraw }} {{ $elem | safeHTML }} {{- end }} To fully understand the code, we need to read # Context and function usage of range, absURL and safeHTML in # Introduction to Hugo Templating .
Why do we need customjscssraw since we alreadly have customcss and customjs? Because sometimes add raw html is more flexible: add css integrity property, or add async keywords to js. This feature is comparable to Hexo injector. See the examples in the next section.
Add CSS or Js in the config.yml The usage is pretty easy, just add the configuration like this (support muliti-line js as well):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 params: ... customcss: - &#34;css/xx.css&#34; customjs: - &#34;js/xx.js&#34; customjscssraw: - &#34;&lt;link rel=&#39;stylesheet&#39; href=&#39;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@fortawesome/fontawesome-free@5.15.3/css/all.min.css&#39; integrity=&#39;sha256-2H3fkXt6FEmrReK448mDVGKb3WW2ZZw35gI7vqHOE4Y=&#39; crossorigin=&#39;anonymous&#39;&gt;&#34; - &gt; &lt;script async src=&#39;https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id=G-XXX&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;script&gt; window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || []; function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);} gtag(&#39;js&#39;, new Date()); gtag(&#39;config&#39;, &#39;G-XXX&#39;); &lt;/script&gt; Tips: Don&rsquo;t forget to add your css/js files to the static/ folder if their path are relative.
Reference: # Add Custom CSS Or Javascript To Your Hugo Site   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Fine-tune GPT with Line-by-Line Dataset</title><url>/en/finetune-lm-line-by-line/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>Machine Learning</tag><tag>NLP</tag><tag>Transformer</tag><tag>python</tag><tag>NLG</tag><tag>Language Model</tag></tags><content type="html">  The latest training/fine-tuning language model tutorial by huggingface transformers can be found here: Transformers Language Model Training There are three scripts: run_clm.py, run_mlm.py and run_plm.py. For GPT which is a causal language model, we should use run_clm.py. However, run_clm.py doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t support line by line dataset. For each batch, the default behavior is to group the training examples into a single block_size line.
However, grouping text doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t make sense for datasets whose lines are not related such as QA dataset:
Q1 [SEP] A1 Q2 [SEP] A2 &amp;amp;hellip;
Concatenate them to: Q1 [SEP] A1 Q2 [SEP] A2 ... might mislead the language model.
Implement Line by Line Data Processing The default data processing logic for run_clm.py:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 # Main data processing function that will concatenate all texts from our dataset and generate chunks of block_size. def group_texts(examples): # Concatenate all …  </content></entry><entry><title>Create Storage Class in Azure Kubernetes Cluster</title><url>/en/create-storage-class-in-aks/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags><tag>Kubernetes</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Follow # Dynamically create and use a persistent volume with Azure Files in Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) to create a new storage class in AKS:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 kind: StorageClass apiVersion: storage.k8s.io/v1 metadata: name: standard-grs provisioner: kubernetes.io/azure-disk parameters: cachingmode: ReadOnly kind: Managed skuName: Standard_GRS reclaimPolicy: Delete allowVolumeExpansion: true volumeBindingMode: Immediate If you create new resource by kubernetes dashboard, an error might occur:
1 2 Deploying file has failed the server could not find the requested resource Two solutions:
Using kubectl apply -f command Change kubernetes dashboard namespace to All namespaces, then create again Another error might happen when claming PVC:
1 error while running &#34;VolumeBinding&#34; prebind plugin for pod &#34;xxx&#34;: Failed to bind volumes: provisioning failed for PVC &#34;xxx&#34; The error message can be found via kubectl describe pvc:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 $ kubectl.exe describe pvc xxx Name: xxx Namespace: xxx StorageClass: standard-grs Status: Pending Volume: Labels: app=xxx Annotations: volume.beta.kubernetes.io/storage-provisioner: kubernetes.io/azure-disk Finalizers: [kubernetes.io/pvc-protection] Capacity: Access Modes: VolumeMode: Filesystem Used By: xxx Events: Type Reason Age From Message ---- ------ ---- ---- ------- Warning ProvisioningFailed 13s (x9 over 3m40s) persistentvolume-controller Failed to provision volume with StorageClass &#34;standard-grs&#34;: azureDisk - Standard_GRS is not supported sku/storageaccounttype. Supported values are [Premium_LRS Standard_LRS StandardSSD_LRS UltraSSD_LRS] Specifically, the error above cannot be resolved inside this cluster. One alternative would be create another cluster which supports sku Standard_GRS.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Confgure Multiple Github Accounts On One Machine</title><url>/en/multiple-github-accounts-on-one-machine/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag><tag>SSH</tag><tag>Hexo</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  How to use different github account for different repository? For instance, we have two github accounts x1 and x2, while x1 for repo1 and x2 for repo2. At the first glance, we can set git config in different repository folder by git config user.name xxx. However, this approach has two drawbacks:
Need to config user name/email in every repository In some case, the git user cannot be configured by git config. For example, hexo-deployer-git . Since the git repo is automatically generated by the deployer, it&rsquo;s hard to manually set the user name. Fortunately, we can leverage SSH config to associate different github accounts with different repos. Define different host entries does the trick: since we login to github via SSH, we use a virtual host as an alias to represent the real host name.
Generating a New SSH Key # Generating a new SSH key and adding it to the ssh-agent 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 $ ssh-keygen -t ed25519 -C &#34;your_email@example.com&#34; Generating public/private ed25519 key pair. Enter file in which to save the key (/home/user/.ssh/id_ed25519): Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase): Enter same passphrase again: Your identification has been saved in /home/user/.ssh/id_ed25519 Your public key has been saved in /home/user/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub The key fingerprint is: SHA256: xxx your_email@example.com Add your SSH private key to the ssh-agent:
1 2 $ ssh-add ~/.ssh/id_ed25519 Identity added: /home/user/.ssh/id_ed25519 (your_email@example.com) Add the Key to GitHub Account # Adding a new SSH key to your GitHub account Copy the public key:
1 2 $ cat ~/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub ssh-ed25519 xxxx your_email@example.com Add the key to github account in github main page: Profile Photo -&gt; Settings -&gt; SSH and GPG keys -&gt; New SSH keys
Edit SSH Config This is the most important part, create or edit ~/.ssh/config:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 Host github.com HostName github.com User git IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_rsa Host githubx1 HostName github.com User git IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_rsa_x1 Host githubx2 HostName github.com User git IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_rsa_x2 Explanations for the config file:
Host: the host alias as well as the section name HostName: the real host name to login User: the username for the SSH connection IdentityFile : the SSH private key file generated before For the above sample config file, assume the key file/github account mapping is:
id_rsa -&gt; main@example.com id_rsa_x1 -&gt; x1@example.com id_rsa_x2 -&gt; x2@example.com Typically, a repo&rsquo;s remote url looks like this:
1 git@github.com:finisky/TextCNN.git By default, we will access the repo by identity main@example.com because the repo remote host is github.com. If we want to access the repo by x1@example.com, just change the remote url to:
1 git@githubx1:finisky/TextCNN.git Test Connection Verify the configuration is easy. Test the connection by the following command (notice that the ssh username is git):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 $ ssh -T git@githubx1 Hi x1! You&#39;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access. $ ssh -T git@githubx2 Hi x2! You&#39;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access. $ ssh -T wrongusername@githubx2 wrongusername@github.com: Permission denied (publickey). If success, the corresponding GitHub username (aka x1, x2) will be displayed after &ldquo;Hi&rdquo;.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How to Get the MongoDB Chunk Size</title><url>/en/mongodb-get-chunk-size/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>Sharding</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently we found the traffic is not balanced across the MongoDB cluster shards. After investigation, the root cause is that data on each shard is not evenly distributed ( Chunk balancing != data balancing != traffic balancing ). The data distribution looks like this:
Shard Data Size mongo-0 10.55 GB mongo-1 25.76 GB mongo-2 10.04 GB Why the data size of mongo-1 is significantly large than others while the chunk number among 3 shards is almost the same? Then we need to analysis the chunk size distribution across these shards.
Get the chunk size is not that straightforward. No API is provided to directly give the chunk size. Although the basic chunk information is stored at config.chunks collection, there is no data size field. Consider a collection cxx whose shard key is Uuid, the chunk information looks like this (for one shard):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 { &#34;_id&#34;: { &#34;$oid&#34;: &#34;603348a8b74404eea898cc25&#34; }, &#34;lastmod&#34;: { &#34;$timestamp&#34;: { &#34;t&#34;: 0, &#34;i&#34;: 773 } }, &#34;lastmodEpoch&#34;: { &#34;$oid&#34;: &#34;5ff83e4ba85a6bd465831542&#34; }, &#34;ns&#34;: &#34;cxx&#34;, &#34;min&#34;: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: &#34;044B96CA34334FBE860D47BD63339B8E&#34; }, &#34;max&#34;: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: &#34;0494E87F8ED34B0E9ECF6BE5363BBD3C&#34; }, &#34;shard&#34;: &#34;mongo-2&#34;, &#34;history&#34;: [{ &#34;validAfter&#34;: { &#34;$timestamp&#34;: { &#34;t&#34;: 6261, &#34;i&#34;: 1632930119 } }, &#34;shard&#34;: &#34;mongo-2&#34; } ] } The good news is that the chunk information contains the min/max key of the chunk. So we can get the chunk size by the dataSize API :
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 { dataSize: &lt;string&gt;, keyPattern: &lt;document&gt;, min: &lt;document&gt;, max: &lt;document&gt;, estimate: &lt;boolean&gt; } The intuition is to get the data size of all the documents in the chunk.
For the above example, use the following command in mongo shell to get the chunk size, remember using maxTimeMS to limit max command execution timeout:
1 db.runCommand({ dataSize: &#34;cxx&#34;, keyPattern: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: 1 }, min: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: &#34;044B96CA34334FBE860D47BD63339B8E&#34; }, max: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: &#34;0494E87F8ED34B0E9ECF6BE5363BBD3C&#34; }, maxTimeMS:1000 }) To analyze the chunk size distribution, we can iterate each chunk and get its size by the above command. Put it together, the final script (modify ns and the Uuid field according to your scenario):
1 2 3 4 5 var ns = &#34;&#34;; db.getSiblingDB(&#34;config&#34;).chunks.find({ns : ns}).forEach(function(chunk) { chunkSize = db.runCommand({ dataSize: ns, keyPattern: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: 1 }, min: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: chunk.min.Uuid }, max: { &#34;Uuid&#34;: chunk.max.Uuid }, maxTimeMS:1000 }) print(chunk.shard + &#34; &#34; + chunk.min.Uuid + &#34;: &#34; + tojson(chunkSize.size/1024/1024) + &#34;MB&#34;) }) Sample output:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 mongo-0 00020DFCE1B64BE28098133E09F0DFF9: 27.868586540222168MB mongo-0 020FC0A3F7DC456D8CA48787A22BFEF5: 0.03055095672607422MB mongo-1 02109DCC630C4EB68D890BB1C664C732: 2.049802780151367MB mongo-1 02394113C1FF4C33BB067299D00F2A57: 0.17893218994140625MB mongo-0 023CB90536CB4D9A83E88BC362CDA80A: 5.774362564086914MB mongo-0 02AD2533642349398B6B7518914C87E7: 8.088775634765625MB mongo-1 03463C80D8844550A3F1F259345807DA: 3.041494369506836MB mongo-0 037F4D692AE34A3FB7F4B5A3205121C2: 1.5527820587158203MB mongo-1 039C5810056F4205B1FC476A67F003BF: 6.535520553588867MB mongo-2 04197554460047ADBD5B62B35F4956B6: 2.715306282043457MB ...   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Chunk Migration Failed Solution: Unable to acquire X lock</title><url>/en/mongodb-chunk-migration-failed/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>Sharding</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After adding new shards to our production MongoDB cluster (v4.4.6-ent with 5 shards, 3 replicas for each shard), we found that the balancer is not working. sh.status() displays many chunk migration errors:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 ... balancer: Currently enabled: yes Currently running: no Failed balancer rounds in last 5 attempts: 0 Migration Results for the last 24 hours: 7 : Failed with error &#39;aborted&#39;, from mongo-1 to mongo-3 7208 : Failed with error &#39;aborted&#39;, from mongo-1 to mongo-4 databases: { &#34;_id&#34; : &#34;X&#34;, &#34;primary&#34; : &#34;mongo-1&#34;, &#34;partitioned&#34; : true, &#34;version&#34; : { &#34;uuid&#34; : UUID(&#34;xxx&#34;), &#34;lastMod&#34; : 1 } } X.A shard key: { &#34;Uuid&#34; : 1 } unique: false balancing: true chunks: mongo-0 231 mongo-1 327 mongo-2 230 mongo-3 208 ... Obviously, the chunks is unbalanced accross shards (327 vs 208). Since the balancer is enabled, we try to debug the issue through mongodb.log on the config server. There are many migration failed logs (sensitive infomation masked):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 { &#34;t&#34;: { &#34;$date&#34;: &#34;2021-09-27T05:05:46.090+00:00&#34; }, &#34;s&#34;: &#34;I&#34;, &#34;c&#34;: &#34;SHARDING&#34;, &#34;id&#34;: 21872, &#34;ctx&#34;: &#34;Balancer&#34;, &#34;msg&#34;: &#34;Migration failed&#34;, &#34;attr&#34;: { &#34;migrateInfo&#34;: &#34;X.A: [{ Uuid: MinKey }, { Uuid: \&#34;xxx\&#34; }), from mongo-a-1, to mongo-a-4&#34;, &#34;error&#34;: &#34;LockTimeout: Unable to acquire X lock on &#39;{13328793763114131834: Collection, 1799578717045662184, X.A}&#39; within 500ms. opId: 669456657, op: MoveChunk, connId: 0.&#34; } } Because the above error happens for the first chunk to be migrated, the whole balancing process is blocked by this error which makes shard mongo-1 holds much more data than other shards. It seems that the error is caused by Unable to acquire X lock on collection.
Try to manually movechunk according to this , but got the same error:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 MongoDB Enterprise mongos&gt; sh.moveChunk(&#34;X.A&#34;, {&#34;Uuid&#34;: &#34;XX&#34;}, &#34;mongo-3&#34; ) { &#34;ok&#34; : 0, &#34;errmsg&#34; : &#34;Unable to acquire X lock on &#39;{13328793763114131834: Collection, 1799578717045662184, X.A}&#39; within 500ms. opId: 719103624, op: MoveChunk, connId: 0.&#34;, &#34;code&#34; : 24, &#34;codeName&#34; : &#34;LockTimeout&#34;, &#34;operationTime&#34; : Timestamp(1632890816, 39), &#34;$clusterTime&#34; : { &#34;clusterTime&#34; : Timestamp(1632890816, 39), &#34;signature&#34; : { &#34;hash&#34; : BinData(0,&#34;/=&#34;), &#34;keyId&#34; : NumberLong(&#34;6952576454697680898&#34;) } } } Increase maxTransactionLockRequestTimeoutMillis? Google a similar discussion here , which suggests to set maxTransactionLockRequestTimeoutMillis longer. However, I think 500ms is long enough to acquire the lock, change the parameter may have side effect on the production environment, so we don&rsquo;t test whether it works.
Jumbo Chunks? According to this post , jumbo chunks might lead to migration failure. So we checked the collection chunks by sh.status(true), NO jumbo chunks found.
Restart the Source Mongod We also try to check the current operations and locks via db.currentOp() , but not have a clue.
Finally, we restart the source mongod process through MongoDB Ops Manager to change the primary in the shard. Surprisingly, it works! A few miniutes later, chunks are evenly distributed accross shards:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 ... balancer: Currently enabled: yes Currently running: no Balancer active window is set between 17:45 and 11:59 server local time Failed balancer rounds in last 5 attempts: 0 Migration Results for the last 24 hours: 236 : Success 2 : Failed with error &#39;aborted&#39;, from mongo-4 to mongo-0 databases: { &#34;_id&#34; : &#34;X&#34;, &#34;primary&#34; : &#34;mongo-1&#34;, &#34;partitioned&#34; : true, &#34;version&#34; : { &#34;uuid&#34; : UUID(&#34;xxx&#34;), &#34;lastMod&#34; : 1 } } X.A shard key: { &#34;Uuid&#34; : 1 } unique: false balancing: true chunks: mongo-0 207 mongo-1 207 mongo-2 207 mongo-3 207 mongo-4 208 ... We guess that the root cause is that the original mongod process has inconsistent states. Restart is just a simple way to force another member to become primary, which bypass the inconsistent states issue of the original mongod.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 { &#34;t&#34;: { &#34;$date&#34;: &#34;2021-09-29T02:43:35.602+00:00&#34; }, &#34;s&#34;: &#34;I&#34;, &#34;c&#34;: &#34;SHARDING&#34;, &#34;id&#34;: 21872, &#34;ctx&#34;: &#34;Balancer&#34;, &#34;msg&#34;: &#34;Migration failed&#34;, &#34;attr&#34;: { &#34;migrateInfo&#34;: &#34;X.A: [{ Uuid: \&#34;xxx\&#34; }, { Uuid: \&#34;xxx\&#34; }), from mongo-a-1, to mongo-a-4&#34;, &#34;error&#34;: &#34;Overflow: Invalid advance (1) past end of buffer[0] at offset: 0&#34; } } The error Overflow: Invalid advance past end of buffer at offset can be resolved by manually restart the source monogd as well.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Prevent Pod From Endless Restart</title><url>/en/prevent-pod-restart/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags><tag>Kubernetes</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When a pod in error state (crashloopbackoff), kubernetes would restart the pod. If you try to exec into the pod to check the log or debug, the following error message appears:
1 unable to upgrade connection: container not found (&#34;&#34;) Because the old pod has been killed and you cannot exec into it anymore. So how can we prevent the pod from endless restart?
Just add a command to the deployment yaml to override the default command by the container image. Make the pod never finished by sleep infinity or tail -f /dev/null:
1 2 command: [&#34;sleep&#34;] args: [&#34;infinity&#34;] or
1 2 command: [&#34;tail&#34;] args: [&#34;-f&#34;, &#34;/dev/null&#34;] Add them to spec.template.spec.containers like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... spec: template: spec: containers: - name: xxx command: [&#34;sleep&#34;] args: [&#34;infinity&#34;] ... Remove the liveness/readiness section from the yaml to make the deployment status green if necessary.
You can exec into the pod to debug as you want.
Reference:
How can I keep a container running on Kubernetes? Define a Command and Arguments for a Container Troubleshoot and Fix Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff Status   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How to Use Multiple Backup Daemons in MongoDB Kubernetes Operator</title><url>/en/mongodb-ops-mgr-multiple-backup-daemons/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag></tags><content type="html">   Multiple Backup Daemons are typically run when the storage requirements or the load generated by the deployment is too much for a single daemon.
Directly scale the statefulset ops-manager-backup-daemon to multiple instances (e.g. 3) doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Because the mongodb-enterprise-operator is watching the statefulset, the instance number will be scaled down to 1 by the MongoDB operator several miniutes later.
So how to scale up the backup dameons by the MongoDB kubernetes operator?
If your MongoDB Ops Manager is v5.0.0, then it would be pretty easy. Edit the Ops Manager yaml and add a line memebers: 3 like this (refer to this commit ):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 ... backup: enabled: true # optional. Defaults to 1 if not set. # Configures the number of backup daemons to create members: 3 ... If the MongoDB Ops Manager is v4.x, I found an alternative: specify replicas: 3 to backup.statefulSet.spec like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... backup: enabled: true headDB: storage: 16Gi statefulSet: spec: replicas: 3 ... Apply the yaml and waiting the backup daemons to scale up. Go to Ops Manager Admin -&amp;gt; Backup -&amp;gt; Daemons, the new added daemons will be there:
Set the head directory to /head/ and press the set button, the daemon is ready to use:
Press Enable Daemon, then you can move jobs to the new backup daemons.
  </content></entry><entry><title>Apex Compile Error: expected primary-expression before ‘>’ token</title><url>/en/apex-primary-expression-error/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>pytorch</tag><tag>cuda</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Apex Compile Error The environment (cuda10.0):
1 $ conda install pytorch==1.1.0 torchvision==0.3.0 cudatoolkit=10.0 -c pytorch The apex repo master HEAD:
1 2 3 4 commit 0c2c6eea6556b208d1a8711197efc94899e754e1 (HEAD -&amp;gt; master, origin/master, origin/HEAD) Author: Nan Zheng &amp;lt;80790206+nanz-nv@users.noreply.github.com&amp;gt; Date: Sat Jul 17 08:53:59 2021 +0800 ... Install apex:
1 2 3 git clone https://github.com/NVIDIA/apex cd apex pip install -v --disable-pip-version-check --no-cache-dir --global-option=&amp;#34;--cpp_ext&amp;#34; --global-option=&amp;#34;--cuda_ext&amp;#34; ./ Compile error like this:
1 2 3 csrc/mlp.cpp:127:54: error: expected primary-expression before ‘&amp;gt;’ token w_ptr.push_back(inputs[i + 1].data_ptr&amp;lt;scalar_t&amp;gt;()); ^ Solution Similar discussions: https://github.com/NVIDIA/apex/issues/802 https://github.com/NVIDIA/apex/issues/1139 Rollback to an earlier version is not a good solution. Actually, the issue is caused by pytorch/gcc/cuda mismatch.
Therefore, make sure:
gcc …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Master-Slave Replication by Change Stream</title><url>/en/mongodb-slave-sync/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>Change Stream</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  By the official manual :
Change streams allow applications to access real-time data changes without the complexity and risk of tailing the oplog. Applications can use change streams to subscribe to all data changes on a single collection, a database, or an entire deployment, and immediately react to them. Because change streams use the aggregation framework, applications can also filter for specific changes or transform the notifications at will.
Here we leverage change stream to replicate data from one MongoDB to another in realtime.
There is some existing tools such as MongoShake do the same thing. However, MongoShake is a little bit complicated to use. We encoutered two issues:
Modify the source code to use TLS authentication Cannot perform increment sync in all sync_mode Since our goal is realtime replication, we choose a more straightforward and controllable way: MongoDB Ops Manager cluster restore and change stream to apply realtime changes.
Notes: we use master and slave to …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Change Stream Makes the Cluster Down</title><url>/en/change-stream-cause-server-restart/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>Change Stream</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  MongoDB change stream is a nice feature. It allows applications to access real-time data changes without the complexity and risk of tailing the oplog.
Recently, when we use change stream to replicate data from one sharded cluster to another, it immediately made the cluster unstable (broke down several nodes and triggered the primary change). Then the read/write operations latency significantly increased.
Observations Observations on our production envrionment:
The cluster immediately down after starting change stream application Mongod restarted Mongos connections significantly increased (about 3x) Service latency notably increased (from milliseconds to seconds) However, such issue is not always happen. The change stream application works fine for another two sharded clusters (test environment, small traffic).
We were struggling to debug the issue. We attempted to upgrade MongoDB client drivers but not work. Since the issue is only happened in the production, it&rsquo;s really hard to reproduce. :-(
Finally, we found this link: https://jira.mongodb.org/browse/SERVER-50769 . Perfect match:
Sharded cluster, MongoDB v4.4.3-ent Heavily used transactions Server restart after starting change stream After requesting the mongod logs, we found logs like this:
{&ldquo;t&rdquo;:{&quot;$date&quot;:&ldquo;2021-07-20T06:36:56.044+00:00&rdquo;},&ldquo;s&rdquo;:&ldquo;F&rdquo;, &ldquo;c&rdquo;:&quot;-&quot;, &ldquo;id&rdquo;:23079, &ldquo;ctx&rdquo;:&ldquo;conn198&rdquo;,&ldquo;msg&rdquo;:&ldquo;Invariant failure&rdquo;,&ldquo;attr&rdquo;:{&ldquo;expr&rdquo;:&quot;_currentApplyOps.getArrayLength() &gt; 0&quot;,&ldquo;file&rdquo;:&ldquo;src/mongo/db/pipeline/document_source_change_stream_transform.cpp&rdquo;,&ldquo;line&rdquo;:535}}
Mixed feeling&hellip;
Solution Upgrade the MongoDB version to 4.4.4+.
See the release notes :
SERVER-50769 : server restarted after expr{&ldquo;expr&rdquo;:&quot;_currentApplyOps.getArrayLength() &gt; 0&quot;,&ldquo;file&rdquo;:&ldquo;src/mongo/db/pipeline/document_source_change_stream_transform.cpp&rdquo;
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Delay Loading Google Auto Ads</title><url>/en/delay-auto-ads-loading/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Google AdSense</tag><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>SEO</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently I found that the Google auto ads significantly slows down the page loading speed. There are also many discussions about this. As a static website, fast loading speed is crutial. In this post, we will optimize the PageSpeed Insights score by delay loading auto ads.
First, let&rsquo;s check the current PSI score in mobile: It seems that the Reduce unused JavaScript section has many items to be improved. Check the official Google auto ads script:
1 &lt;script data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-000xxx&#34; async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; Although the script is async, the page loading speed is affected. Changing async to defer makes no difference: https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10808109/script-tag-async-defer Loading Ads after Page Loaded Refer to: # How to Setup Lazy Load for Google AdSense Ad units? Wrap the ads loading into a function and load ads after page onload event is triggered:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 &lt;script&gt; function func() { ... } if (window.addEventListener) window.addEventListener(&#34;load&#34;, func, false); else if (window.attachEvent) window.attachEvent(&#34;onload&#34;, func); else window.onload = func; &lt;/script&gt; Then the original script is rewritten like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt; function downloadJsAtOnload() { var element = document.createElement(&#34;script&#34;); element.setAttribute(&#34;data-ad-client&#34;, &#34;ca-pub-000xxx&#34;); element.async = true; element.src = &#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&#34;; document.body.appendChild(element); }; if (window.addEventListener) window.addEventListener(&#34;load&#34;, downloadJsAtOnload, false); else if (window.attachEvent) window.attachEvent(&#34;onload&#34;, downloadJsAtOnload); else window.onload = downloadJsAtOnload; &lt;/script&gt; Unfortunately, the above script still not works. The PSI score is still very poor ( &lt; 50).
Delay Loading Auto Ads Let&rsquo;s do it a little bit aggresive, loading the ads after 5s by setTimeout():
1 2 3 4 5 &lt;script&gt; setTimeout(function(){ ... }, 5000); &lt;/script&gt; The final implementation (remember to replace data-ad-client to your own id):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt; function downloadJsAtOnload() { setTimeout(function downloadJs() { var element = document.createElement(&#34;script&#34;); element.setAttribute(&#34;data-ad-client&#34;, &#34;ca-pub-000xxx&#34;); element.async = true; element.src = &#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&#34;; document.body.appendChild(element); }, 5000); }; if (window.addEventListener) window.addEventListener(&#34;load&#34;, downloadJsAtOnload, false); else if (window.attachEvent) window.attachEvent(&#34;onload&#34;, downloadJsAtOnload); else window.onload = downloadJsAtOnload; &lt;/script&gt; Now it works!
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Customize Hexo Blogroll Page</title><url>/en/simplest-blogroll/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>Hexo Extension</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Blogroll is natively supported in NexT theme. All links will be shown in the sidebar. However, as your links increases, the sidebar length increases as well. It makes the page lengthy and distracting. Therefore, we consider creating a dedicated blogroll page.
After searching, most of the existing approaches need to modify NexT source code (theme swig template files). The implementation is a little bit complicated while breaks the theme&rsquo;s integrity. When you update the theme later, you will need to manually merge or rebase the master to your code.
Actually, there is a straightforward solution. Consider that we can embed html to markdown, creating a new post with customized css/html would be enough. :-)
Potential solutions Let&rsquo;s discuss the following three solutions:
Use native NexT blogroll config Customize a new blogroll template and change the code Creating a customized post The first solution is easy but not scalable. The second solution is a little bit hard to implement and makes upgrading the theme harder. The final solution is easy to implement and maintain.
Customize Hexo blogroll page Create a post Create a new folder links in source, then create a file named index.md:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 --- title: Links date: 2021-06-16 00:34:27 --- &lt;div class=&#34;post-body&#34;&gt; &lt;div id=&#34;links&#34;&gt; &lt;style&gt; .links-content{ margin-top:1rem; } .link-navigation::after { content: &#34; &#34;; display: block; clear: both; } .card { width: 45%; font-size: 1rem; padding: 10px 20px; border-radius: 4px; transition-duration: 0.15s; margin-bottom: 1rem; display:flex; } .card:nth-child(odd) { float: left; } .card:nth-child(even) { float: right; } .card:hover { transform: scale(1.1); box-shadow: 0 2px 6px 0 rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.12), 0 0 6px 0 rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.04); } .card a { border:none; } .card .ava { width: 3rem!important; height: 3rem!important; margin:0!important; margin-right: 1em!important; border-radius:4px; } .card .card-header { font-style: italic; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; } .card .card-header a { font-style: normal; color: #2bbc8a; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none; } .card .card-header a:hover { color: #d480aa; text-decoration: none; } .card .card-header .info { font-style:normal; color:#a3a3a3; font-size:14px; min-width: 0; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; } &lt;/style&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;links-content&#34;&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;link-navigation&#34;&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; &lt;img class=&#34;ava&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/hvnobug/assets/common/avatar.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;card-header&#34;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hvnobug.com/&#34;&gt;Emil’s blog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;这是一个分享IT技术的小站。&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; &lt;img class=&#34;ava&#34; src=&#34;https://yingwiki.top/avatar&#34; /&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;card-header&#34;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://yingwiki.top&#34;&gt;越行勤&#39;s Blog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;努力学习的小菜鸟&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; 其实就是一段css再接上几个div，以后每加一个友链，只需要复制如下一段即可：
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; &lt;img class=&#34;ava&#34; src=&#34;{avatarurl}&#34; /&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;card-header&#34;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;{link}&#34;&gt;{name}&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;{description}&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; When you run hexo g, links/index.html will be generated.
Add a menu item links Open the NexT configuration file _config.yml, find the section menu and add a new line：
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 ... menu: tags: /tags/ || tags categories: /categories/ || th ... Links: /links/ || link ... Done! Run hexo clean and hexo g to check the result: References # Hexo个人博客自定义友链页面 # hexo博客next主题自定义友情链接页面   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Links</title><url>/en/flinks/</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html">  Please visit the Chinese version for friend links.
  </content></entry><entry><title>Hexo Change Permanent Link Format With Backward Compatibility</title><url>/en/change-permalink-format/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>SEO</tag><tag>Hexo</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently I would like to simplify permanent link for each post. From:
/2021/03/21/migrateopsmanager.en/
To:
/migrateopsmanager.en/
Shorter URL is more concise and readable, as the date string makes no sense to users. But what&rsquo;s the meaning of URL backward compatibility?
Change Permanent Link Format Issue According to the official document , changing permalink format is pretty easy: just modify :year/:month/:day/:title/ to :title/ would be OK. However, the real problem is that all existing incoming links will be invalid after this modification. Then the ranking of our site will be affected which is unacceptable.
Unlike WordPress, it&rsquo;s hard to make a 301 redirect in Hexo. I worked out some possible solutions:
Add a canonical link tag to &lt;head&gt; for each post Generated two permalinks, making the old one redirects to the new one by the first solution Keep existing permalinks unchanged, use new format for new posts To be safe, I choose the last one. So how to implement it?
New Post New Permalink Format Implementation The algorithm is straightforward: if the post creation time is after new_format_date, post process the permalink and remove the useless date string. We will try to write a fitler to implement it: https://hexo.io/api/filter Hexo passes data to filters in sequence and the filters then modify the data one after the other.
The first argument passed into each filter is data. The data passed into the next filter can be modified by returning a new value. If nothing is returned, the data remains unmodified.
After reading documentation, we found a filter called # post-permalink which is used to determine the permalink of posts:
1 2 3 hexo.extend.filter.register(&#39;post_permalink&#39;, function(data){ // ... }); The document doesn&rsquo;t explain the input parameter in detail. Actually, different filters have different input data structures. Maybe we need to read the source code. Specifically, for this filter, data is the permalink string like this: 2021/03/21/migrateopsmanager.en/ .
Let&rsquo;s create a scripts folder in the Hexo root folder and write a script refinepermalink.js:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 var new_format_date = new Date(&#39;2021-05-01&#39;); hexo.extend.filter.register(&#39;post_permalink&#39;, function(original_link){ var pivot = original_link.slice(0, -1).lastIndexOf(&#34;/&#34;) var date_str = original_link.substring(0, pivot); var date = new Date(date_str); var title = original_link.substring(pivot + 1); var result = original_link; if (date &gt; new_format_date) { result = title; console.log(&#39; &#39;, date, &#39;### Change permalink:&#39;, original_link, &#39;--&gt;&#39;, result); } return result; }); The above implementation is self-explained. Execute hexo g and then we are done:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 $ hexo g INFO Start processing 2021-06-14T16:00:00.000Z ### Change permalink: 2021/06/15/changepermalinkformat/ --&gt; changepermalinkformat/ 2021-05-01T16:00:00.000Z ### Change permalink: 2021/05/02/sqlservercleanupqueries/ --&gt; sqlservercleanupqueries/ 2021-05-01T16:00:00.000Z ### Change permalink: 2021/05/02/sqlservercleanupqueries.en/ --&gt; sqlservercleanupqueries.en/ INFO Files loaded in 1.99 s ... References # 玩转Hexo的Scripts # Getting started with Hexo Plug-ins, and scripts # Redirecting Old Permalinks on Statically Generated Blogs   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>SQL Server CleanUp Database Queries</title><url>/en/sql-server-cleanup-queries/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags><tag>SQL Server</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  We have a costly SQL server database with bad performance. Specifically, some store procedures (join several tables on primary key, each table has ~10M rows) were executed for several miniutes. The execution plan showed that the index seek costs 90% of the total time. Finally we found the root cause is the indexes have very high degree of fragmentation. Since its DBA had changed many times, we need to analyze the database schemas, table disk usage and storage procedure dependency tables. Based on these results, we cleanup tables, store procedures and rebuild the indexes to improve the DB performance. Here are the queries to accomplish these tasks.
Get Disk Usage By Table 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 SELECT t.NAME AS TableName, s.Name AS SchemaName, p.rows AS RowCounts, SUM(a.total_pages) * 8 / 1024 AS TotalSpaceMB, SUM(a.used_pages) * 8 / 1024 AS UsedSpaceMB, (SUM(a.total_pages) - SUM(a.used_pages)) * 8 /1024 AS UnusedSpaceMB FROM sys.tables t INNER JOIN sys.indexes i ON t.OBJECT_ID = i.object_id INNER JOIN sys.partitions p ON i.object_id = p.OBJECT_ID AND i.index_id = p.index_id INNER JOIN sys.allocation_units a ON p.partition_id = a.container_id LEFT OUTER JOIN sys.schemas s ON t.schema_id = s.schema_id WHERE t.NAME NOT LIKE &#39;dt%&#39; AND t.is_ms_shipped = 0 AND i.OBJECT_ID &gt; 255 GROUP BY t.Name, s.Name, p.Rows ORDER BY UsedSpaceMB DESC Sample result:
TableName SchemaName RowCounts TotalSpaceMB UsedSpaceMB UnusedSpaceMB T1 dbo 25609971 97735 97366 369 T2 dbo 157963374 76543 76341 201 T3 dbo 10714232 56383 53113 3269 T4 dbo 47533799 26000 25310 690 T5 dbo 15956528 17750 17742 8 Get Storage Procedure Usage 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 DECLARE @dbname varchar(30) = &#39;&#39;; select db_name(st.dbid) as database_name, object_name(st.objectid) as name, p.size_in_bytes / 1024 as size_in_kb, p.usecounts, st.text from sys.dm_exec_cached_plans p cross apply sys.dm_exec_sql_text(p.plan_handle) st where p.objtype = &#39;proc&#39; and st.dbid = db_id(@dbname) order by p.usecounts desc Sample result:
database_name name size_in_kb usecounts text D Proc_Upsert 8800 39675743 xxx D Proc_Update 1368 2216916 xxx D Proc_Select 280 1641531 xxx Get Storage Procedure Last Execution Time 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 SELECT DB_NAME(database_id) ,OBJECT_NAME(object_id,database_id) as procname ,cached_time ,last_execution_time ,execution_count FROM sys.dm_exec_procedure_stats order by procname Sample result:
procname cached_time last_execution_time execution_count CleanUpArticles 2021-04-20 17:00:02.710 2021-04-20 17:00:02.710 3788 CleanUpTables 2021-04-22 12:51:17.807 2021-04-22 12:51:17.807 6019 Proc_Select 2021-04-19 02:09:41.830 2021-04-19 02:09:41.830 3827 Get Storage Procedure Dependency Table 1 2 3 4 5 SELECT DISTINCT p.name AS proc_name, t.name AS table_name FROM sys.sql_dependencies d INNER JOIN sys.procedures p ON p.object_id = d.object_id INNER JOIN sys.tables t ON t.object_id = d.referenced_major_id ORDER BY proc_name, table_name Sample result:
proc_name table_name P1 T1 P2 T1 P2 T2 Get Amount of Index Fragmentation Refer to: # Resolve index fragmentation by reorganizing or rebuilding indexes 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 DECLARE @dbname varchar(30) = &#39;&#39;; DECLARE @tablename varchar(30) = &#39;&#39;; SELECT a.object_id, object_name(a.object_id) AS TableName, a.index_id, name AS IndedxName, avg_fragmentation_in_percent FROM sys.dm_db_index_physical_stats (DB_ID(@dbname) , OBJECT_ID(@tablename) , NULL , NULL , NULL) AS a INNER JOIN sys.indexes AS b ON a.object_id = b.object_id AND a.index_id = b.index_id; Sample result:
object_id TableName index_id IndedxName avg_fragmentation_in_percent 1733581214 T1 1 PK_dbo.T1 23.53719 1733581214 T1 3 key 22.5999 Rebuild Index 1 2 3 ALTER INDEX [PK_dbo.T1] ON [dbo].[T1] REBUILD WITH (ONLINE = ON); Reorganize Index 1 2 3 ALTER INDEX [PK_dbo.T1] ON [dbo].[T1] REORGANIZE;   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Migrate Ops Manager to a new Kubernetes Cluster</title><url>/en/migrate-ops-manager/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag></tags><content type="html">  Recently we want to deploy MongoDB Ops Manager and MongoDB deployments in different data centers to improve disaster recovery. If they are deploymented in the same data center and unfortunately it fails, you cannot restore the backup data to a new cluster as both Ops Manager and deployments are unavailable.
Of course, we don&amp;amp;rsquo;t want to re-deploy the existing MongoDB deployments in Kubernetes. But how to make the deployments sending data to the new ops manager URL?
How Ops Manager Works Previously I thought the Ops Manager and deployments were tightly coupled which is totally wrong. Actually they are independent of each other and can be independently deployed.
Here we deploy them in Kubernetes cluster. However, it&amp;amp;rsquo;s fine to deploy one in a VM and another in Kubernetes. MongoDB deployments use MongoDB Agent to send data to Ops Manager, and the Ops Manager uses groupId and apiKey to verify the deployment&amp;amp;rsquo;s identity and keep track of its status.
Therefore, the problem …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Strongly-Typed Collection Usage Example</title><url>/en/mongodb-strongly-typed-collection-example/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Using MongoDB in .NET is easy. However, there are two ways to manipulate the documents in C# code: raw bson document or stronly-typed document. In this article, we will compare the difference of them by examples. Basically, strongly-typed collection is preferred unless you have strong reason to use weakly-typed document (different types in the same collection?).
BsonDocument CRUD The MongoDB C# Driver Official Document provide examples in this style. I guess the reason is that MongoDB is schemaless and the driver would like to demonstrate how to access document without schema. Actually, noSQL doesn&amp;rsquo;t means no SQL but stands for not only SQL. Creating a schema for a collection is still recommended because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to access documents and use index.
Here is the demo&amp;rsquo;s document definition:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 public class DemoEntry { public string Uuid { get; set; } public string Value { get; set; } public override string ToString() { return Uuid + &amp;#34;: &amp;#34; + …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How to Retry MongoDB Transaction</title><url>/en/mongodb-retry-transaction/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Transaction</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  MongoDB transaction is a nice feature. Although MongoDB uses optimistic concurrency control, write conflict is unavoidable. The situation becomes worse in multi-document transaction which modifies many documents in one transaction. If a write conflict happens, a MongoDBCommandException will be thrown:
Exception: Command update failed: Encountered error from mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017 during a transaction :: caused by :: WriteConflict error: this operation conflicted with another operation. Please retry your operation or multi-document transaction..
How to handle the writeconflict error in MongoDB?
A straightforwad way is to manually retry the transaction in application level when exception happens. However, the retry logic is non-trivial: What&amp;amp;rsquo;s the exception type? Is it a transient or persistent error ? How many times should we retry? How to apply the retry logic while keep the code clean?
Fortunately, the new MongoDB driver has already solved the issue. It incorperates the …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Agent Monitoring and Backup not Working</title><url>/en/mongodb-agent-monitoring-not-work/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Today I try to import an existing MongoDB deployment (out of the kubernetes cluster) into MongoDB Ops Manager which is running in kubernetes. After installing MongoDB Agent to the deployment, only automation functionality works while monitoring and backup not work. The root cause is that the agent still try to post data into Ops Manager&rsquo;s internal endpoint.
The latest MongoDB Agent consists of a single binary that contains all three functions: Automation, Monitoring, and Backup. So theoretically install and configure the all-in-one automation agent in the deployment VM is enough.
Configure the automation agent according to this , edit mmsBaseUrl in /etc/mongodb-mms/automation-agent.config (assume our Ops Manager public url is http://myopsmanager.com:8080, other fields such as mmsApiKey are omitted here):
1 2 3 ... mmsBaseUrl=http://myopsmanager.com:8080 ... Startthe automation agent service:
1 $ systemctl start mongodb-mms-automation-agent.service Verify the agent in the Ops Manager and import the deployment. In the Ops Manager server page, only automation is green, while monitoring and backup functionality is still grey (standby). Check the backup agent log in the deployment VM:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 /var/log/mongodb-mms-automation$ cat backup-agent.log [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] AgentVersion = 10.14.17.6445 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] GitCommitHash = 0000000000000000000000000000000000000000 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] ManagedAgent = true [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] GoVersion = go1.14.7 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] mothership = ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:8080 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] https = false [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] httpProxy = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] krb5Principal = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] krb5Keytab = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] krb5ConfigLocation = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] gssapiServiceName = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] sslClientCertificate = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] sslTrustedServerCertificates = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] sslRequireValidServerCertificates = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] sslTrustedMMSBackupServerCertificate = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] logFile = /var/log/mongodb-mms-automation/backup-agent.log [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] maxLogFileSizeBytes = 104857600 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] maxLogFileDurationHrs = 240 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] enableKeepAlive = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] keepAliveDuration = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] connDeadline = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.245+0000] [header.info] [::0] mothershipResponseHeaderTimeout = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.444+0000] [agent.info] [backupexecutor/executor.go:Execute:75] Starting backup module version 10.14.17.6445 0000000000000000000000000000000000000000 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.492+0000] [agent.info] [commonbackup/utils.go:func1:217] Listen for shutdown signal [2021-01-20T07:49:51.494+0000] [agent.warn] [components/agent.go:Iterate:69] Unable to load latest configuration from server. Will try again. Tag: unassigned Err: Op: Get Err: dial tcp: lookup ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local: Temporary failure in name resolution [2021-01-20T07:50:50.713+0000] [agent.warn] [components/agent.go:Iterate:69] Unable to load latest configuration from server. Will try again. Tag: unassigned Err: Op: Get Err: dial tcp: lookup ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local: Temporary failure in name resolution Check the monitoring agent log:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 /var/log/mongodb-mms-automation$ cat monitoring-agent.log [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] AgentVersion = 10.14.17.6445 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] GitCommitHash = 0000000000000000000000000000000000000000 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] ManagedAgent = true [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] GoVersion = go1.14.7 ... [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] maxProfilingEntries = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] mmsBaseUrl = http://ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:8080 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] logFile = /var/log/mongodb-mms-automation/monitoring-agent.log [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] maxLogFileSizeBytes = 104857600 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] maxLogFileDurationHrs = 240 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] useWindowsEventLog = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.248+0000] [header.info] [::0] zlibCompressionLevel = &lt;unset&gt; [2021-01-20T07:49:51.444+0000] [agent.info] [monitoringexecutor/executor.go:Execute:99] Starting monitoring module [2021-01-20T07:49:51.444+0000] [services.compressor.info] [monitoring/encoding.go:NewPoolingZlibCompressor:243] Starting 2 compressor handlers [2021-01-20T07:49:51.444+0000] [agent.info] [monitoring/agent.go:NewOnlineAgent:288] Creating generic consumer pool with a limit of 4 consumers [2021-01-20T07:49:51.490+0000] [agent.error] [monitoring/agent.go:Iterate:171] Failed to fetch Conf Failure getting conf. Op: Get Err: dial tcp: lookup ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local: Temporary failure in name resolution at cm/monitoring/server.go:167 at cm/monitoring/server.go:219 at cm/monitoring/agent.go:169 at cm/monitoring/agent.go:261 at monitoring/monitoringexecutor/executor.go:125 at louisaberger/procexec/concurrency.go:45 at src/runtime/asm_amd64.s:1373 [2021-01-20T07:49:51.490+0000] [agent.info] [monitoring/agent.go:Run:266] Done. Sleeping for 27s... Obviously, the monitoring and the backup modules are still using internal ops manager URL. However, I don&rsquo;t find anywhere else to configure the mmsBaseUrl except /etc/mongodb-mms/automation-agent.config.
Since MongoDB Agent is not open-sourced, we cannot figure out how it get mmsBaseUrl.
A simple workaround is to use hosts file to map the internal endpoint to the Ops Manager service public IP (e.g. myopsmanager.com IP), edit /etc/hosts:
1 xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local And it works.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Agent Host Discovery Issue</title><url>/en/mongodb-host-discovery-issue/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  I have a sharded cluster (2 shards, each 3 mongods; 3 config server, 2 mongoses) which is deployed by MongoDB Ops Manager.
Last week, one of the shard host status was shown as a grey diamond (Hover: &ldquo;Last Ping: Never&rdquo;). Besides, in the Ops Manager&rsquo;s server page, a server had two processes (e.g. sharddb-0 and sharddb-config). However, the cluster still works well and we can list the host sharddb-0-0(shard 0, replica 0) in the mongo shell by sh.status() and rs.status(). What&rsquo;s wrong with the cluster?
Problem Analysis It looks like that one of the server is out of Ops Manager&rsquo;s monitoring (but the agent log was still collected in time): In the first glance, I thought the issue was caused by the host. Therefore, I deleted the corresponding pod as well as its pvc in kubernetes and waiting for the host to be recovered. No luck.
Monitoring Logs I checked the automation agent log:
[2021-01-15T10:13:03.299+0000] [discovery.monitor.info] [monitoring/discovery.go:discover:793] Performing discovery with 10 hosts [2021-01-15T10:13:06.661+0000] [discovery.monitor.info] [monitoring/discovery.go:discover:850] Received discovery responses from 20/20 requests after 3s [2021-01-15T10:13:58.298+0000] [agent.info] [monitoring/agent.go:Run:266] Done. Sleeping for 55s&hellip; [2021-01-15T10:13:58.298+0000] [discovery.monitor.info] [monitoring/discovery.go:discover:793] Performing discovery with 10 hosts
Looks like the issue was caused by mongodb-mms-automation-agent host discovery.
Since there are 11 hosts in total (2 * 3 + 3 + 2 = 11), the mongodb-mms-automation-agent needs to send 22 requests instead of 20. That&rsquo;s why it doesn&rsquo;t discover host sharddb-0-0.
System Warnings After that, I found some system warnings in the admin page:
Automation metrics found conflicting canonical hosts=[sharddb-0-0.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017] within all ping&rsquo;s hosts=[sharddb-0-0.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017]. Skipping this sample.
Backup agent warnings:
com.xgen.svc.mms.svc.alert.AlertProcessingSvc [runAlertCheck:187] Alert check failed: groupId=5ff879a85d86101b89072b19, event=BACKUP_AGENT_DOWN, target=unassigned java.lang.IllegalStateException: Duplicate key sharddb-0-0.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local (attempted merging values BackupAgentAudit{Id: 5ff8802c39e579142fd18bcd, GroupId: 5ff879a85d86101b89072b19, Hostname: sharddb-0-0.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local, Version: 10.14.17.6445} and BackupAgentAudit{Id: 5ff8802d39e579142fd18d2f, GroupId: 5ff879a85d86101b89072b19, Hostname: sharddb-0-1.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local, Version: 10.14.17.6445})
The above logs indicate that the host sharddb-0-0 is conflicted with some other hosts. But how to make the automation agent discover the missing hosts?
Solution After one week grinding, I accidently found the culprit: conflict host mappings. What&rsquo;s host mappings? Refer to: Host Mappings Go to Deployment -&gt; More -&gt; Host Mappings to check the existing host mappings. If you find something like this:
Host Alias sharddb-0-0.sharddb-sh.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017 sharddb-0-1:27017 That means sharddb-0-0 is mapped to sharddb-0-1, then conflicting hosts issue occurs.
Solution: delete the conflict host mappings, or simply delete all host mappings. (Don&rsquo;t worry, the mapping will be reconstructed several minutes later.)
I guess the root cause is that the Ops Manager doesn&rsquo;t update the host mappings timely. If host A obtain a new IP which is previously used by host B, then the issue happens.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Don't Use Load Balancer In front of Mongos</title><url>/en/dont-use-load-balancer-in-front-of-mongos/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>.NET Core</tag><tag>C#</tag><tag>Sharding</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When I execute MongoDB transactions in parallel, I encounter lots of MongoCommandException: code 251, codename NoSuchTransaction:
Command find failed: cannot continue txnId 4 for session 38604515-2584-45a5-a17a-5eb5d34ea6c4 - = with txnId 5. Command find failed: cannot continue txnId 4 for session 38604515-2584-45a5-a17a-5eb5d34ea6c4 - = with txnId 6. Command insert failed: cannot continue txnId 31 for session 3ed7ea61-eae1-440f-8d95-b6e066b35b69 - = with txnId 34.
Problem Analysis I performed some tests to pinpoint the issue:
Use single thread to execute transaction, no error Use a dedicated MongoClient for each thread (each transaction), no error It seems that it&rsquo;s a MongoDB driver bug related to the MongoClient. Then I create a issue here: # Multi-thread Transaction Failure for Sharded Cluster .
However, the culprit is the load balancer in front of mongos. A MongoDB transaction in sharded cluster must be executed in the same mongos instance. If you put a load balancer in front of mongos instances, the operations inside a transaction might be executed in different mongos then the above errors happen.
Refer to: # Transactions issue on sharded cluster Look at Mongos Pinning :
Drivers MUST send all commands for a single transaction to the same mongos (excluding retries of commitTransaction and abortTransaction).
After the driver selects a mongos for the first command within a transaction, the driver MUST pin the ClientSession to the selected mongos. Drivers MUST send all subsequent commands that are part of the same transaction (excluding certain retries of commitTransaction and abortTransaction) to the same mongos.
Expose Each Mongos as a Dedicated Service So we need to expose every mongos to public seperately. I finally understand why the official document uses nodeport instead of kubernetes service to expose externally.
Here is a sample mongos-service.yaml which creates a dedicated service for each mongos instance (e.g. 2 mongoses), the trick is to explicitly specify the pod name in the spec.selector:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 apiVersion: v1 kind: Service metadata: name: mongos-svc-0 namespace: mongodb labels: app: sharddb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator spec: type: LoadBalancer ports: - protocol: TCP port: 27017 targetPort: 27017 selector: app: sharddb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator statefulset.kubernetes.io/pod-name: sharddb-mongos-0 --- apiVersion: v1 kind: Service metadata: name: mongos-svc-1 namespace: mongodb labels: app: sharddb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator spec: type: LoadBalancer ports: - protocol: TCP port: 27017 targetPort: 27017 selector: app: sharddb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator statefulset.kubernetes.io/pod-name: sharddb-mongos-1 Refer to: # Deploy MongoDB Sharded Cluster by Ops Manager Error Reproduce Code 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 public class TransactionTest { private const string DatabaseName = &#34;Test&#34;; private const string CollectionName = &#34;Test&#34;; public const string ConnectionString = &#34;&#34;; public MongoClient GetMongoClient(int timeout = 5) { var clientSettings = MongoClientSettings.FromConnectionString(ConnectionString); clientSettings.ConnectTimeout = TimeSpan.FromSeconds(5); clientSettings.ServerSelectionTimeout = TimeSpan.FromSeconds(timeout); clientSettings.AllowInsecureTls = true; var mongoClient = new MongoClient(clientSettings); return mongoClient; } public async Task TestTransactionAsync() { var client = GetMongoClient(); var tasks = new List&lt;Task&gt;(); for (int i = 0; i &lt; 5; ++i) { //var client = GetMongoClient(i + 5); tasks.Add(DoAsync(client)); } await Task.WhenAll(tasks); } private async Task DoAsync(IMongoClient mongoClient) { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Client hashcode: &#34; + mongoClient.GetHashCode()); var collection = mongoClient.GetDatabase(DatabaseName).GetCollection&lt;BsonDocument&gt;(CollectionName); while (true) { var uuid1 = Guid.NewGuid().ToString(&#34;N&#34;).Substring(24); var uuid2 = Guid.NewGuid().ToString(&#34;N&#34;).Substring(24); try { using (var session = await mongoClient.StartSessionAsync()) { session.StartTransaction(); await collection.InsertOneAsync(session, new BsonDocument(&#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid1)); await collection.InsertOneAsync(session, new BsonDocument(&#34;Uuid&#34;, uuid2)); await session.CommitTransactionAsync(); } Console.WriteLine($&#34;[{uuid1}] [{uuid2}]&#34;); } catch (Exception e) { Console.WriteLine(&#34;$$$ &#34; + e.Message); } } } }   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Lightsquid Stop Working in 2021</title><url>/en/lightsquid-hardcode-year/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[   Lightsquid is a handy log analyzer for squid proxy. However, the project is not maintained since 2009.
Today, I found lightsquid doesn&rsquo;t work in 2021. Why?
Lightsquid Error When I run lightparser, the output looks like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 $ ./lightparser.pl access.log.66666 &gt;&gt;&gt; use file :: /var/log/squid/access.log.66666 run TIME: 1 sec LightSquid parser statistic report 3312 lines processed (average 3312.00 lines per second) 0 lines parsed 0 lines recovered 0 lines notrecovered 0 lines skiped by bad year 3312 lines skiped by date filter 0 lines skiped by Denied filter 0 lines skiped by skipURL filter WARNING !!!!, parsed 0 lines from total : 3312 please check confiuration !!!! may be wrong log format selected ? Seems that all lines are filtered by the date filter. I double checked the log format and make sure it is correct and the same with previous days.
Analyze the Problem Look at this piece of code (I am a Perl layman): here 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 my $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,31,12-1,2020-1900)+1000; $fToday=1 if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;today&#34;); $fToday=1 if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;yesterday&#34;); if ($fToday) { ($sec,$min,$hour,$mday,$mon,$year,$wday,$yday,$isdst) = localtime; $filterdate=sprintf(&#34;%04d%02d%02d&#34;,$year+1900,$mon+1,$mday);; $filterdatestart=timelocal( 0, 0, 0,$mday,$mon,$year); $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,$mday,$mon,$year); print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; filter today: $filterdate\n&#34; if ($debug); } if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;yesterday&#34;) { $filterdatestart=$filterdatestart-(24*60*60); $filterdatestop =$filterdatestop -(24*60*60); ($sec,$min,$hour,$mday,$mon,$year,$wday,$yday,$isdst) = localtime($filterdatestart); $filterdate=sprintf(&#34;%04d%02d%02d&#34;,$year+1900,$mon+1,$mday);; print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; filter yesterday: $filterdate\n&#34; if ($debug); } if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/^(\d\d\d\d)(\d\d)(\d\d)$/) { $filterdate=$ARGV[0]; $filterdatestart=timelocal( 0, 0, 0,$3,$2-1,$1); $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,$3,$2-1,$1); print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; filter date:	$filterdate\n&#34; if ($debug); } if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/access\.log\.(\d)/) { $filename=$ARGV[0]; $catname=&#34;zcat&#34; if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/\.gz$/); $catname=&#34;bzcat&#34; if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/\.bz2$/); } print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; use file :: $logpath/$filename\n&#34; if ($debug); ... #speed optimization for FILTERDATE mode $Ltimestamp=substr $_,0,11; if ($Ltimestamp&lt;$filterdatestart or $Ltimestamp&gt;$filterdatestop) { print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; skipDafteFilter URL $Lurl\n$_&#34; if ($debug2 &gt;= 2 ); $skipfilterdatecntr++; next; }; Found two issues:
A hardcode 2020 in $filterdatestop which makes lightsquid not work in 2021 today argument cannot work with customized file at the same time First Issue Obviously, $filterdatestop is the culprit:
1 my $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,31,12-1,2020-1900)+1000; A quick fix is to change the hardcoded 2020 to 2100. It seems that the month and year parameter are weird&hellip;
I read the document of Perl&rsquo;s &ldquo;Time::Local&rdquo; and found that the design is really complex and hard to understand (personally I think it is anti-pattern, why not make it a simple design which supports only absolute year?):
Years greater than 999 are interpreted as being the actual year, rather than the offset from 1900. Thus, 1964 would indicate the year Martin Luther King won the Nobel prize, not the year 3864. Years in the range 100..999 are interpreted as offset from 1900, so that 112 indicates 2012. This rule also applies to years less than zero (but see note below regarding date range). Years in the range 0..99 are interpreted as shorthand for years in the rolling &ldquo;current century,&rdquo; defined as 50 years on either side of the current year. Thus, today, in 1999, 0 would refer to 2000, and 45 to 2045, but 55 would refer to 1955. Twenty years from now, 55 would instead refer to 2055. This is messy, but matches the way people currently think about two digit dates. Whenever possible, use an absolute four digit year instead. Then I try to understand what these lines means:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 use Time::Local; my $date1 = timelocal(59,59,23,31,12-1,2020-1900); my $date2 = timelocal(59,59,23,31,12-1,2020-1900)+1000; my $date3 = timelocal(59,59,23,31,11,2020); print &#34;$date1\n&#34;; print &#34;$date2\n&#34;; print &#34;$date3\n&#34;; Output:
1 2 3 1609430399 1609431399 1609430399 The solution is easy, change this line to(note that the month is zero indexed (0..11)), and now it works until 2100:
1 my $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,31,11,2100)+1000; Second Issue Another problem is that today argument cannot work with customized filename:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 $fToday=1 if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;today&#34;); $fToday=1 if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;yesterday&#34;); if ($fToday) { ... } if ($ARGV[0] eq &#34;yesterday&#34;) { ... } if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/^(\d\d\d\d)(\d\d)(\d\d)$/) { $filterdate=$ARGV[0]; $filterdatestart=timelocal( 0, 0, 0,$3,$2-1,$1); $filterdatestop =timelocal(59,59,23,$3,$2-1,$1); print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; filter date:	$filterdate\n&#34; if ($debug); } if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/access\.log\.(\d)/) { $filename=$ARGV[0]; $catname=&#34;zcat&#34; if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/\.gz$/); $catname=&#34;bzcat&#34; if ($ARGV[0] =~ m/\.bz2$/); } print &#34;&gt;&gt;&gt; use file :: $logpath/$filename\n&#34; if ($debug); Apparently, only one argument ARGV[0] is applied. If you wrote the command like this and not fixed the first issue:
1 $./lightparser.pl access.log.66666 today or
1 $./lightparser.pl today access.log.66666 You will encounter the &ldquo;parsed 0 lines&rdquo; error.
Summary Just fix the first issue and you will make lightsquid works longer :-)
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 $ ./lightparser.pl access.log.66666 &gt;&gt;&gt; use file :: /var/log/squid/access.log.66666 &gt;&gt;&gt; Make Report 20210102 (1577 - log line parsed) &gt;&gt;&gt; Make Report 20210103 (1572 - log line parsed) run TIME: 1 sec LightSquid parser statistic report 3312 lines processed (average 3312.00 lines per second) 3149 lines parsed 0 lines recovered 0 lines notrecovered 0 lines skiped by bad year 0 lines skiped by date filter 163 lines skiped by Denied filter 0 lines skiped by skipURL filter Fixed version: https://github.com/finisky/lightsquid-1.8.1   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Deploy MongoDB Sharded Cluster by Ops Manager</title><url>/en/mongodb-om-create-sharded-cluster/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag><tag>Sharding</tag></tags><content type="html">  MongoDB sharded cluster is the most complicated architecture. The deployment of sharded cluster in Kubernetes is relatively hard. We will go through the deployment process by MongoDB Ops Manager in this post.
Before start, please go through the Create a UserDB ReplicaSet first.
A MongoDB sharded cluster consists of the following components:
shard : Each shard contains a subset of the sharded data. Each shard can be deployed as a replica set . mongos : The mongos acts as a query router, providing an interface between client applications and the sharded cluster. config servers : Config servers store metadata and configuration settings for the cluster. In this post, we are going to create a sharded cluster with 2 shards (3 instances replica set), 2 mongos and 3 config servers.
MongoDB Ops Manager Series:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth Create a Sharded Cluster The creation …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Cluster In Kubernetes(5): Enable UserDB TLS and Auth</title><url>/en/mongodb-om-tls-auth/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html">  This is part5, we will use the generated certficates to enable user database TLS and AUTH.
MongoDB Ops Manager Series:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth Understanding Different Secure Connections Before we start, look at the following three TLS:
Secure Connections to Ops Manager Secure Connections to Application Database Secure Connections to MongoDB Deployments A picture is worth a thousand words: What we want is the last one: Enable TLS to MongoDB Deployments. Unfortunately, this configuration cannot be performed through Ops Manger web UI as well. Because we need to &amp;amp;ldquo;upload&amp;amp;rdquo; certificate to each server but the UI does not has such capability.
If you read the Ops Manager document # Enable TLS for a Deployment :
Get and Install the TLS Certificate on Each MongoDB Host
Acquire a TLS certificate for each host serving a MongoDB process. This certificate must …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Cluster In Kubernetes(4): Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates</title><url>/en/mongodb-om-self-signed-certificates/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html">  This is part4, we will create a self-signed CA certificate and three server certificates.
MongoDB Ops Manager Series:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth Self-signed certificates is not recommended for production. It cannot prevent man-in-the-middle attack. Since our main purpose is to encrypt the communication messages instead of authentication. Self-signed certificates is acceptable.
Get Internal Server Endpoints Look at the userdb servers: The userdb ReplicaSet has 3 servers, they communicates with each other by internal endpoints:
userdb-0.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local userdb-1.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local userdb-2.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local In Part 3 we have configured the external endpoints: userdb0.com, userdb1.com, userdb2.com for servers. Therefore, we can access the userdb by internal endpoints xxx.svc.cluster.local inside kubernetes …  </content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Cluster In Kubernetes(3): Expose UserDB to Public</title><url>/en/mongodb-om-expose-services/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  This is part3, we will expose the user database pods to the public so that Mongo client is able to access it.
MongoDB Ops Manager Series:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth So far, the user database can be accessed only inside the kubernetes cluster. The official blog&rsquo;s approach is to expose the pods by NodePort: # Connect to a MongoDB Database Resource from Outside Kubernetes I don&rsquo;t know why the official blog recommend NodePort. Obviously, LoadBalancer is a better way to expose MongoDB. We will use LoadBalancer to expose userdb pods.
Create LoadBalancer Service Configure userdb0service.yaml:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 apiVersion: v1 kind: Service metadata: name: userdb-0-svc-ext namespace: mongodb labels: app: userdb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator pod-anti-affinity: userdb statefulset.kubernetes.io/pod-name: userdb-0 spec: type: LoadBalancer ports: - protocol: TCP port: 27017 targetPort: 27017 selector: app: userdb-svc controller: mongodb-enterprise-operator pod-anti-affinity: userdb statefulset.kubernetes.io/pod-name: userdb-0 Apply it:
1 2 $ kubectl apply -f userdb0service.yaml service/userdb-0-svc-ext created After a while, the service userdb-0-svc-ext will be assigned a public IP. Then we can bind a domain name to the IP (optional). Suppose the domain name is userdb0.com.
Modify the above yaml and create another two services userdb-1-svc-ext and userdb-2-svc-ext to expose the two remaining pods.
MongoClient Connection Test, getaddrinfo ENOTFOUND Error Now we can use mongo shell to access userdb:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 $ mongo &#34;mongodb://&lt;ip0&gt;:27017,&lt;ip1&gt;:27017,&lt;ip2&gt;:27017/&#34; MongoDB shell version v4.4.2 connecting to: mongodb://&lt;ip0&gt;:27017,&lt;ip1&gt;:27017,&lt;ip2&gt;:27017/?compressors=disabled&amp;gssapiServiceName=mongodb Implicit session: session { &#34;id&#34; : UUID(&#34;6b780874-6ecb-4510-b7e9-61bff04a4711&#34;) } MongoDB server version: 4.2.2 WARNING: shell and server versions do not match --- The server generated these startup warnings when booting: 2020-12-10T08:32:10.037+0000 I STORAGE [initandlisten] 2020-12-10T08:32:10.037+0000 I STORAGE [initandlisten] ** WARNING: Using the XFS filesystem is strongly recommended with the WiredTiger storage engine 2020-12-10T08:32:10.037+0000 I STORAGE [initandlisten] ** See http://dochub.mongodb.org/core/prodnotes-filesystem 2020-12-10T08:32:10.848+0000 I CONTROL [initandlisten] 2020-12-10T08:32:10.848+0000 I CONTROL [initandlisten] ** WARNING: Access control is not enabled for the database. 2020-12-10T08:32:10.848+0000 I CONTROL [initandlisten] ** Read and write access to data and configuration is unrestricted. 2020-12-10T08:32:10.848+0000 I CONTROL [initandlisten] --- MongoDB Enterprise userdb:SECONDARY&gt; Looks something wrong. Why the prompt shows that we connect to a SECONDARY node? The default mongo readPreference is PRIMARY.
If you connect the DB through MongoDB Compass, the following error appears:
1 getaddrinfo ENOTFOUND userdb-0.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local After investigation, this article # Connecting from external sources to MongoDB replica set in Kubernetes fails with getaddrinfo ENOTFOUND error but standalone works answered my question:
When connecting to a replica set, the host:port pairs in the connection string are a seedlist.
The driver/client will attempt to connect to each host in the seedlist in turn until it gets a connection.
It runs the isMaster command to determine which node is primary, and to get a list of all replica set members.
Then is drops the original seedlist connection, and attempts to connect to each replica set member using the host and port information retrieved.
The host information returned by the isMaster usually matches the entry in rs.conf(), which are the hostnames used to initiate the replica set.
In your Kubernetes cluster, the nodes have internal hostnames that are used to initiate the replica set, but that your external clients can&rsquo;t resolve.
In order to get this to work, you will need to have the mongod nodes isMaster command return a different set of hostnames depending on where the client request is coming from. This is similar to split-horizon DNS.
Look over the Deploy a Replica Set documentation for mongodb/kubernetes, and the replicaSetHorizons setting.
Verify by running rs.conf() in the mongo shell:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 MongoDB Enterprise userdb:SECONDARY&gt; rs.conf() { &#34;_id&#34; : &#34;userdb&#34;, &#34;version&#34; : 1, &#34;protocolVersion&#34; : NumberLong(1), &#34;writeConcernMajorityJournalDefault&#34; : true, &#34;members&#34; : [ { &#34;_id&#34; : 0, &#34;host&#34; : &#34;userdb-0.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017&#34;, ... }, { &#34;_id&#34; : 1, &#34;host&#34; : &#34;userdb-1.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017&#34;, ... }, { &#34;_id&#34; : 2, &#34;host&#34; : &#34;userdb-2.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:27017&#34;, ... } ], &#34;settings&#34; : { ... } } Besides, mongo shell and MongoDB Compass have different behaviors when connecting to multiple hosts:
mongo shell: show connect success but it might not be true: only one node is connected MongoDB Compass: connect failed The behavior is caused by different connection policies. To solve the problem, we need to use spec.connectivity.replicaSetHorizons to specify the public address. However, to use this setting, spec.security.tls must be enabled first:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 security: tls: enabled: true connectivity: replicaSetHorizons: - &#34;userdb&#34;: &#34;userdb0.com:27017&#34; - &#34;userdb&#34;: &#34;userdb1.com:27017&#34; - &#34;userdb&#34;: &#34;userdb2.com:27017&#34; The bad news is that enable TLS is more complicated than I thought before. Here we use self-signed certificates to encrypt the transport layer communication. Four certificates are required: 1 CA certificate and 3 server certificates.
Let&rsquo;s create the certificates step by step: Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Cluster In Kubernetes(2): Create a UserDB ReplicaSet</title><url>/en/mongodb-om-create-user-db/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  This is part2, we will create a user database that is a 3 instances ReplicaSet.
MongoDB Ops Manager Series:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth The so called Application Database is the backend DB of Ops Manager. It cannot be used to store user data. The user database is called MongoDB Deployment. Note that the deployment is different with Kubernetes deployment.
For simplicity, we will create a replicaset instead of a sharded cluster. The configuration process is almost the same. Because sharded cluster consists of more components, the configuration is more complicated. Let&rsquo;s start with an easier one. :-)
Reference: Deploy MongoDB Sharded Cluster by Ops Manager Unfortunately, creating user database cannot be directly done by the Ops Manager web UI. Most of the operations should be performed by the MongoDB Kubernetes Operator, aka the kubectl command line. If you try to create it through web UI, you need to manually configure variety of parameters and install Agents which I don&rsquo;t know how to do it. So to my understanding, Ops Manager is a great tool for visualization and automation tasks, but not good at cluster manipulation. I think the reason is that the cluster specification is too complicated to incorperated to the UI.
The official blog created user database by a new generated API key. However, I always failed with this method. I bypass the issue by creating the user database by ops-manager-admin-key. Though it&rsquo;s not recommended, it works. Update 2020-12-23: Please follow the official approach below. The 401 unauthorized issue is caused by that the API Key Secret username is not the same with the admin username.
The Official Approach Generate a Public API Key Go to Ops Manager, &ldquo;UserName -&gt; Account -&gt; Public API Access&rdquo;, click the top right-most &ldquo;Account&rdquo;: Note that the &lt;apikey&gt; appears only once, please well remembered.
Create API Key Secret Make sure that the user specified here is the same with the Ops Manager admin user!(created at Install MongoDB Ops Manager )
1 2 $ kubectl create secret generic om-user-credentials --from-literal=&#34;user=xxx@xxx.com&#34; --from-literal=&#34;publicApiKey=&lt;apikey&gt;&#34; -n mongodb secret/om-user-credentials created Create Ops Manager Connection ConfigMap Find Ops Manager url first:
1 2 $ kubectl get om ops-manager -o jsonpath=&#39;{.status.opsManager.url}&#39; -n mongodb http://ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:8080 Create ops-manager-connection ConfigMap with the above URL：
1 2 $ kubectl create configmap ops-manager-connection --from-literal=&#34;baseUrl=http://ops-manager-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local:8080&#34; -n mongodb configmap/ops-manager-connection created Create User Database userdb Create the user database by kubectl, edit the userdb.yaml and fill in credential and configMap fields:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 apiVersion: mongodb.com/v1 kind: MongoDB metadata: name: userdb namespace: mongodb spec: members: 3 version: 4.2.2-ent type: ReplicaSet opsManager: configMapRef: name: ops-manager-connection credentials: om-user-credentials 1 2 $ kubectl apply -f userdb.yaml -n mongodb mongodb.mongodb.com/userdb created Simple(Crude) Approach (Not Recommended) Please follow the official approach above.
You might encounter the following error after apply userdb.yaml:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 $ kubectl get mdb -n mongodb NAME TYPE STATE VERSION AGE userdb ReplicaSet Failed 4.2.2-ent 86s $ kubectl describe mdb -n mongodb Name: userdb Namespace: mongodb Labels: &lt;none&gt; Annotations: kubectl.kubernetes.io/last-applied-configuration: {&#34;apiVersion&#34;:&#34;mongodb.com/v1&#34;,&#34;kind&#34;:&#34;MongoDB&#34;,&#34;metadata&#34;:{&#34;annotations&#34;:{},&#34;name&#34;:&#34;userdb&#34;,&#34;namespace&#34;:&#34;mongodb&#34;},&#34;spec&#34;:{&#34;credentials&#34;:... API Version: mongodb.com/v1 Kind: MongoDB Metadata: Creation Timestamp: 2020-12-10T08:19:02Z Generation: 1 Resource Version: 52201207 Self Link: /apis/mongodb.com/v1/namespaces/mongodb/mongodb/userdb UID: 8c04df70-5249-4c3b-8a28-3907890e4eb8 Spec: Credentials: om-user-credentials Members: 3 Ops Manager: Config Map Ref: Name: ops-manager-connection Type: ReplicaSet Version: 4.2.2-ent Status: Last Transition: 2020-12-10T08:20:33Z Message: Failed to prepare Ops Manager connection: Error reading or creating project in Ops Manager: Status: 401 (Unauthorized), Detail: You are not authorized for this resource. Observed Generation: 1 Phase: Failed Version: Events: &lt;none&gt; 401 (Unauthorized) error, it seems that the generated key is not valid.
I found an API key in the Public API access page by chance. Although the whole key is partially shown in the Ops Manager, we can found the original key in the kubernetes secret: ops-manager-admin-key. Let&rsquo;s check the last bits of the ops-manager-admin-key in the Ops Manager: Modify the last line of userdb.yaml：
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 apiVersion: mongodb.com/v1 kind: MongoDB metadata: name: userdb namespace: mongodb spec: members: 3 version: 4.2.2-ent type: ReplicaSet opsManager: configMapRef: name: ops-manager-connection credentials: ops-manager-admin-key Then apply it. It works!
Again, this method is not recommended, but till now I don&rsquo;t find other alternatives.
A new statefulset userdb is creating, wait until the state becomes &ldquo;Running&rdquo;:
1 2 3 $ kubectl get mdb -n mongodb NAME TYPE STATE VERSION AGE userdb ReplicaSet Running 4.2.2-ent 13m Refresh the Ops Manager UI, click All Clusters, you will find that there are 2 clusters with corresponding context and Project: View userdb processes: Found that both TLS and AUTH are disabled. The transport layer communication is not encryped, username/password is not required.
View userdb servers: Note that the server address is something like: userdb-0.userdb-svc.mongodb.svc.cluster.local, which is an internal address. Therefore, we cannot connect to the userdb through Mongo Client.
Now the user database is sucessfully created!
Next we will expose the user database to the public by creating services: Expose UserDB to Public   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Cluster In Kubernetes(1): Install MongoDB Ops Manager</title><url>/en/mongodb-ops-manager/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>Kubernetes</tag><tag>MongoDB Ops Manager</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  It&rsquo;s pretty easy to configure a MongoDB standalone instance (almost zero configuration). However, if you want to run a production-level MongoDB cluster, the configuration process is non-trivial. For a production cluster, replication/sharding/dyanmic scaling/backup/transport encryption/monitoring are required. Is there a nice tool to help us?
MongoDB cluster is a distributed system, which is well suited to run in Kubernetes. However, the collaboration of MongoDB instances usually need to manually run commands on each instance which is independent of Kubernetes. Therefore, MongoDB Enterprise Kubernetes Operator is developed to mitigate the gap. Morever, MongoDB Ops Manager is a great web portal to help these automation tasks.
The whole deployment and configure process is a little bit long, I wrote a series of small pieces to make each of them compact and easy to follow:
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create a UserDB ReplicaSet Expose UserDB to Public Openssl Generates Self-signed Certificates Enable UserDB TLS and Auth Prerequisites
Have a Kubernetes cluster Basic understanding of MongoDB Basic understanding of Kubernetes deployment/service/statefulset Familiar with kubectl operations This is part1, we first introduce the MongoDB Ops Manager components, then install it into your Kubernetes cluster.
MongoDB Ops Manager Kubernetes Overview A simple diagram to illustrate the MongoDB Ops Manager architecture: Kubernetes Deployment：
Mongodb Enterprise Operator : Extend the Kubernetes API by CustomResourceDefinition Kubernetes StatefulSet：
Ops Manager: MongoDB Ops Manager web portal, need a persistent volume Application Database: Ops Manager backend DB, default a 3 instances replicaset User Database: created by Ops Manager, a 3 instance replicaset in this tutorial Kubernetes Services:
Ops Manager Service: Ops Manager web service. Mongo Admin manipulates the projects and the MongoDB deployments by it UserDB Services: exposed services for UserDB. Mongo Client connected to UserDB through these services Install MongoDB Ops Manager in Kubernetes The install process is not hard, just follow the official blog: # Part1: Running MongoDB Ops Manager in Kubernetes Here we provide more details including kubernetes dashboard snapshots and command outputs.
Install MongoDB Enterprise Operator 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 $ kubectl create namespace mongodb namespace/mongodb created $ kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mongodb/mongodb-enterprise-kubernetes/master/crds.yaml Warning: kubectl apply should be used on resource created by either kubectl create --save-config or kubectl apply customresourcedefinition.apiextensions.k8s.io/mongodb.mongodb.com configured Warning: kubectl apply should be used on resource created by either kubectl create --save-config or kubectl apply customresourcedefinition.apiextensions.k8s.io/mongodbusers.mongodb.com configured Warning: kubectl apply should be used on resource created by either kubectl create --save-config or kubectl apply customresourcedefinition.apiextensions.k8s.io/opsmanagers.mongodb.com configured Warning: kubectl apply should be used on resource created by either kubectl create --save-config or kubectl apply clusterrole.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator-mongodb-webhook configured $ kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mongodb/mongodb-enterprise-kubernetes/master/mongodb-enterprise.yaml serviceaccount/mongodb-enterprise-operator created clusterrole.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator-mongodb-certs unchanged clusterrolebinding.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator-mongodb-webhook-binding configured clusterrolebinding.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator-mongodb-certs-binding configured role.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator created rolebinding.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-operator created serviceaccount/mongodb-enterprise-appdb created serviceaccount/mongodb-enterprise-database-pods created serviceaccount/mongodb-enterprise-ops-manager created role.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-appdb created rolebinding.rbac.authorization.k8s.io/mongodb-enterprise-appdb created deployment.apps/mongodb-enterprise-operator created Tips: if your create a different namespace (not mongodb), you need to manually download the two yamls and modify its namespace to your own namespace name.
Here we created a deployment: mongodb-enterprise-operator, view it in the kubernetes dashboard：
Install MongoDB Ops Manager Create Ops Manager Secret 1 2 $ kubectl create secret generic ops-manager-admin-secret --from-literal=Username=&#34;xxx@xxx.com&#34; --from-literal=Password=&#34;Test&#34; --from-literal=FirstName=&#34;Last&#34; --from-literal=LastName=&#34;Last&#34; -n mongodb secret/ops-manager-admin-secret created Remember the username and password, we will login to the portal by them later.
MongoDB Ops Manager Config: ops-manager.yaml 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 apiVersion: mongodb.com/v1 kind: MongoDBOpsManager metadata: name: ops-manager namespace: mongodb spec: # the version of Ops Manager distro to use version: 4.2.4 # the name of the secret containing admin user credentials. adminCredentials: ops-manager-admin-secret externalConnectivity: type: LoadBalancer # the Replica Set backing Ops Manager. # appDB has the SCRAM-SHA authentication mode always enabled applicationDatabase: members: 3 Apply ops-manager.yaml 1 2 $ kubectl apply -f ops-manager.yaml mongodbopsmanager.mongodb.com/ops-manager created After execution, 3 statefulset are created:
A 3 instances statefulset as Ops Manager backend DB A statefulset as Ops Manager web portal A statefuleset as backup daemon Wait until these resource status becomes &ldquo;Running&rdquo;:
1 2 3 $ kubectl get om -n mongodb NAME REPLICAS VERSION STATE (OPSMANAGER) STATE (APPDB) STATE (BACKUP) AGE WARNINGS ops-manager 4.2.4 Running Running Pending 18m View the services: Find the Ops Manager service ops-manager-svc-ext url：x.x.x.x:8080. Open it in the browser: Fill in the ops-manager-admin-secret username and password then login. A configuration page appears, complete it now or later by the Admin UI.
Delete Secret ops-manager-admin-secret 1 2 $ kubectl delete secret ops-manager-admin-secret -n mongodb secret &#34;ops-manager-admin-secret&#34; deleted The official tutorial said that it will never be used. I guess the username/password has been wrote to the backend DB. So just safely delete it.
Finish UI Note: the DB shown above is the backend DB of Ops Manager (aka Application Database), not the user database.
Next we will use MongoDB Kubernetes Operator to create user database:
Create a UserDB ReplicaSet By the way, the official blog Part2 introduces some advanced features for your reference: # Part2: Ops Manager in Kubernetes   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MongoDB Certificate Key File Ownership And Permission</title><url>/en/mongodb-cert-permission/</url><categories><category>MongoDB</category></categories><tags><tag>MongoDB</tag><tag>TLS</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When you setup TLS/SSL for MongoDB Configure mongod and mongos for TLS/SSL , you might encounter the following errors:
1 2 {&#34;t&#34;:{&#34;$date&#34;:&#34;2020-11-30T08:02:19.406+00:00&#34;},&#34;s&#34;:&#34;E&#34;, &#34;c&#34;:&#34;NETWORK&#34;, &#34;id&#34;:23248, &#34;ctx&#34;:&#34;main&#34;,&#34;msg&#34;:&#34;Cannot read certificate file&#34;,&#34;attr&#34;:{&#34;keyFile&#34;:&#34;/etc/ssl/testserver1.pem&#34;,&#34;error&#34;:&#34;error:0200100D:system library:fopen:Permission denied&#34;}} {&#34;t&#34;:{&#34;$date&#34;:&#34;2020-11-30T08:02:19.406+00:00&#34;},&#34;s&#34;:&#34;F&#34;, &#34;c&#34;:&#34;CONTROL&#34;, &#34;id&#34;:20574, &#34;ctx&#34;:&#34;main&#34;,&#34;msg&#34;:&#34;Error during global initialization&#34;,&#34;attr&#34;:{&#34;error&#34;:{&#34;code&#34;:140,&#34;codeName&#34;:&#34;InvalidSSLConfiguration&#34;,&#34;errmsg&#34;:&#34;Can not set up PEM key file.&#34;}}} or
1 {&#34;t&#34;:{&#34;$date&#34;:&#34;2020-11-30T08:01:14.545+00:00&#34;},&#34;s&#34;:&#34;I&#34;, &#34;c&#34;:&#34;ACCESS&#34;, &#34;id&#34;:20254, &#34;ctx&#34;:&#34;main&#34;,&#34;msg&#34;:&#34;Read security file failed&#34;,&#34;attr&#34;:{&#34;error&#34;:{&#34;code&#34;:30,&#34;codeName&#34;:&#34;InvalidPath&#34;,&#34;errmsg&#34;:&#34;permissions on / are too open&#34;}}} So what&rsquo;s the right ownership and permission for the certificate pem file? The answer is: the pem file should have read access but no write access for the user mongodb.
Solution 1 chown mongodb:mongodb [xxx.pem] chmod 400 [xxx.pem] Finally, the pem files look like this:
1 2 -r-------- 1 mongodb mongodb 4.4K Nov 30 18:11 test-ca.pem -r-------- 1 mongodb mongodb 5.4K Nov 30 17:19 test-server1.pem Then everything works fine.
If the pem file cannot be read by user mongodb (e.g. file owner is root with 600 permission), then Permission denied.
If the pem file belongs to mongodb but with more permission, then permissions on / are too open.
Solution 2 chmod 644 [xxx.pem] Unfortunately, the official documentation doesn&rsquo;t provide tips for this, hope these explanation helps.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Mysqlbench Server Status Metrics Meaning</title><url>/en/mysql-server-status-metrics/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>mysql</tag><tag>innodb</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Monitoring mysql server metrics is crucial for a DBA. Typically, we can simply monitor the recent server status summary through mysqlbench. But what&rsquo;s the meaning for these metrics? Some of them are self-explained such as connections and traffic while others are not. For example, what&rsquo;s the difference between Selects per second and Innodb reads per second? How to measure the write performance?
The following figure illustrates the serve status: Server Status Metrics Definition After some research, I found a nice article which explain them well: Selects per second: Com_select / second Innodb reads per second: Innodb_data_reads / second InnoDB writes per second: Innodb_data_writes / second
So what&rsquo;s the definition of Innodb_data_reads and Innodb_data_writes? From mysql reference manual : Innodb_data_reads: The total number of data reads (OS file reads). Innodb_data_writes: The total number of data writes.
Metrics Relationship Selects per second vs Innodb reads per second Look at the following figure and compared with the previous one: The interesting point is that with much higher Selects per second, the Innodb reads per second is almost 0. Why? The reason is that most of the data including table and index are loaded into server memory for the latter case. No file reads is needed for selects because of the cache (most of the time).
Therefore, Selects per second is not equal or proportion to Innodb reads per second. We can verify this idea by looking at another metric Innodb Buffer Usage which reflects the &ldquo;cache&rdquo; size, it is much higher than the case with high Innodb reads per second.
Comparatively, Innodb writes per second is able to reflect the write performance. Because cache mechanism cannot be applied to write operation.
IO/Memory Relationship during DB Startup Let&rsquo;s consider another interesting observation: when we just start the DB, the query latency is relatively high. The latency will be gradually dropped down after running for sometime.
Yes, the magic part is the Innodb Buffer Pool. After running for a long time, the hot data will be loaded into memory and the query latency will be significantly reduced. So we should keep an eye on Innodb Buffer Usage as well. What&rsquo;s innodb buffer usage The above figure is the CPU, IO and Memory Usage Percent curve after a DB startup. Intially IO is high and memory usage is low, one hour later, the IO becomes low while the memory usage (innodb buffer pool usage) raises up to 80%.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MySQL Replication Lag Monitoring Script</title><url>/en/monitor-mysql-replication-lag/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>mysql</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Master-slave replication is widely used in production. Monitoring the replication lag is a common and critical task. Typically, we are able to get the real-time difference between the master and the slave by periodically checking the Seconds_Behind_Master variable.
According to link Seconds_Behind_Master: this field shows an approximation for difference between the current timestamp on the slave against the timestamp on the master for the event currently being processed on the slave.
Get the Seconds_Behind_Master value is easy, just run show slave status on the slave node. However, this command displays too much information so that it&rsquo;s hard to find the key info. If you want to select only Seconds_Behind_Master from mysql system table, it&rsquo;s a nightmare to find a worked solution for your mysql version.
Here the simple script helps:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 #!/bin/bash # Fill the following variables host= # slave node! user= password= while true; do seconds=`mysql -h $host -u $user -p$password -e &#39;show slave status\G&#39; 2&gt;/dev/null |grep Seconds` echo `date &#34;+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M:%S&#34;`$seconds sleep 1 done Sample output of the script:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 ... 2020-11-11 17:17:11 Seconds_Behind_Master: 89 2020-11-11 17:17:12 Seconds_Behind_Master: 89 2020-11-11 17:17:13 Seconds_Behind_Master: 91 2020-11-11 17:17:14 Seconds_Behind_Master: 90 2020-11-11 17:17:15 Seconds_Behind_Master: 91 2020-11-11 17:17:16 Seconds_Behind_Master: 91 ...   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>AspNetCore Accept text/plain as applicatoin/json</title><url>/en/aspnet-core-support-text-plain/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>C#</tag><tag>.NET Core</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  We developed a REST API long time ago and recently found that the released client has a flaw: the HttpRequestMessage is missing content-type application/json. In earlier version we manually deserialize the request json by reading the request body but now we leverage AspNetCore framework to automatically get the request structure from the API parameter. However, the legacy client will not work: HTTP 415 &ldquo;Unsupported Media Type&rdquo; error happens.
Therefore, for backward compatibility, we need to make the server treat all coming requests as application/json even it is a plain text (by default).
The legacy client:
1 msg.Content = new StringContent(JsonConvert.SerializeObject(request)); It should be:
1 msg.Content = new StringContent(JsonConvert.SerializeObject(request), Encoding.UTF8, &#34;application/json&#34;); First, I try to force modify the request content-type to applicatoin/json. However, there is no elegant way to do this.
Then I explore 3 methods to support text/plain content-type:
[Consumes()] annotation above Controller class. (not work) This method doesn&rsquo;t work as consumes annotation only restricts the request content-type, but not regard the request as application/json. In other words, if you specify text/plain in consumes annotation, although the action treat it as a valid type, it will not properly deserialize it to json. 415 error still exists.
Reading request body and parsing as json yourself. https://weblog.west-wind.com/posts/2017/Sep/14/Accepting-Raw-Request-Body-Content-in-ASPNET-Core-API-Controllers?Page=2 This method works, but not what we want: we just deprecated manually deserializing object method and resort to leverage AspNetCore framework to do so.
Add text/plain to SupportedMediaTypes. (RECOMMENDED) Open your aspnetcore Startup.cs, add following snippet to ConfigureServices:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 public void ConfigureServices(IServiceCollection services) { ... services.AddMvc(config =&gt; { foreach (var formatter in config.InputFormatters) { if (formatter.GetType() == typeof(JsonInputFormatter)) { ((JsonInputFormatter) formatter).SupportedMediaTypes.Add(MediaTypeHeaderValue.Parse(&#34;text/plain&#34;)); } } }); ... } Now the server can handle both text/plain and application/json, treating request body as json format.
# Default input formatter in ASP.NET Core 2   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Permanantly Disable ipv6 on Ubuntu</title><url>/en/ubuntu-disable-ipv6/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Ubuntu</tag><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Someone may argue that there is no reason to disable ipv6 on Linux. For me, the reason is that in some ipv6-enabled website, I frequently be classified as a bot who need to solve captcha which is really annoying :-( . Consider the ipv6 address is never change (assigned by service provider), disable ipv6 is the simplest solution.
Let&rsquo;s come to the solution. Just use your favorite editor to add one line in /etc/sysctl.conf:
1 net.ipv6.conf.&lt;your.device.name&gt;.disable_ipv6=1 where &lt;your.device.name&gt; maybe eth0, lo or the device name shown by ifconfig. Then you can use sysctl -p to take effect immediately or reboot to test if ipv6 has been persistently disabled.
The above solution is tested on Ubuntu 20.04 LTS.
Notes:
net.ipv6.conf.all.disable_ipv6 = 1 is unnecessary. net.ipv6.conf.default.disable_ipv6 = 1 doesn&rsquo;t work on my server (maybe default is not well defined?). Personally I don&rsquo;t like the update-grub solution as we cannot re-enable ipv6 without reboot. Reference: # How to disable IPv6 permanently? # How to Disable IPv6 on Ubuntu Linux   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Entity Framework use Expression instead of Func Delegate</title><url>/en/ef-expression/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>Entity Framework Core</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When we use entity framework to manipulate SQL database, we use where to query and include to load related entities (join operation).
Sample database table schema: Employee: Id, Name, Age Salary: Id, BasePay
Typical query scenarios:
Query employee 3&rsquo;s name =&gt; Employee.Where(x =&gt; x.Id == 3) Query employee Jack&rsquo;s age =&gt; Employee.Where(x =&gt; x.Name == &ldquo;Jack&rdquo;) Query employee Jack&rsquo;s basepay =&gt; Employee.Where(x =&gt; x.Name == &ldquo;Jack&rdquo;).Include(x =&gt; x.Salary) &hellip; To make the code clean and focus, the following examples will not include dbContext creation logic, we assume db = DbContext() which contains the Employee table.
For code reuse purpose, we may extract a common method like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 Employee GetEntity(Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt; whereFunc, Func&lt;DbSet&lt;Employee&gt;, IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt;&gt; navigationFunc = null) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = navigationFunc != null ? navigationFunc(db.Employee) : db.Employee; var employee = await query.Where(x =&gt; whereFunc(x)).ToListAsync(); return employee; } The implmentation looks simple and straightfoward: just extract the where and navigation Func&lt;&gt; to a function.
However, the above function has severe perfomance issue: when we execute the function, it retrieves all data from the table and locally applies where filter. Actually, the underlying mechanism is not that simple as entity framework will compile the expression and translated to SQL statements, though it looks like just a syntactic sugar.
Problem Analysis The reason is well explained in the following post: # Don’t use Func delegate on the Entity Framework entities The post said that .Where Linq method has two overloads. One is IQueryable while another is IEnumerable. When we use the above function, IEnumerable will be used so that all data will be retrieved to local.
I agree with the conclusion. However, when I use F12 to go to its definition, they are the same:
1 public static IQueryable&lt;TSource&gt; Where&lt;TSource&gt;(this IQueryable&lt;TSource&gt; source, Expression&lt;Func&lt;TSource, bool&gt;&gt; predicate); Since IQueryable implements IEnumerable, it falls back to IEnumerable. Anyway, we need to pass Expression&lt;Func&gt; to the common function.
Take Employee.Where(x =&gt; x.Name == &quot;Jack&quot;).Select(x =&gt; x.Name) for example. If you print out the translated SQL, you will find that the where expression is missing:
1 2 SELECT `x`.`Name` FROM `XXX`.`Employee` And that&rsquo;s why we have severe performance issue. Next we discuss how to write correct Expresssion&lt;Func&gt; and its usage.
Where Expression The original Func&lt;&gt; function:
1 2 3 4 5 6 Employee GetEntity(Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt; whereFunc) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = db.Employee.Where(x =&gt; whereFunc(x)); var employee = await query.ToListAsync(); return employee; } The Expression&lt;Func&gt; way (just wrap the Func into Expression, pay attention to Where parameter):
1 2 3 4 5 6 Employee GetEntity(Expression&lt;Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt;&gt; whereExpr) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = db.Employee.Where(whereExpr); var employee = await query.ToListAsync(); return employee; } From the caller&rsquo;s view, the usage are the same (the underlying mechanism are totally different):
1 var employee = GetEntity(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;Jack&#34;); If you print out the translated SQL, the where clause comes back:
1 2 3 SELECT `x`.`Name` FROM `XXX`.`Employee` WHERE `x`.`Name` == &#39;Jack&#39; Navigation Expression I spent some time to investigate how to transform Func&lt;DbSet&lt;Employee&gt;, IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt;&gt; to Expression. The hardest part is the return vaule is not fixed: you may .include(x =&gt; x.Salary), .include(x =&gt; x.Assets), both or nothing. Finally I found a way to solve it: use object as return value.
The original version:
1 2 3 4 5 6 Employee GetEntity(Func&lt;DbSet&lt;Employee&gt;, IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt;&gt; navigationFunc) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = navigationFunc(db.Employee).Where(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;Jack&#34;); var employee = await query.ToListAsync(); return employee; } The Expression&lt;Func&gt; way:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 Employee GetEntity(params Expression&lt;Func&lt;Employee&gt;, object&gt;&gt;[] navigationExprs) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = db.Employee; foreach (var navigationExpr in navigationExprs) { query = query.Include(navigationExpr); } query = query.Where(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;Jack&#34;); var employee = await query.ToListAsync(); return employee; } The usage are different:
Original version 1 var employee = GetEntity(x =&gt; x.Include(y =&gt; y.Salary); Expression version 1 var employee = GetEntity(x =&gt; x.Salary); Reference: # Passing multiple Include statements into a Repository Put It All Together 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 Employee GetEntity(Expression&lt;Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt;&gt; whereExpr, params Expression&lt;Func&lt;Employee&gt;, object&gt;&gt;[] navigationExprs) { IQueryable&lt;Employee&gt; query = db.Employee; foreach (var navigationExpr in navigationExprs) { query = query.Include(navigationExpr); } query = query.Where(whereExpr); var employee = await query.ToListAsync(); return employee; } Issues It seems that the Expression as a parameter cannot be wrapped. If you have another function:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 Employee GetEntityFunc(Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt; whereFunc) { Expression&lt;Func&lt;Employee, bool&gt;&gt; whereExpr = x =&gt; whereFunc(x); return GetEntity(whereExpr); } var employee = GetEntityFunc(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;Jack&#34;); Although it&rsquo;s syntactically correct, it doesn&rsquo;t work in entity framework as the where clause is applied locally.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Can't locate CGI.pm in @INC</title><url>/en/perl-cgi/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Ubuntu</tag><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Install an old library lightsquid on Ubuntu 20.04. When visit the cgi, internal server error pops up.
Debug the cgi by directly run it in /var/www/lightsquid:
1 2 3 /var/www/lightsquid$ perl index.cgi Can&#39;t locate CGI.pm in @INC (you may need to install the CGI module) (@INC contains: /etc/perl /usr/local/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/perl/5.30.0 /usr/local/share/perl/5.30.0 /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/perl5/5.30 /usr/share/perl5 /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/perl/5.30 /usr/share/perl/5.30 /usr/local/lib/site_perl /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/perl-base) at index.cgi line 19. BEGIN failed--compilation aborted at index.cgi line 19. Seems that some modules are missing, after several search: https://packages.ubuntu.com/search?suite=trusty&amp;arch=any&amp;mode=filename&amp;searchon=contents&amp;keywords=cgi.pm Combined with the error message:
1 $ apt install libcgi-pm-perl Then it works:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 /var/www/lightsquid$ perl index.cgi ```html &lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC &#34;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN&#34;&gt; &lt;HTML&gt; &lt;HEAD&gt; &lt;META name=&#34;robots&#34; content=&#34;noindex,nofollow&#34;&gt; &lt;META name=&#34;generator&#34; content=&#34;LightSquid - http://lightsquid.sf.net&#34;&gt; &lt;META http-equiv=&#34;Content-Type&#34; content=&#34;text/html; charset=US-ASCII&#34;&gt; &lt;META HTTP-EQUIV=&#34;REFRESH&#34; CONTENT=&#34;600&#34;&gt; ...   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Get SQL Query in Entity Framework Core</title><url>/en/ef-core-get-sql-query/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>Entity Framework Core</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  View the generated SQL query by entity framework is important. The translated SQL query may not what you expected. Sometimes it leads to significant performance issue.
Print the generated query for an IQueryable&lt;T&gt; in EF Core is different with EF. Finally I found a worked solution which is listed below.
The following code is tested in MySql.Data.EntityFrameworkCore 8.0.16. Just put the following class into your project:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 public static class QueryableExtensions { private static readonly TypeInfo QueryCompilerTypeInfo = typeof(QueryCompiler).GetTypeInfo(); private static readonly FieldInfo QueryCompilerField = typeof(EntityQueryProvider).GetTypeInfo().DeclaredFields.First(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;_queryCompiler&#34;); private static readonly FieldInfo QueryModelGeneratorField = typeof(QueryCompiler).GetTypeInfo().DeclaredFields.First(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;_queryModelGenerator&#34;); private static readonly FieldInfo DataBaseField = QueryCompilerTypeInfo.DeclaredFields.Single(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;_database&#34;); private static readonly PropertyInfo DatabaseDependenciesField = typeof(Database).GetTypeInfo().DeclaredProperties.Single(x =&gt; x.Name == &#34;Dependencies&#34;); public static string ToSql&lt;TEntity&gt;(this IQueryable&lt;TEntity&gt; query) { var queryCompiler = (QueryCompiler)QueryCompilerField.GetValue(query.Provider); var queryModelGenerator = (QueryModelGenerator)QueryModelGeneratorField.GetValue(queryCompiler); var queryModel = queryModelGenerator.ParseQuery(query.Expression); var database = DataBaseField.GetValue(queryCompiler); var databaseDependencies = (DatabaseDependencies)DatabaseDependenciesField.GetValue(database); var queryCompilationContext = databaseDependencies.QueryCompilationContextFactory.Create(false); var modelVisitor = (RelationalQueryModelVisitor)queryCompilationContext.CreateQueryModelVisitor(); modelVisitor.CreateQueryExecutor&lt;TEntity&gt;(queryModel); var sql = modelVisitor.Queries.First().ToString(); return sql; } } The usage is straightforward, just append a .ToSql() after your IQueryable&lt;T&gt;:
1 2 3 IQueryable&lt;PriceTable&gt; query = ...; string generatedQuery = query.ToSql(); Console.WriteLine(generatedQuery); Then you can get the query to check if it&rsquo;s expected:
1 2 3 4 SELECT `x`.`Id`, `x`.`Price` FROM `XXX`.`PriceTable` WHERE `x`.`Id` = &#39;xxx&#39; ORDER BY `x`.`CreateTime` DESC Tips: the approach is easy to use with little dependency. I&rsquo;m not an EF expert, but consider the &ldquo;crazy&rdquo; reflection and type casting, DO NOT use it in production environment, ONLY for debug purpose.
Reference: # Get SQL code from an Entity Framework Core IQueryable   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>MountVolume.SetUp failed for volume secret not found Issue</title><url>/en/kubernetes-recover-secret/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags><tag>Kubernetes</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Today I found that some pods in kubernetes cluster are failed, the status is Waiting: ContainerCreating. The pod events:
1 2 3 4 MountVolume.SetUp failed for volume &#34;xxxxx&#34; : secret &#34;xxxxx&#34; not found kubelet aks-agentpool-xxx-vmss000001 Unable to attach or mount volumes: unmounted volumes=[xxxxx], unattached volumes=[xxxxx]: timed out waiting for the condition I remember that about one week ago I delete some secretes in this cluster. Therefore, the problem becomes how to recover the deleted secret &ldquo;xxxxx&rdquo;?
Refer the following documents: # To create additional API tokens According to # Service Account Admission Controller :
1 if the pod does not have a ServiceAccount set, it sets the ServiceAccount to default. Since the missing secret format is &ldquo;default-token-xxxxx&rdquo;, the ServiceAccount must be default.
Then we create a service.json file:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 { &#34;kind&#34;: &#34;Secret&#34;, &#34;apiVersion&#34;: &#34;v1&#34;, &#34;metadata&#34;: { &#34;name&#34;: &#34;default-token-xxxxx&#34;, &#34;annotations&#34;: { &#34;kubernetes.io/service-account.name&#34;: &#34;default&#34; } }, &#34;type&#34;: &#34;kubernetes.io/service-account-token&#34; } There are two fields in metadata need to be modified:
name: change to your missing secret name which is included in the warning message kubernetes.io/service-account.name: default Execute the following command:
1 kubectl create -f ./secret.json Check if the secret is there:
1 kubectl get secrets Done. Waiting for the pod to start!
If you deleted the default kubernetes secret by mistake, hope this artible helps. :-)
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Clean .com.google.Chrome.* in /tmp</title><url>/en/cleanup-tmp/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Ubuntu</tag><tag>Linux</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently, I found there were huge amount of files named .com.google.Chrome.* be created in my /tmp folder. Obviously the culprit is Chrome. However, after some research no solution is found to prevent Chrome creating these garbage.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 /tmp$ du -csh .com.google.Chrome.* 8.0K .com.google.Chrome.00OKwD 104K .com.google.Chrome.013jYf 172K .com.google.Chrome.015x5t ... 48K .com.google.Chrome.Zytrhf 16K .com.google.Chrome.zz233G 36K .com.google.Chrome.ZzrsZY 163M total /tmp$ find /tmp -name &#34;.com.google.Chrome*&#34; -ls| wc -l 3468 Update 2020/12/12 I found there are lots of .com.google.Chrome.* files in /tmp/snap.chromium/tmp :-( . Look at the ncdu results:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 --- /tmp/snap.chromium/tmp ------------------------------------------------------------------------- /.. 4.1 MiB [##########] /.com.google.Chrome.xTBobr 4.1 MiB [######### ] /.com.google.Chrome.0hcsFR 4.0 MiB [######### ] /.com.google.Chrome.YdhzL5 4.0 MiB [######### ] /.com.google.Chrome.nJ5W3A 4.0 MiB [######### ] /.com.google.Chrome.unS6es ... Total disk usage: 6.8 GiB Apparent size: 12.1 GiB Items: 482530 Now the cleanup script has been updated.
The listed files were created within two days! Looks that it&rsquo;s harmless, huh? Definitely NOT! By default, Linux will cleanup the /tmp at boot. If your system is rarely reboot:
These files might make your disk full Huge amount of files in /tmp will block your system boot Refer to this post: # A start job is running for Create Volatile Files and Directories Therefore, I have to make a cron job to automatically cleanup /tmp periodically. The cleanup script cleanuptmp.sh:
1 2 3 #!/bin/bash find /tmp -name &#34;.com.google.Chrome*&#34; -mtime +0.5 -exec rm -r {} \; find /tmp/snap.chromium/tmp -name &#34;.com.google.Chrome*&#34; -mtime +0.5 -exec rm -r {} \; The script will delete all .com.google.Chrome* directories with last modify time 12 hours before.
Since the /tmp/snap.chromium/tmp folder has restricted deletion flag t:
1 2 3 $ sudo ls -al /tmp/snap.chromium/ ... drwxrwxrwt 887 root root 1114112 Dec 12 11:40 tmp We need to add a cron job entry to root user by sudo crontab -e:
1 15 10,22 * * * /home/xxx/cleanuptmp.sh It will cleanup the /tmp at 10:15 and 22:15 everyday.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>A start job is running for Create Volatile Files and Directories</title><url>/en/tmp-folder-explosion/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Yesterday, when I login to my VM I found that the disk is full. Even a tab command completion cannot be done. I immediately delete some unused files and the system works. However, when I reboot the system, it stucked at A start job is running for Create Volatile Files and Directories...:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 ... [ OK ] Started File System Check on /dev/disk/cloud/azure_resource-part1. [ OK ] Started File System Check Daemon to report status. [ OK ] Started File System Check on /dev/d…5d996-7436-4ec8-b5d6-0d7b6100aeb5. Mounting /data... [ OK ] Mounted /data. [ OK ] Reached target Local File Systems. Starting AppArmor initialization... Starting ebtables ruleset management... Starting Tell Plymouth To Write Out Runtime Data... Starting Set console font and keymap... [ OK ] Started Set console font and keymap. [ OK ] Started Tell Plymouth To Write Out Runtime Data. [ OK ] Started ebtables ruleset management. [ OK ] Started Flush Journal to Persistent Storage. Starting Create Volatile Files and Directories... [ OK ] Started AppArmor initialization. [ **] A start job is running for Create V… Directories (13min 46s / no limit) I searched and found a similar discussion: # Boot stuck at “A start job is running for Create Volatile Files and Directories” I used an Azure VM with an extra disk. However, it always failed to boot into recovery mode. Then I removed the extra disk from the portal and the system mount the disk failed and went to the single user mode so that I can execute commands:
1 2 root@DEAN:/tmp# ls /tmp bash: /bin/ls: Argument list too long Then occasionally I found that there are HUGE amount of something like this .com.google.Chrome.nFbq9T:
1 2 root@DEAN:/tmp# ls .com.google.Chrome.* bash: /bin/ls: Argument list too long Since I have a web crawler in the system, it seems that there are something wrong but it doesn&rsquo;t matter. I also cannot execute rm -f .com.google.Chrome.* due to Argument list too long. First list them:
1 2 3 4 5 root@DEAN:/home# find /tmp -type f -iname &#34;.com.google.Chrome*&#34; -ls | head find: ‘/tmp/.com.google.Chrome.nFbq9T’: No such file or directory find: ‘/tmp/.com.google.Chrome.WKCRCU’: No such file or directory find: ‘/tmp/.com.google.Chrome.62cCbn’: No such file or directory find: ‘/tmp/.com.google.Chrome.RR1E3L’: No such file or directory The command cannot quickly return, but I got above error messages. Seems that the OS is cleaning the /tmp folder but I cannot verify this. Through df -lh I found that the available disk space is increasing. To speed up the process, execute:
1 root@DEAN:/home# find /tmp -iname &#34;.com.google.Chrome*&#34; -delete &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1 After nearly an hour it finished:
1 2 3 4 5 6 ~$ df -lh Filesystem Size Used Avail Use% Mounted on udev 1.9G 0 1.9G 0% /dev tmpfs 393M 1.1M 392M 1% /run /dev/sda1 29G 13G 16G 46% / ... It looks like there were 16G .com.google.Chrome. files&hellip; And because of this, the system is stuck at boot. Unfortunately, the root cause of this problem is not found yet.
By the way, directly move /tmp to /tmp.bak and recreate /tmp might be more efficient as suggested in the above post&hellip;
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>SSH Server Refused Our Key</title><url>/en/server-refused-our-key/</url><categories><category>Linux</category></categories><tags><tag>Linux</tag><tag>Ubuntu</tag><tag>SSH</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  After I changed the HOME folder to another place, I copied the ssh config folder from old HOME to the new place. Supposedly it should directly work, right? However, when I login the server with my private key, the server said: &ldquo;Server Refused Our Key&rdquo;&hellip;
I spent some time to figure out the problem: new HOME folder access mode issue, it SHOULD NOT have write access for group.
Firstly, I think the server sshd uses wrong config: OLDHOME/.ssh/. However, NEWHOME/.ssh/ contains same files, either one should work.
Check the server error log:
1 2 3 ~$: tail /var/log/auth.log ... Mar 28 17:08:43 DEAN sshd[40801]: Authentication refused: bad ownership or modes for directory NEWHOME The message clearly points out the issue, then I google this message and found that, by default, ssh StrictModes option is on, and it requires the HOME folder not have group write access. Besides, the .ssh/ foler should be 700, the authorized_keys file should be 600:
1 2 3 chmod g-w /home/user/ chmod 700 /home/user/.ssh/ chmod 600 /home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys Or you can switch StrictModes off, but highly not recommended to do so. Because the StrictModes prevents other users modify your .ssh/ to illegally login.
Finally the login success message appears:
1 2 3 Using username &#34;X&#34;. Authenticating with public key &#34;rsa-key&#34; Welcome to Ubuntu 18.04.3 LTS Reference # SSH Authentication Refused: Bad Ownership or Modes for Directory   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Resolve a Collection of Customized Class in UnityConfig</title><url>/en/resolve-class-collection-in-unity-config/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>C#</tag><tag>Dependency Injection</tag><tag>Software Engineering</tag><tag>Unity</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Unity supports three ways of registering types:
Instance registration Type registration Factory registration Typically, Instance registration and Type registration resolve dependencies through ResolvedParameter&lt;T&gt;, while Factory registration resolve dependencies by a factory delegate. In practice, when you want to resolve a List&lt;T&gt; or Dictionary&lt;T1, T2&gt;, Factory registration is what you want. Let&rsquo;s go through how to resolve a collection of customized classes.
Animal Example Start with example, assume we have an IAnimal interface which has two implementations. There is a Zoo class which accept List&lt;IAnimal&gt; as the parameter:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 public interface IAnimal { void Run(); } public class Tiger : IAnimal { public void Run() { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Tiger runs away&#34;); } } public class Deer : IAnimal { public void Run() { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Deer runs away&#34;); } } public class Zoo { private readonly List&lt;IAnimal&gt; _animals; public Zoo(List&lt;IAnimal&gt; animals) { _animals = animals; } public void Play() { foreach (var animal in _animals) { animal.Run(); } } } Here comes the quesiton, how to register List&lt;IAnimal&gt;? A straightforward approach might look like this (WRONG):
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 container.RegisterType&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;( &#34;AnimalList&#34;, new InjectionConstructor( new List&lt;IAnimal&gt; { new ResolvedParameter&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Tiger&#34;), new ResolvedParameter&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Deer&#34;) }) ); Compile error:
1 Argument 1: cannot convert from &#39;Unity.Injection.ResolvedParameter&lt;ConsoleApp1.IAnimal&gt;&#39; to &#39;ConsoleApp1.IAnimal&#39; Because in List&lt;IAnimal&gt;, the type is IAnimal, while ResolvedParameter&lt;IAnimal&gt; is a type of Unity.Injection.ResolvedParameter&lt;IAnimal&gt;, there is a type mismatching. Therefore, we cannot dynamically resolve a collection of customized class by InjectionConstructor().
Directly Resolve Collection Resolving collections of Objects of a Particular Type Unity supports creating multiple registration of the same type by adding a name to the registration.
When you want to obtain a list of all the registered objects of a specific type, IPrinter in this case, you can use the array T[] or IEnumerable&lt;T&gt; of that type. The difference between array and enumerable resolution is that array only returns named (nondefault name) registrations where enumerable always returns all, named and unnamed registrations.
We can modify the parameter of Zoo from List&lt;IAnimal&gt; to IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; to solve the problem:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 public class Zoo { private readonly IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; _animals; public Zoo(IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; animals) { _animals = animals; } public void Play() { foreach (var animal in _animals) { animal.Run(); } } } Then register Zoo like this:
1 2 3 4 container.RegisterType&lt;Zoo, Zoo&gt;(&#34;Zoo&#34;, new InjectionConstructor( new ResolvedParameter&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;() )); However, such directly resolving collection approach has a drawback: it cannot resolve a subset of registered types, it always resolves all registered types. For instance, if you register Tiger and Deer as IAnimal but want to resolve a List&lt;IAnimal&gt; which only contains Tiger, it cannot be done.
RegisterFactory is what you need.
Resolve Collection by RegisterFactory RegisterFactory register a function delegate to resolve a collection of IAnimal:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 container.RegisterFactory&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;( &#34;AnimalList&#34;, m =&gt; new List&lt;IAnimal&gt; { m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Tiger&#34;), // m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Deer&#34;), } ); RegisterFactory accepts Func&lt;IUnityContainer, object&gt; as parameter and resolves an IAnimal instance during initialization. It&rsquo;s able to resolve two IAnimal instances by simply uncommenting m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&quot;Deer&quot;).
In summary, RegisterFactory is a more flexible way than RegisterType to resolve dependencies. Just a little bit complex.
Full Code 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 using System; using System.Collections.Generic; using Unity; using Unity.Injection; namespace ConsoleApp1 { public interface IAnimal { void Run(); } public class Tiger : IAnimal { public void Run() { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Tiger runs away&#34;); } } public class Deer : IAnimal { public void Run() { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Deer runs away&#34;); } } public class Zoo { private readonly IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; _animals; public Zoo(IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; animals) { _animals = animals; } public void Play() { foreach (var animal in _animals) { animal.Run(); } } } public class SimpleZoo { private readonly IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; _animals; public SimpleZoo(IEnumerable&lt;IAnimal&gt; animals) { _animals = animals; } public void Play() { foreach (var animal in _animals) { animal.Run(); } } } class Program { static void Main(string[] args) { // Registration var container = new UnityContainer(); container.RegisterType&lt;IAnimal, Deer&gt;(&#34;Deer&#34;, new InjectionConstructor()); container.RegisterType&lt;IAnimal, Tiger&gt;(&#34;Tiger&#34;, new InjectionConstructor()); container.RegisterFactory&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;( &#34;AnimalList&#34;, m =&gt; new List&lt;IAnimal&gt; { m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Tiger&#34;) } ); container.RegisterType&lt;Zoo, Zoo&gt;(&#34;Zoo&#34;, new InjectionConstructor( new ResolvedParameter&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;() )); container.RegisterType&lt;SimpleZoo, SimpleZoo&gt;(&#34;SimpleZoo&#34;, new InjectionConstructor( new ResolvedParameter&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;(&#34;AnimalList&#34;) )); // Resolve the instances Console.WriteLine(&#34;Zoo: &#34;); var zoo = container.Resolve&lt;Zoo&gt;(&#34;Zoo&#34;); zoo.Play(); Console.WriteLine(); Console.WriteLine(&#34;SimpleZoo: &#34;); var simpleZoo = container.Resolve&lt;SimpleZoo&gt;(&#34;SimpleZoo&#34;); simpleZoo.Play(); Console.ReadKey(); } } } Reference C# Unity register a list of registered types and resolve by adding N instances Registering Types and Object Instances Dependency Injection with Unity Resolving collections of Objects of a Particular Type   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>VS2017 .NET Core Projects Load Failed</title><url>/en/vs-net-core-load-failed/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>.NET Core</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html">  If you use Visual Studio 2017 and create an .NET Core projects the first time, the following errors might appear:
The current .NET SDK does not support targeting .NET Standard 2.0. Either target .NET Standard 1.6 or lower, or use a version of the .NET SDK that supports .NET Standard 2.0.	XXXProject	C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio\2017\Enterprise\MSBuild\Sdks\Microsoft.NET.Sdk\build\Microsoft.NET.TargetFrameworkInference.targets
Another related issue is .NET Core project load failed. Both errors point out that the corresponding .NET SDK is missing.
If you follow the instructions to install .NET Core SDK with a random version from here: https://aka.ms/dotnet-download . Most likely that the issue cannot be resolved.
Check Installed SDKs Use dotnet --info:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 $ dotnet --info .NET Core SDK (reflecting any global.json): Version: 2.2.401 Commit: 729b316c13 Runtime Environment: OS Name: Windows OS Version: 10.0.14393 OS Platform: Windows RID: win10-x64 Base Path: C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk\2.2.401\ Host (useful for support): Version: 2.2.8 Commit: b9aa1abc51 .NET Core SDKs installed: 2.1.202 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk] 2.1.511 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk] 2.2.207 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk] 2.2.300 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk] 2.2.401 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\sdk] .NET Core runtimes installed: Microsoft.AspNetCore.All 2.1.15 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.All] Microsoft.AspNetCore.All 2.2.5 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.All] Microsoft.AspNetCore.All 2.2.6 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.All] Microsoft.AspNetCore.All 2.2.8 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.All] Microsoft.AspNetCore.App 2.1.15 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.App] Microsoft.AspNetCore.App 2.2.5 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.App] Microsoft.AspNetCore.App 2.2.6 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.App] Microsoft.AspNetCore.App 2.2.8 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.AspNetCore.App] Microsoft.NETCore.App 2.0.9 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.NETCore.App] Microsoft.NETCore.App 2.1.15 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.NETCore.App] Microsoft.NETCore.App 2.2.5 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.NETCore.App] Microsoft.NETCore.App 2.2.6 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.NETCore.App] Microsoft.NETCore.App 2.2.8 [C:\Program Files\dotnet\shared\Microsoft.NETCore.App] To install additional .NET Core runtimes or SDKs: https://aka.ms/dotnet-download It seems that there are many existing .NET Core 2.2.x SDKs. Why it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work?
Solution Short Answer Go to the following link to install SDK: # Download .NET SDKs for Visual Studio Restart Visual Studio and rebuild the project
Long Answer # The current .NET SDK does not support targeting .NET Standard 2.0 error in Visual Studio 2017 update 15.3 The above stackoverflow url has an answer which suggests to install .NET SDK from the following link (resolve the issue but don&amp;rsquo;t know why): # Download .NET SDKs for Visual Studio Compare the SDK download url with the offical .NET Core SDK site: # Download .NET Core 2.2 , you will find that they are the same:
1 https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download/dotnet-core/thank-you/sdk-2.2.110-windows-x64-installer Looks magic, right? So I guess the reason is that Visual Studio 2017 is only compatible with a specific version of .NET Core SDK, regardless which version your project actually used. Fortunately the first site provides a compatible SDK version list for different VS versions, install from that site would resolve the problem.
  </content></entry><entry><title>Memory Related Metrics in C#</title><url>/en/memory-metrics/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>.NET Core</tag><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Recently we use Grafana to monitor ASP.NET Core apps. We have an interesting observation that sometimes the &ldquo;allocated memory&rdquo; is larger than &ldquo;working set&rdquo;. After investigation, we found the root cause is that the app uses native dlls which operates on unmanaged memory which is not managed by GC. Therefore, how to correctly collect memory related metrics in C#?
We will explain these related concepts in this post.
Basic Concepts Managed vs Unmanaged Code # What is &ldquo;managed code&rdquo;? To put it very simply, managed code is just that: code whose execution is managed by a runtime.
# Interoperating with unmanaged code Code that executes under the control of the runtime is called managed code. Conversely, code that runs outside the runtime is called unmanaged code. COM components, ActiveX interfaces, and Windows API functions are examples of unmanaged code.
Unsafe Code # Unsafe code and pointers In the common language runtime (CLR), unsafe code is referred to as unverifiable code.
Please note that unmanaged != unsafe. According to their definitions, unsafe code still runs on top of CLR, while unmanaged code is not managed by CLR. In short, unmanaged code must be unsafe, but unsafe code is still &ldquo;under manage&rdquo;.
GC.GetTotalMemory # What is private bytes, virtual bytes, working set? # GC.GetTotalMemory(Boolean) Method Retrieves the number of bytes currently thought to be allocated. A parameter indicates whether this method can wait a short interval before returning, to allow the system to collect garbage and finalize objects.
WorkingSet # Process.MaxWorkingSet Property The working set of a process is the set of memory pages currently visible to the process in physical RAM memory. These pages are resident and available for an application to use without triggering a page fault.
Private Bytes # Process.PrivateMemorySize64 Property The value returned by this property represents the current size of memory used by the process, in bytes, that cannot be shared with other processes.
Create Unmanaged Objects in C# If we want to test whether a memory API collects unmanaged memory as well, we need to create unmanaged object first. Basically, you can write a native c/c++ dll to directly work with memory. Fortunately, we have an easier way to create unmanaged objects: Marshal Class.
# Marshal Class Provides a collection of methods for allocating unmanaged memory, copying unmanaged memory blocks, and converting managed to unmanaged types, as well as other miscellaneous methods used when interacting with unmanaged code.
We will use Marshal.AllocHGlobal Method to request unmanaged memory.
# Marshal.AllocHGlobal Method 1 2 // Claim 10MB memory from unmanaged memory of the process IntPtr unmanagedMem = Marshal.AllocHGlobal(10 * 1024 * 1024); Demo App 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 using System; using System.Diagnostics; using System.Runtime.InteropServices; using System.Threading; namespace ConsoleApp1 { class Program { static void Main(string[] args) { Console.WriteLine(&#34;Initial:&#34;); GetMetrics(); var managedMem = new string(&#39;x&#39;, 10 * 1024 * 1024); Thread.Sleep(2000); Console.WriteLine(&#34;Request 10MB memory in managed heap&#34;); GetMetrics(); Thread.Sleep(2000); IntPtr unmanagedMem = Marshal.AllocHGlobal(10 * 1024 * 1024); // Intended not to call Marshal.FreeHGlobal(unmanagedMem); Console.WriteLine(&#34;Request 10MB unmanaged memory&#34;); GetMetrics(); } static void GetMetrics() { var process = Process.GetCurrentProcess(); var workingSet = process.WorkingSet64 / 1024 / 1024; var gcTotalMemory = GC.GetTotalMemory(true) / 1024 / 1024; var privateBytes = process.PrivateMemorySize64 / 1024 / 1024; Console.WriteLine($&#34;WorkingSet: {workingSet}MB GCTotalMemory: {gcTotalMemory}MB PrivateBytes: {privateBytes}MB&#34;); Console.WriteLine(); } } } Results:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Initial: WorkingSet: 14MB GCTotalMemory: 0MB PrivateBytes: 8MB Request 10MB memory in managed heap WorkingSet: 34MB GCTotalMemory: 20MB PrivateBytes: 28MB Request 10MB unmanaged memory WorkingSet: 34MB GCTotalMemory: 20MB PrivateBytes: 38MB Easy to find that the statistics is align with VS Diagnostic Tools.
Observations PrivateBytes includes unmanaged memory WorkingSet doesn&rsquo;t include unmanaged memory WorkingSet != GCTotalMemory + PrivateBytes, which means they are not directly related   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>TypeError Class advice impossible in Python3</title><url>/en/class-advice-impossible/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>pytorch</tag><tag>cuda</tag><tag>python</tag><tag>apex</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  The error looks like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 $ python test.py Traceback (most recent call last): File &#34;test.py&#34;, line 3, in &lt;module&gt; ... File &#34;miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/apex/__init__.py&#34;, line 18, in &lt;module&gt; from apex.interfaces import (ApexImplementation, File &#34;miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/apex/interfaces.py&#34;, line 10, in &lt;module&gt; class ApexImplementation(object): File &#34;miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/apex/interfaces.py&#34;, line 14, in ApexImplementation implements(IApex) File &#34;miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/zope/interface/declarations.py&#34;, line 483, in implements raise TypeError(_ADVICE_ERROR % &#39;implementer&#39;) TypeError: Class advice impossible in Python3. Use the @implementer class decorator instead. Refer to this issue: https://github.com/NVIDIA/apex/issues/116 Install the latest version resolved the issue:
1 2 3 4 5 pip uninstall apex git clone https://www.github.com/nvidia/apex cd apex python setup.py install   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Jupyter dlopen cannot load any more object with static TLS</title><url>/en/jupyter-dlopen/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>pytorch</tag><tag>cuda</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  A weird problem that execute &ldquo;import torch&rdquo; in bash works but when you run it in Jupyter notebook:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 ImportError Traceback (most recent call last) &lt;ipython-input-4-8ba1970b60ce&gt; in &lt;module&gt; 6 import random 7 ----&gt; 8 import torch 9 import torch.nn as nn 10 ~/miniconda3/envs/tf/lib/python3.6/site-packages/torch/__init__.py in &lt;module&gt; 79 del _dl_flags 80 ---&gt; 81 from torch._C import * 82 83 __all__ += [name for name in dir(_C) ImportError: dlopen: cannot load any more object with static TLS Seems that it&rsquo;s a compatibility issue. Even though there are a large volume of discussions but none of them works. Ironically, I accidently fixed the issue by resolving another: # RuntimeError cuDNN error CUDNN_STATUS_EXECUTION_FAILED Solution Potential Solution I marked these solutions as &ldquo;potential&rdquo; because I didn&rsquo;t make a strict control variable experiment. I tried all of them and it worked. :-)
My environment:
1 2 3 4 5 1. Ubuntu 14.04 LTS 2. Python 3.6.9 3. PyTorch 1.3.0 4. cuda 10.1 (Tesla K40m) The order of following solutions matters.
Upgrade/Downgrade Cuda To the best of my understanding, this operation does the trick (but didn&rsquo;t verified). Downgrade cuda from 10.x to 9.0.
Upgrade/Downgrade PyTorch 1 conda install pytorch==1.2.0 torchvision==0.4.0 cudatoolkit=10.0 -c pytorch If you use conda, you can refer to this page to find a working combination: INSTALLING PREVIOUS VERSIONS OF PYTORCH Upgrade Jupyter 1 $ conda update jupyter Upgrade Ubuntu I do-release-upgrade from 14.04 to 16.04 and finally 18.04 LTS. Ubuntu Upgrades   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>RuntimeError cuDNN error CUDNN_STATUS_EXECUTION_FAILED Solution</title><url>/en/cudnn-status-execution-failed/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>pytorch</tag><tag>cuda</tag><tag>python</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  1 RuntimeError: cuDNN error: CUDNN_STATUS_EXECUTION_FAILED When you encountered the above issue and Google it, you will find lots of discussions. Unfortunately, very rare of them are useful and work.
Actually, the root cause is pytorch/cuda/python compatibility issue.
Solution The solution is straightforward. Simply downgrade pytorch and install a different version of cuda or python would be fine.
My environment:
Ubuntu 18.04 LTS Python 3.6.9 PyTorch 1.3.0 cuda 10.1 This command resolved my issue (PyTorch version really matters! from 1.3.0 to 1.2.0):
1 conda install pytorch==1.2.0 torchvision==0.4.0 cudatoolkit=10.0 -c pytorch If you use conda, you can refer to this page to find a working combination (downgrade might be better than upgrade&hellip;): INSTALLING PREVIOUS VERSIONS OF PYTORCH Detailed Error Message 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 $ python seq2seq.py Traceback (most recent call last): File &#34;seq2seq.py&#34;, line 311, in &lt;module&gt; trainIters(encoder, attndecoder, 75000, print_every=5000) File &#34;seq2seq.py&#34;, line 289, in trainIters decoder, encoder_optimizer, decoder_optimizer, criterion) File &#34;seq2seq.py&#34;, line 233, in train encoder_output, encoder_hidden = encoder(input_tensor[ei], encoder_hidden) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/module.py&#34;, line 541, in __call__ result = self.forward(*input, **kwargs) File &#34;seq2seq.py&#34;, line 154, in forward output, hidden = self.gru(output, hidden) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/module.py&#34;, line 541, in __call__ result = self.forward(*input, **kwargs) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/rnn.py&#34;, line 729, in forward return self.forward_tensor(input, hx) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/rnn.py&#34;, line 721, in forward_tensor output, hidden = self.forward_impl(input, hx, batch_sizes, max_batch_size, sorted_indices) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/rnn.py&#34;, line 699, in forward_impl result = self.run_impl(input, hx, batch_sizes) File &#34;/home/user/miniconda3/envs/torch/lib/python3.7/site-packages/torch/nn/modules/rnn.py&#34;, line 680, in run_impl self.dropout, self.training, self.bidirectional, self.batch_first) RuntimeError: cuDNN error: CUDNN_STATUS_EXECUTION_FAILED DO NOT Upgrade Ubuntu Someone said newer Ubuntu fixed some low-level libraries. I upgraded Ubuntu from 14.04 to 16.04 and then to 18.04, nothing happened.
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>invalid object doesn't have additional properties error</title><url>/en/k8s-invalid-object/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags><tag>Kubernetes</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When I use kubectl to deploy a service:
1 $ kubectl --kubeconfig=C:\Users\xxx\.kube\config apply -f deploy.yaml --namespace=xxx a SchemeError was raised:
1 EXEC(0,0): Error : SchemaError(io.k8s.api.apps.v1beta1.RollingUpdateStatefulSetStrategy): invalid object doesn&#39;t have additional properties Seems that the issue is caused by kubectl version mismatch: Install and Set Up kubectl 1 You must use a kubectl version that is within one minor version difference of your cluster. For example, a v1.2 client should work with v1.1, v1.2, and v1.3 master. Using the latest version of kubectl helps avoid unforeseen issues. Follow these steps to resolve the issue:
Check deploy.yaml Make sure deploy.yaml is correct and the docker image can be run locally.
Check kubeconfig Double check the right kubeconfig is specified and connect to the right cluster:
1 2 3 &gt; kubectl.exe version Client Version: version.Info{Major:&#34;1&#34;, Minor:&#34;17&#34;, GitVersion:&#34;v1.17.0&#34;, GitCommit:&#34;70132b0f130acc0bed193d9ba59dd186f0e634cf&#34;, GitTreeState:&#34;clean&#34;, BuildDate:&#34;2019-12-07T21:20:10Z&#34;, GoVersion:&#34;go1.13.4&#34;, Compiler:&#34;gc&#34;, Platform:&#34;windows/amd64&#34;} Unable to connect to the server: dial tcp: lookup k8s-cluster.io: no such host Connect Right Server The server is displayed after &ldquo;dial tcp:&rdquo;: &ldquo;k8s-cluster.io&rdquo;. If &ldquo;Unable to connect to the server&rdquo; is displayed, you might use a wrong kubeconfig file. Correct the config by --kubeconfig option.
Check kubectl Version &amp; Path One may install multiple kubectl on the same machine. If you found client version is not matched, consider specifying the right one. You can also view the current kubectl by (For Linux, command which):
1 2 3 4 &gt; Get-Command kubectl.exe CommandType Name Version Source ----------- ---- ------- ------ Application kubectl.exe 0.0.0.0 C:\Program Files\Docker\Docker\Resources\bin\kubectl.exe I install the Docker Desktop on Windows and the default kubectl location is C:\Program Files\Docker\Docker\Resources\bin\. So, download the matched kubectl from Install and Set Up kubectl and put it in this folder solved the problem.
Reference Kubectl create “invalid object”   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>ReSharper Marked Classes in Red Color Issue</title><url>/en/resharper-red-color/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>C#</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  I have encountered an issue: solution can be successfully built and run, but lots of classes in the VisualStudio are marked as red color by ReSharper. Clean and rebuild the solution doesn&rsquo;t work. Something like this: Everything compiles, but Resharper marks everything in red? Clean ReSharper Cache The following instructions are tested under Resharper Ultimate 2019.2:
1 Visual Studio &gt; ReSharper &gt; General &gt; Options &gt; General &gt; Clear Caches &ldquo;Restart&rdquo; ReSharper:
1 Visual Studio &gt; Tools &gt; Options &gt; ReSharper Ultimate &gt; Suspend Now/Resume Now If this operation doesn&rsquo;t resolve the issue, continue reading&hellip;
VisualStudio Clean Build VisualStudio&rsquo;s solution clean doesn&rsquo;t remove bin/ and obj/, which might lead to some weird build or runtime errors. In our case, it seems that ReSharper still uses old assembly. Specifically, when you change a project from dotnet framework to dotnetstandard or dotnetcore, the issue frequently happens. Therefore, a REALLY CLEAN BUILD should be performed. ( How to clean Visual Studio bin and obj folders )
To make a clean build, commit all changes and execute:
1 $ git clean -fdx Warning! This command is DANGEROUS, it will delete all untracked files. (bin/, obj/, etc.)
What these options mean: ( https://git-scm.com/docs/git-clean )
-d Normally, when no is specified, git clean will not recurse into untracked directories to avoid removing too much. Specify -d to have it recurse into such directories as well. If any paths are specified, -d is irrelevant; all untracked files matching the specified paths (with exceptions for nested git directories mentioned under &ndash;force) will be removed.
-f &ndash;force If the Git configuration variable clean.requireForce is not set to false, git clean will refuse to delete files or directories unless given -f or -i. Git will refuse to modify untracked nested git repositories (directories with a .git subdirectory) unless a second -f is given.
-x Don’t use the standard ignore rules (see gitignore[5] ), but still use the ignore rules given with -e options from the command line. This allows removing all untracked files, including build products. This can be used (possibly in conjunction with git restore or git reset) to create a pristine working directory to test a clean build.
After the git clean, rebuild the solution and wait resharper finish processing the assembly. Then the red color warnings disappear. :-)
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>How to Update Hexo?</title><url>/en/update-hexo/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[   Hexo 4.0.0 has been released on 2019-10-14. How to upgrade it?
Upgrade Hexo Go to the hexo folder Modify package.json file, inside &ldquo;dependencies&rdquo; braces: 1 2 - &#34;hexo&#34;: &#34;^3.9.0&#34;, + &#34;hexo&#34;: &#34;^4.0.0&#34;, UNNECESSARY to change
1 2 3 &#34;hexo&#34;: { &#34;version&#34;: &#34;3.9.0&#34; }, and it will be automatically updated after &ldquo;npm update&rdquo;.
Run 1 $ npm update Done. Then check the hexo version as below.
Check Hexo Version Go to the hexo folder and run:
1 2 3 $ hexo --version hexo: 4.0.0 hexo-cli: 1.1.0   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>C# Unity Replace InjectionFactory by RegisterFactory Example</title><url>/en/register-factory-exp/</url><categories><category>C#</category></categories><tags><tag>C#</tag><tag>Dependency Injection</tag><tag>Software Engineering</tag><tag>Unity</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  When you use RegisterType or RegisterInstance combined with InjectionFactory in old version of Unity, the following complier warning will be displayed:
&lsquo;InjectionFactory&rsquo; is obsolete: &lsquo;InjectionFactory has been deprecated and will be removed in next release. Please use IUnityContainer.RegisterFactory(&hellip;) method instead.
The code that triggered the warning:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 var container = new UnityContainer(); container.RegisterType&lt;IAnimal, Cat&gt;(&#34;Cat&#34;, new InjectionConstructor()); container.RegisterType&lt;IAnimal, Dog&gt;(&#34;Dog&#34;, new InjectionConstructor()); container.RegisterType&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;( &#34;AnimalList&#34;, new InjectionFactory( m =&gt; new List&lt;IAnimal&gt; { m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Cat&#34;), m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Dog&#34;), } ) ); The solution is straightforward, follow the instruction and use RegisterFactory instead:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 container.RegisterFactory&lt;List&lt;IAnimal&gt;&gt;( &#34;AnimalList&#34;, m =&gt; new List&lt;IAnimal&gt; { m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Cat&#34;), m.Resolve&lt;IAnimal&gt;(&#34;Dog&#34;), } ); The main difference of the replacement:
Replace &ldquo;RegisterType&rdquo; to &ldquo;RegisterFactory&rdquo; Remove InjectionFactory wrapper Moreover, it&rsquo;s easy to find the difference by comparing the declarations:
1 2 3 4 IUnityContainer RegisterType&lt;T&gt;(this IUnityContainer container, string name, params InjectionMember[] injectionMembers); InjectionFactory(Func&lt;IUnityContainer, object&gt; factoryFunc); IUnityContainer RegisterFactory&lt;TInterface&gt;(this IUnityContainer container, string name, Func&lt;IUnityContainer, object&gt; factory, IFactoryLifetimeManager lifetimeManager = null);   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Azure CloudService Deployment "Keyset does not exist"</title><url>/en/cloud-service-keyset/</url><categories><category>Misc</category></categories><tags/><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Deploy Azure cloudservice failed, and Microsoft Azure Activity Log shows the following message：
1 2 3 4 15:45:39 - Checking for Remote Desktop certificate... 15:45:40 - Applying Diagnostics extension. 15:46:03 - Applying remote desktop protocol (RDP) extension. 15:46:03 - Keyset does not exist. It seems that the problem is caused by the certificate which is used to encrypt the user credentials of RDP.
First, I found the corresponding certificate in ServiceConfiguration.Cloud.cscfg (hiding the thumbprint):
1 &lt;Certificate name=&#34;Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Plugins.RemoteAccess.PasswordEncryption&#34; thumbprint=&#34;XXXXX&#34; thumbprintAlgorithm=&#34;sha1&#34; /&gt; If the certificate is not installed, the error message should be:
1 2 3 16:59:15 - Applying Diagnostics extension. 16:59:40 - Applying remote desktop protocol (RDP) extension. 16:59:40 - Certificate with thumbprint XXXX doesn&#39;t exist. However, I checked the certificate by certmgr.msc and found it in personal\certificates folder.
Looks weird.
Just have a try, delete it, re-import the certificate, and redeploy the cloudservice, it works!
  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>NDCG Metrics & Implementations</title><url>/en/ndcg/</url><categories><category>Machine Learning</category></categories><tags><tag>Machine Learning</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Intro to NDCG Normalized Discounted Cumulative Gain (NDCG) is a measure of ranking quality. Typically, it is used to measure the performance of a ranker and widely adopted in information retrieval. Our goal is to rank relevant documents higher than irrelavant documents. Here comes the problem, given a list of documents with corresponding grades, how to model the ranking quality?
Concretely, assume we want to rank a list of 5 documents with grades: $$G = [3, 1, 2, 0, 2]$$
Cumulative Gain (CG) In practice, we only care about top $k$ ranked results. Assume $k = p$, then we represent it as $CG@p$. We define cumulative gain as: $$CG@p = \sum_{i=1}^{p}G(i)$$
CG is too simple to model the ranking quality. Consider it does not penalize the ranked document position, given a fixed number $p$, $CG@p$ keeps unchanged even if the order changed.
Discounted Cumulative Gain (DCG) Discount gain goes one step further which takes document position into account: $$DCG@p = \sum_{i=1}^{p}\frac{2^{G(i)} - 1}{\log_2(i+1)}$$
However, DCG is unnormalized, which means that different ranking groups are hard to compare. When we optimize the ranking performance, we would like to know where we are. Therefore, we normalize DCG to [0, 1] so that it is comparable among different queries.
Normalized Discounted Cumulative Gain (NDCG) Given a list and $p$, it is pretty easy to compute the optimal ranking order: sorting the list by grades in descending order. For instance, the optimal ranking order for $G = [3, 1, 2, 0, 2]$ is $|G| = [3, 2, 2, 1, 0]$. Define $$NDCG@p = \frac{DCG@p}{IDCG@p}$$ where Ideal Discounted Cumulative Gain (IDCG) is defined as: $$IDCG@p = \sum_{i=1}^{p}\frac{2^{|G|(i)}-1}{\log_2(i+1)}$$ where $|G|$ means the optimal order of $G$.
NDCG for Dataset Given a dataset $D$ with $n$ ranking groups, there are two ways to compute the dataset&rsquo;s NDCG: $$NDCG_{D} = \frac{\sum_{i=1}^{n}DCG_{i}}{\sum_{i=1}^{n}IDCG_{i}}$$
$$NDCG_{D} = \frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n}NDCG_{i}$$
To the best of my knowledge, we usually use the latter formula. Although both definitions range [0, 1], the latter definition makes more sense as it represents the averge NDCG across all queries in the dataset.
NDCG Implementations C# Implemenation 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 namespace ConsoleApp1 { using System; using System.Collections.Generic; using System.Linq; class Program { public static double Ndcg(List&lt;List&lt;int&gt;&gt; rankedDataset, int p, List&lt;int&gt; customGain = null) { if (!rankedDataset.Any()) { return 0; } var gain = customGain; if (gain == null) { gain = new int[p].ToList(); for (int i = 0; i &lt; p; ++i) { gain[i] = (int)Math.Pow(2, i) - 1; } } double ndcgSum = 0; int count = 0; foreach (var list in rankedDataset) { double dcg = 0; for (var i = 0; i &lt; list.Count &amp;&amp; i &lt; p; i++) { dcg += gain[list[i]] / Math.Log(i + 2); } double idcg = 0; var optimalOrder = list.OrderByDescending(x =&gt; x).ToList(); for (var i = 0; i &lt; optimalOrder.Count &amp;&amp; i &lt; p; i++) { idcg += gain[optimalOrder[i]] / Math.Log(i + 2); } if (Math.Abs(idcg) &lt; 0.000001) { continue; } ++count; ndcgSum += dcg / idcg; } return ndcgSum / count; } static void Main(string[] args) { var dataset = new List&lt;List&lt;int&gt;&gt; { new List&lt;int&gt; { 3, 1, 2, 0, 2 } }; Console.WriteLine(&#34;NDCG@5: &#34; + Ndcg(dataset, 5)); dataset[0] = dataset[0].OrderBy(x =&gt; x).ToList(); Console.WriteLine(&#34;Worst NDCG@5: &#34; + Ndcg(dataset, 5)); dataset[0] = dataset[0].OrderByDescending(x =&gt; x).ToList(); Console.WriteLine(&#34;Best NDCG@5: &#34; + Ndcg(dataset, 5)); Console.ReadKey(); } } } Python Implementation 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 import math def Ndcg(rankedDataset, p, customGain = None): if len(rankedDataset) == 0: return 0 gain = customGain if gain == None: gain = [(pow(2, i) - 1) for i in range(p)] ndcgSum = 0 count = 0 for singleList in rankedDataset: dcg = 0 for i in range(min(len(singleList), p)): dcg += gain[singleList[i]] / math.log(i + 2) idcg = 0 optimalOrder = sorted(singleList, reverse = True) for i in range(min(len(optimalOrder), p)): if i &gt;= p: break idcg += gain[optimalOrder[i]] / math.log(i + 2) if abs(idcg) &lt; 0.0001: continue count += 1 ndcgSum += dcg / idcg return ndcgSum / count if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;: dataset = [[ 3, 1, 2, 0, 2 ]] print (&#34;NDCG@5:&#34; + str(Ndcg(dataset, 5))) dataset[0] = sorted(dataset[0]) print (&#34;Worst NDCG@5:&#34; + str(Ndcg(dataset, 5))) dataset[0] = sorted(dataset[0], reverse = True) print (&#34;Best NDCG@5:&#34; + str(Ndcg(dataset, 5))) Output 1 2 3 NDCG@5:0.950849602851865 Worst NDCG@5:0.5664478625498256 Best NDCG@5:1.0   ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Fontawesome Icons Show As Blank Squares</title><url>/en/font-awesome-issue/</url><categories><category>Hexo</category></categories><tags><tag>Hexo</tag><tag>NexT</tag><tag>fontawesome</tag></tags><content type="html">  Description After deploying the Hexo websites to server, all the NexT icons were shown as blank squares. Analysis The NexT theme uses Font Awesome to display icons. If the website is started locally, everything is fine. Another interesting point is that the issue exists in Chrome but not IE.
Stylish plugin in Chrome. I forced all pages use customized fonts by Stylish. Maybe the font does not contain such icons. However, even I disable the plugin, the issue still exists.
The deploy folder does not contain the font files. After checking the website folder on the server, I found that it is not the root cause.
Consider the problem only appears in Chrome, I suspect the font files were not properly loaded. Turn on develop tools with F12 in Chrome and IE. Refresh the page and magic happens: Chrome and IE loads different font files, while woff/woff2 files were not correctly loaded by Chrome.
Solution Edit _config.yml of Next theme and use CDN to load fontawesome files:
1 2 3 4 5 6 # Internal version: 4.6.2 # See: https://fontawesome.com # Example: # fontawesome: //cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/font-awesome@4/css/font-awesome.min.css # fontawesome: //cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/font-awesome/4.6.2/css/font-awesome.min.css fontawesome: //stackpath.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.7.0/css/font-awesome.min.css Now everything works fine~
References: Fontawesome Troubleshooting Font awesome is not showing icon   </content></entry></search>